<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Benny Freeman</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/38087797</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Benny Freeman</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 15:47:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Influence of temperature on gas transport properties of tetraaminodiphenylsulfone (TADPS) based polybenzimidazoles</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/89c6124f8310e0d11791e7ba7460b03e6176e0fe</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/89c6124f8310e0d11791e7ba7460b03e6176e0fe</guid></item><item><title>Corrigendum to “Ion partitioning between brines and ion exchange polymers” [Polymer 165 (2019) 91–100]</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0382e5c999fe661717464c3cd5875e328f8c225c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0382e5c999fe661717464c3cd5875e328f8c225c</guid></item><item><title>Ethylene and Ethane Transport Properties of Hydrogen-Stable Ag +-Based Facilitated Transport Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/636ff8bdf92622704b00d57d5ba8a00b5ef179ef</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/636ff8bdf92622704b00d57d5ba8a00b5ef179ef</guid></item><item><title>Synergistically Improved PIM-1 Membrane Gas Separation Performance by PAF-1 Incorporation and UV Irradiation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c7aa6e07914e46950baf08bc05cf1634a2a56794</link><description>Super-glassy polymer membranes have suffered from the trade-off relationship between permeability and selectivity for gas separation applications, despite the fact that membrane technology exhibits remarkable energy efficiency advantages over other...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c7aa6e07914e46950baf08bc05cf1634a2a56794</guid></item><item><title>Influence of polydopamine deposition conditions on hydraulic permeability, sieving coefficients, pore size and pore size distribution for a polysulfone ultrafiltration membrane</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0fa6264e744477a8a5bc593a05de3add8ef5e860</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0fa6264e744477a8a5bc593a05de3add8ef5e860</guid></item><item><title>Physical aging, CO2 sorption and plasticization in thin films of polymer with intrinsic microporosity (PIM-1)</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/035dba17770da5b6661b27c3e134a9961520cc35</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/035dba17770da5b6661b27c3e134a9961520cc35</guid></item><item><title>Fouling-resistant ultrafiltration membranes prepared via co-deposition of dopamine/zwitterion composite coatings</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0cc3aa0e77f364a16ec1e3214dd842d5a2f48326</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0cc3aa0e77f364a16ec1e3214dd842d5a2f48326</guid></item><item><title>Ultrafast selective transport of alkali metal ions in metal organic frameworks with subnanometer pores</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fc139c330ac282b1a90106ec8d3198d8492d8880</link><description>Subnanometer metal organic framework pores can selectively transport alkali metal ions of the same valence and similar sizes. Porous membranes with ultrafast ion permeation and high ion selectivity are highly desirable for efficient mineral separation, water purification, and energy conversion, but it is still a huge challenge to efficiently separate monatomic ions of the same valence and similar sizes using synthetic membranes. We report metal organic framework (MOF) membranes, including ZIF-8 and UiO-66 membranes with uniform subnanometer pores consisting of angstrom-sized windows and nanometer-sized cavities for ultrafast selective transport of alkali metal ions. The angstrom-sized windows acted as ion selectivity filters for selection of alkali metal ions, whereas the nanometer-sized cavities functioned as ion conductive pores for ultrafast ion transport. The ZIF-8 and UiO-66 membranes showed a LiCl/RbCl selectivity of ~4.6 and ~1.8, respectively, which are much greater than the LiCl/RbCl selectivity of 0.6 to 0.8 measured in traditional porous membranes. Molecular dynamics simulations suggested that ultrafast and selective ion transport in ZIF-8 was associated with partial dehydration effects. This study reveals ultrafast and selective transport of monovalent ions in subnanometer MOF pores and opens up a new avenue to develop unique MOF platforms for efficient ion separations in the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fc139c330ac282b1a90106ec8d3198d8492d8880</guid></item><item><title>Salt concentration dependence of ionic conductivity in ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e48a17a333689ddb734daa2253e0be64afcc3fcb</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e48a17a333689ddb734daa2253e0be64afcc3fcb</guid></item><item><title>Synthesis and characterization of a phosphine oxide based Poly(arylene ether ketone) and blends with poly(2,6-dimethyl-1,4-phenylene oxide) for gas separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34bf8f8624b85aa685f9eebd10496933b0a7d461</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34bf8f8624b85aa685f9eebd10496933b0a7d461</guid></item><item><title>Large-scale polymeric carbon nanotube membranes with sub–1.27-nm pores</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/85b93eb69fcb08388cd26c8db8c1fbea286f097a</link><description>We report the first study of large-scale polymer membranes with &lt;1.27-nm-diameter aligned carbon nanotubes. We report the first characterization study of commercial prototype carbon nanotube (CNT) membranes consisting of sub–1.27-nm-diameter CNTs traversing a large-area nonporous polysulfone film. The membranes show rejection of NaCl and MgSO4 at higher ionic strengths than have previously been reported in CNT membranes, and specific size selectivity for analytes with diameters below 1.24 nm. The CNTs used in the membranes were arc discharge nanotubes with inner diameters of 0.67 to 1.27 nm. Water flow through the membranes was 1000 times higher than predicted by Hagen-Poiseuille flow, in agreement with previous CNT membrane studies. Ideal gas selectivity was found to deviate significantly from that predicted by both viscous and Knudsen flow, suggesting that surface diffusion effects may begin to dominate gas selectivity at this size scale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/85b93eb69fcb08388cd26c8db8c1fbea286f097a</guid></item><item><title>Water and ion sorption in a series of cross-linked AMPS/PEGDA hydrogel membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7b56de22a7844dbfe944db7c3473f8ce17844ef0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7b56de22a7844dbfe944db7c3473f8ce17844ef0</guid></item><item><title>Ion Diffusion Coefficients in Ion Exchange Membranes: Significance of Counterion Condensation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/816baad3130cb78e9904aee0f79820ec09fb5e7c</link><description>This study presents a new framework for extracting single ion diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes from experimental ion sorption, salt permeability, and ionic conductivity data. The framework was used to calculate cation and anion diffusion coefficients in a series of commercial ion exchange membranes contacted by aqueous NaCl solutions. Counterion diffusion coefficients were greater than co-ion diffusion coefficients for all membranes after accounting for inherent differences due to ion size. A model for ion diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes, incorporating ideas from counterion condensation theory, was proposed to interpret the experimental results. The model predicted co-ion diffusion coefficients reasonably well with no adjustable parameters, while a single adjustable parameter was required to accurately describe counterion diffusion coefficients. The results suggest that for cross-linked ion exchange membranes in which counterion condensation occurs condensed counterions mi...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/816baad3130cb78e9904aee0f79820ec09fb5e7c</guid></item><item><title>Water Vapor Sorption, Diffusion, and Dilation in Polybenzimidazoles</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b5faa068e4bdaf7bfa681a90674ae488c5c3d88c</link><description>Polybenzimidazoles (PBIs) have been investigated for use as gas separation membranes due to their thermal stability and good H2/CO2 separation performance at elevated temperatures. However, PBIs are hydrophilic, and effects of water vapor on PBI separation performance are essentially unexplored. This study investigates water sorption, diffusion, and dilation of a commercial PBI, Celazole, and a recently synthesized sulfonyl-containing PBI, TADPS-TPA. Water binds strongly to both polymers and requires elevated temperatures for removal. Water vapor sorption in Celazole follows dual-mode behavior up to unit activity, while upward concavity is observed at high activities in the TADPS-TPA sorption isotherm. Both PBIs swell significantly in water, and desorption hysteresis suggests water-induced conditioning of the PBI matrix. Model fits of dilation behavior enable estimation of partial molar volume and water-accessible fractional free volume (FFV) as a function of water activity. Water vapor diffusion coeffici...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b5faa068e4bdaf7bfa681a90674ae488c5c3d88c</guid></item><item><title>Infrared Spectroscopy of Polybenzimidazole in the Dry and Hydrate Forms: A Combined Experimental and Computational Study</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/602b55237a943cc1a2139ceb98e524cafd79113b</link><description>In the present article, the infrared spectrum of polybenzimidazole (PBI) in the dry and hydrate forms has been studied both experimentally and theoretically to improve the interpretation of its complex features, especially in the ν(NH)/ν(OH) range, which is extensively affected by sorbed water and temperature. Time-resolved Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy measurements were performed to monitor H2O sorption, whereas the temperature behavior was investigated by in situ measurements in the 100–450 °C range. Density functional theory calculations on simplified models of dry and hydrated PBI showed good agreement with experimental results and allowed a reliable interpretation of the observed effects. The combined experimental/computational analysis provided relevant structural information which suggested the possibility of modifying the diffusion properties of PBI and motivated further experimental activities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/602b55237a943cc1a2139ceb98e524cafd79113b</guid></item><item><title>Thermal rearranged poly(imide-co-ethylene glycol) membranes for gas separation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e3ee0f93fe8d440b36fdbed7645de0cb89eba27f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e3ee0f93fe8d440b36fdbed7645de0cb89eba27f</guid></item><item><title>Synthesis and characterization of polybenzimidazole membranes for gas separation with improved gas permeability: A grafting and blending approach</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/67bd83c86921d7ad84b7ddd542bc952e5b69b580</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/67bd83c86921d7ad84b7ddd542bc952e5b69b580</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium ion partitioning between aqueous salt solutions and inhomogeneous ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0ce73033c17d9740df2af22127f6d3924785c1b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0ce73033c17d9740df2af22127f6d3924785c1b</guid></item><item><title>Effect of fixed charge group concentration on salt permeability and diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bdcdf8ccc23f0f433d1148e4fbd74b5ed1b88aa</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bdcdf8ccc23f0f433d1148e4fbd74b5ed1b88aa</guid></item><item><title>Ordered polymeric membranes using metals</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7c8612159ebefaa9208894f4252593762ecf3fb1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7c8612159ebefaa9208894f4252593762ecf3fb1</guid></item><item><title>Transport of terpenes through composite PDMS/PAN solvent resistant nanofiltration membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/343e63b6e64d0ef898f03e37ecf90dc5796e78ad</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/343e63b6e64d0ef898f03e37ecf90dc5796e78ad</guid></item><item><title>Thermally cross-linked diaminophenylindane (DAPI) containing polyimides for membrane based gas separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7e56f7c8695a7a7dfc6dbd4c1ac584e5e91c95dc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7e56f7c8695a7a7dfc6dbd4c1ac584e5e91c95dc</guid></item><item><title>Influence of concentration polarization and thermodynamic non-ideality on salt transport in reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2d65b4b592b9caab663d71b5e6932fb5edf2ae7a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2d65b4b592b9caab663d71b5e6932fb5edf2ae7a</guid></item><item><title>Ion partitioning between brines and ion exchange polymers</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/385440bbbf98a09d76af1bff88091ed5bca7dd1a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/385440bbbf98a09d76af1bff88091ed5bca7dd1a</guid></item><item><title>Fouling mechanisms in constant flux crossflow ultrafiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/66453abacf4a5ff1a6f8a50f60c2bf074e8db8fc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/66453abacf4a5ff1a6f8a50f60c2bf074e8db8fc</guid></item><item><title>Organic solvent nanofiltration of binary vegetable oil/terpene mixtures: Experiments and modelling</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4b92f3e29aeb3566f65fc556d15fa0bf72924077</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4b92f3e29aeb3566f65fc556d15fa0bf72924077</guid></item><item><title>Effect of Water Content on Sodium Chloride Sorption in Cross-Linked Cation Exchange Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ce7c8b7a9417224c0afbb20539a64a7ff8e6366</link><description>Ion exchange membranes used for energy generation and water purification selectively transport ions, and this characteristic is strongly influenced by ion sorption in such membranes. Although water content and fixed charge group concentration are key factors affecting ion sorption in ion exchange membranes, their individual effects on ion sorption are not often studied. Here, a series of cross-linked cation exchange membranes (CEMs) were synthesized with different water uptake values and similar fixed charge group concentrations to study the effect of water content on ion sorption in such materials. Equilibrium co-ion concentrations in all membranes were very similar at a given external salt concentration, suggesting that co-ion sorption in these materials was mainly influenced by fixed charge group concentration rather than water content per se. Equilibrium co-ion sorption data were interpreted using a thermodynamic model based on Donnan theory and Manning’s counterion condensation theory. The inhomogene...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ce7c8b7a9417224c0afbb20539a64a7ff8e6366</guid></item><item><title>Fouling and in-situ cleaning of ion-exchange membranes during the electrodialysis of fresh acid and sweet whey</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bbe8046fb4c48c7f129021fbdca80a09e32f3eab</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bbe8046fb4c48c7f129021fbdca80a09e32f3eab</guid></item><item><title>Correction to Effect of Water Content on Sodium Chloride Sorption in Cross-Linked Cation Exchange Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f9c464a8655221ddaa43930f24a1a035262e3784</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f9c464a8655221ddaa43930f24a1a035262e3784</guid></item><item><title>Fast and selective fluoride ion conduction in sub-1-nanometer metal-organic framework channels</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e2f8c0303f0904b7ef7d3ce76252d97b79269342</link><description>Biological fluoride ion channels are sub-1-nanometer protein pores with ultrahigh F− conductivity and selectivity over other halogen ions. Developing synthetic F− channels with biological-level selectivity is highly desirable for ion separations such as water defluoridation, but it remains a great challenge. Here we report synthetic F− channels fabricated from zirconium-based metal-organic frameworks (MOFs), UiO-66-X (X = H, NH2, and N+(CH3)3). These MOFs are comprised of nanometer-sized cavities connected by sub-1-nanometer-sized windows and have specific F− binding sites along the channels, sharing some features of biological F− channels. UiO-66-X channels consistently show ultrahigh F− conductivity up to ~10 S m−1, and ultrahigh F−/Cl− selectivity, from ~13 to ~240. Molecular dynamics simulations reveal that the ultrahigh F− conductivity and selectivity can be ascribed mainly to the high F− concentration in the UiO-66 channels, arising from specific interactions between F− ions and F− binding sites in the MOF channels. While biological fluoride ion channels display excellent F− conductivity and selectivity, designing synthetic analogues remains highly challenging. Here the authors show that zirconium-based metal–organic frameworks with F− binding sites and sub-1-nanometer channels exhibit ultrahigh F− conductivity and selectivity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e2f8c0303f0904b7ef7d3ce76252d97b79269342</guid></item><item><title>Gas separation properties of polybenzimidazole/thermally-rearranged polymer blends</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7a7b883d5f21ab581dc95522010c9381a1604c87</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7a7b883d5f21ab581dc95522010c9381a1604c87</guid></item><item><title>Synthesis and characterization of post-sulfonated poly(arylene ether sulfone) membranes for potential applications in water desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed2bc5312bac72be7a0112a3246ca061008acfa3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed2bc5312bac72be7a0112a3246ca061008acfa3</guid></item><item><title>Influence of water content on alkali metal chloride transport in cross-linked Poly(ethylene glycol) Diacrylate.1. Ion sorption</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98c0a85a48d0c000980c242ae3747e5b786d17a5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98c0a85a48d0c000980c242ae3747e5b786d17a5</guid></item><item><title>Reflecting on 12 Years as an I&amp;EC Research Associate Editor</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6967a8cdc0bb5da8c69f85f155c650eb34259e6a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6967a8cdc0bb5da8c69f85f155c650eb34259e6a</guid></item><item><title>Compositionally Controlled Polyether Membranes via Mono(μ-alkoxo)bis(alkylaluminum)-Initiated Chain-Growth Network Epoxide Polymerization: Synthesis and Transport Properties</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d26f14341e3a3387c5a64b3333e14fa300010647</link><description>The addition of a diglycidyl-ether to a mono(μ-alkoxo)bis(alkylaluminum)-initiated epoxide polymerization presents a strategy for amorphous polyether-based membrane synthesis. In situ kinetic 1H NM...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d26f14341e3a3387c5a64b3333e14fa300010647</guid></item><item><title>Modeling water diffusion in polybenzimidazole membranes using partial immobilization and free volume theory</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c60c8c2e052cd6db71f11d17db18c32cdfa2eb89</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c60c8c2e052cd6db71f11d17db18c32cdfa2eb89</guid></item><item><title>Origin of CO2-philic Sorption of Graphene Oxide Layered Nanosheets and Its Derivatives.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/61aade46890b1450a4413e9d017c60d0af69e49c</link><description>Graphene oxide (GO) is a promising two-dimensional material for adsorbents and membranes, particularly for CO2 separation process. However, CO2 diffusion and sorption in GO and its layered structures are still not well understood because of its heterogeneous structure. Here we report CO2 sorption in GO and its derivatives (e.g., reduced GO (rGO)) in powders and films. These CO2 sorption behaviors reveal that GO is highly CO2-philic via complex CO2-functional group-surface interactions, as compared with graphite and rGOs. Even in highly interlocked, lamellar GO films, CO2 molecules above a certain threshold pressure can diffuse into GO interlayers, causing GO films to swell, leading to dramatic increases in CO2 sorption. Besides, intercalated water in GO interlayers can be removed by preferential CO2 sorption without any changes in GO chemical structure. This finding helps to explain the origin of CO2 affinity with GO and has implications for preparing anhydrous GO assemblies for various applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/61aade46890b1450a4413e9d017c60d0af69e49c</guid></item><item><title>Influence of water content on alkali metal chloride transport in cross-linked Poly(ethylene glycol) diacrylate.2. Ion diffusion</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed52b2f69bbf98235416b14f1c765ed2f3daf54f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed52b2f69bbf98235416b14f1c765ed2f3daf54f</guid></item><item><title>CMS membranes from PBI/PI blends: Temperature effect on gas transport and separation performance</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99df0c8e0417ab26c2c118afefccdbd486e75d23</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99df0c8e0417ab26c2c118afefccdbd486e75d23</guid></item><item><title>Polymer: Looking forward</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/16b4854e8ceb325a50480f83994134dc759faa3a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/16b4854e8ceb325a50480f83994134dc759faa3a</guid></item><item><title>Efficient metal ion sieving in rectifying subnanochannels enabled by metal–organic frameworks</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/63759a1c519dc8e53d84ff15faa0a2d7a952e738</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/63759a1c519dc8e53d84ff15faa0a2d7a952e738</guid></item><item><title>Hydrogen Stable Supported Ionic Liquid Membranes with Silver Carriers: Propylene and Propane Permeability and Solubility</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/acce1c749b4e35b83e83260560f90f7a4021c180</link><description>Pure gas permeabilities of propylene and propane through ionic liquids supported on porous alumina membranes were determined as a function of silver salt concentration from 0 to 1 M and feed pressu...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/acce1c749b4e35b83e83260560f90f7a4021c180</guid></item><item><title>Don Paul: 60 Years in Research and Education</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/70e5c4df61d9f34558d9bd9ec55c44a4e943c78f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/70e5c4df61d9f34558d9bd9ec55c44a4e943c78f</guid></item><item><title>Water Treatment: Are Membranes the Panacea?</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/26aa37800ec02a256c5bbe2c8c1179eb1a6be0d5</link><description>Alongside the rising global water demand, continued stress on current water supplies has sparked interest in using nontraditional source waters for energy, agriculture, industry, and domestic needs. Membrane technologies have emerged as one of the most promising approaches to achieve water security, but implementation of membrane processes for increasingly complex waters remains a challenge. The technical feasibility of membrane processes replacing conventional treatment of alternative water supplies (e.g., wastewater, seawater, and produced water) is considered in the context of typical and emerging water quality goals. This review considers the effectiveness of current technologies (both conventional and membrane based), as well as the potential for recent advancements in membrane research to achieve these water quality goals. We envision the future of water treatment to integrate advanced membranes (e.g., mixed-matrix membranes, block copolymers) into smart treatment trains that achieve several goals, including fit-for-purpose water generation, resource recovery, and energy conservation. Expected final online publication date for the Annual Review of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, Volume 11 is June 8, 2020. Please see http://www.annualreviews.org/page/journal/pubdates for revised estimates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/26aa37800ec02a256c5bbe2c8c1179eb1a6be0d5</guid></item><item><title>Unprecedentedly Low CO2 Transport through Vertically Aligned, Conical Silicon Nanotube Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5cfe0c499aadae2985a1a8c9eae36dc5c42b1f91</link><description>Nanotube membranes could show significantly enhanced permeance and selectivity for gas separations. Up until now, studies have primarily focused on applying carbon nanotubes to membranes to achieve ultrafast mass transport. Here, we report the first preparation of silicon nanotube (SiNT) membranes via a template-assisted method and investigate the gas transport behavior through these SiNT membranes using single- and mixed-gas permeation experiments. The SiNT membranes consist of conical cylinder-shaped nanotubes vertically aligned on a porous silicon wafer substrate. The diameter of the SiNT pore mouths are 10 and 30 nm, and the average inner diameter of the tube body is 80 nm. Interestingly, among the gases tested, we found an unprecedentedly low CO2 permeance through the SiNT membranes in single-gas permeation experiments, exceeding the theoretical Knudsen selectivity towards small gases/CO2 separation. This behavior was caused by the reduction of CO2 permeability through the blocking effect of CO2 adsorbed in the narrow pore channels of the SiNT cone regions, indicating that CO2 molecules have a high affinity to the native silicon oxide layer (~2 nm) that is formed on the inner walls of SiNTs. SiNT membranes also exhibited enhanced gas permeance and water flux as compared to classic theoretical models, and as such may prove useful as a new type of nanotube material for use in membrane applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5cfe0c499aadae2985a1a8c9eae36dc5c42b1f91</guid></item><item><title>Gas transport properties of PDMS-coated reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/74f9c81887f310e114b2190b17f6f39dee32afc8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/74f9c81887f310e114b2190b17f6f39dee32afc8</guid></item><item><title>Reimagining petroleum refining</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cdd74272e045e575a141329f15baa31251aea547</link><description>Rigid polymer membranes separate crude oil components without distillation Chemical separations involve often-complex mixtures of molecules into individual components or mixtures of components with similar properties. Such separations are integral to a variety of technologies, such as the production of liquid fuels and chemicals for transportation as well as everything from plastic bags to sterile medical equipment. On page 310 of this issue, Thompson et al. (1) describe the preparation and characterization of new polymeric membranes for crude oil fractionation, an extremely complex hydrocarbon separation process that is vital to the production of modern fuels and chemicals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cdd74272e045e575a141329f15baa31251aea547</guid></item><item><title>Can Self-Assembly Address the Permeability/Selectivity Trade-Offs in Polymer Membranes?</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/48e929a958a8e3215dfbd48dd8cedc9f6c0043c0</link><description>In 1999, Freeman published a visionary article that proposed a molecular basis for the trade-off between permeability and selectivity for polymeric gas separation membranes, which is often codified...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/48e929a958a8e3215dfbd48dd8cedc9f6c0043c0</guid></item><item><title>Tailoring molecular interactions between microporous polymers in high performance mixed matrix membranes for gas separations.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fc2b5402ccad63d9e0cea23adbdf4ac34ceb469a</link><description>Membranes are crucial to lowering the huge energy costs of chemical separations. Whilst some promising polymers demonstrate excellent transport properties, problems of plasticisation and physical aging due to mobile polymer chains, amongst others, prevent their exploitation in membranes for industrial separations. Here we reveal that molecular interactions between a polymer of intrinsic microporosity (PIM) matrix and a porous aromatic framework additive (PAF-1) can simultaneously address plasticisation and physical aging whilst also increasing gas transport selectivity. Extensive spectroscopic characterisation and control experiments involving two near-identical PIMs, one with methyl groups (PIM-EA(Me2)-TB) and one without (PIM-EA(H2)-TB), directly confirm the key molecular interaction as the adsoprtion of methyl groups from the PIM matrix into the nanopores of the PAF. This interaction reduced physical aging by 50%, suppressed polymer chain mobilities at high pressure and increased H2 selectivity over larger gases such as CH4 and N2.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fc2b5402ccad63d9e0cea23adbdf4ac34ceb469a</guid></item><item><title>Mobile ion partitioning in ion exchange membranes immersed in saline solutions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9969340729db6e9a09e68c84ecbd938026aa13af</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9969340729db6e9a09e68c84ecbd938026aa13af</guid></item><item><title>Influence of Physicochemical Properties on Gas Transport Properties of Silver-Containing Ionic Liquid Mixtures for Olefin/Paraffin Membrane Separation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/961d69d0058d1d9a65cd2287af6141808b7367d4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/961d69d0058d1d9a65cd2287af6141808b7367d4</guid></item><item><title>Competitive sorption in CO2/CH4 separations: the case of HAB-6FDA polyimide and its TR derivative and a general analysis of its impact on the selectivity of glassy polymers at multicomponent conditions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7068206a7730d90589c48e99cdddb002013331a0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7068206a7730d90589c48e99cdddb002013331a0</guid></item><item><title>Co-ion specific effect on sodium halides sorption and transport in a cross-linked poly(p-styrene sulfonate-co-divinylbenzene) for membrane applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/43629d2a1697e48ae6d895e3232b565ad5d1a094</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/43629d2a1697e48ae6d895e3232b565ad5d1a094</guid></item><item><title>Glassy polymers: Historical findings, membrane applications, and unresolved questions regarding physical aging</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2760ad33a69d19a414149ebb4efe9eb56d8dfa5d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2760ad33a69d19a414149ebb4efe9eb56d8dfa5d</guid></item><item><title>Gas sorption and diffusion in poly(dimethylsiloxane) (PDMS)/graphene oxide (GO) nanocomposite membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/72a495b1cd78751f9fa9c7caccd9ffa0c5b5a2d8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/72a495b1cd78751f9fa9c7caccd9ffa0c5b5a2d8</guid></item><item><title>Designing Solute-Tailored Selectivity in Membranes: Perspectives for Water Reuse and Resource Recovery.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/13b92754f976ca73103386f880a7f9e96e543a01</link><description>Treatment of nontraditional source waters (e.g., produced water, municipal and industrial wastewaters, agricultural runoff) offers exciting opportunities to expand water and energy resources via water reuse and resource recovery. While conventional polymer membranes perform water/ion separations well, they do not provide solute-specific separation, a key component for these treatment opportunities. Herein, we discuss the selectivity limitations plaguing all conventional membranes, which include poor removal of small, neutral solutes and insufficient discrimination between ions of the same valence. Moreover, we present synthetic approaches for solute-tailored selectivity including the incorporation of single-digit nanopores and solute-selective ligands into membranes. Recent progress in these areas highlights the need for fundamental studies to rationally design membranes with selective moieties achieving desired separations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/13b92754f976ca73103386f880a7f9e96e543a01</guid></item><item><title>Prediction of lattice energy of benzene crystals: A robust theoretical approach</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3e95c479b9cd5204fbdde6a9cbd9c7e27f0d7ed9</link><description>We present an inexpensive and robust theoretical approach based on the fragment molecular orbital methodology and the spin‐ratio scaled second‐order Møller–Plesset perturbation theory to predict the lattice energy of benzene crystals within 2 kJ⋅mol−1. Inspired by the Harrison method to estimate the Madelung constant, the proposed approach calculates the lattice energy as a sum of two‐ and three‐body interaction energies between a reference molecule and the surrounding molecules arranged in a sphere. The lattice energy converges rapidly at a radius of 13 Å. Adding the corrections to account for a higher correlated level of theory and basis set superposition for the Hartree Fock (HF) level produced a lattice energy of −57.5 kJ⋅mol−1 for the benzene crystal structure at 138 K. This estimate is within 1.6 kJ⋅mol−1 off the best theoretical prediction of −55.9 kJ⋅mol−1. We applied this approach to calculate lattice energies of the crystal structures of phase I and phase II—polymorphs of benzene—observed at a higher temperature of 295 K. The stability of these polymorphs was correctly predicted, with phase II being energetically preferred by 3.7 kJ⋅mol−1 over phase I. The proposed approach gives a tremendous potential to predict stability of other molecular crystal polymorphs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3e95c479b9cd5204fbdde6a9cbd9c7e27f0d7ed9</guid></item><item><title>Characterization and gas transport properties of UV-irradiated polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS)-containing polyimide copolymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bc7075446c32b8a03f010ebe57884ce2769be18</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bc7075446c32b8a03f010ebe57884ce2769be18</guid></item><item><title>Versatile Synthetic Platform for Polymer Membrane Libraries Using Functional Networks</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ca69f4bd8826c4cd185247a343bf722e7e37825b</link><description>Poly(ethylene glycol) (PEG) diacrylate copolymer networks containing pentafluorophenyl active esters can be quantitatively substituted with a wide variety of primary amines, enabling the developmen...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ca69f4bd8826c4cd185247a343bf722e7e37825b</guid></item><item><title>Gas Separation by Mixed Matrix Membranes with Porous Organic Polymer Inclusions within o-Hydroxypolyamides Containing m-Terphenyl Moieties</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/12abc56c09d8fa57b7f4fda8e82387b92ea8dc5c</link><description>A hydroxypolyamide (HPA) manufactured from 2,2-bis(3-amino-4-hydroxy phenyl)-hexafluoropropane (APAF) diamine and 5′-terbutyl-m-terphenyl-4,4′′-dicarboxylic acid chloride (tBTpCl), and a copolyimide produced by stochiometric copolymerization of APAF and 4,4′-(hexafluoroisopropylidene) diamine (6FpDA), using the same diacid chloride, were obtained and used as polymeric matrixes in mixed matrix membranes (MMMs) loaded with 20% (w/w) of two porous polymer networks (triptycene-isatin, PPN-1, and triptycene-trifluoroacetophenone, PPN-2). These MMMs, and also the thermally rearranged membranes (TR-MMMs) that underwent a thermal treatment process to convert the o-hydroxypolyamide moieties to polybenzoxazole ones, were characterized, and their gas separation properties evaluated for H2, N2, O2, CH4, and CO2. Both TR process and the addition of PPN increased permeability with minor decreases in selectivity for all gases tested. Excellent results were obtained, in terms of the permeability versus selectivity compromise, for H2/CH4 and H2/N2 separations with membranes approaching the 2008 Robeson’s trade-off line. The best gas separation properties were obtained when PPN-2 was used. Finally, gas permeation was characterized in terms of chain intersegmental distance and fraction of free volume of the membrane along with the kinetic diameters of the permeated gases. The intersegmental distance increased after TR and/or the addition of PPN-2. Permeability followed an exponential dependence with free volume and a quadratic function of the kinetic diameter of the gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/12abc56c09d8fa57b7f4fda8e82387b92ea8dc5c</guid></item><item><title>Erratum to 'Single and binary ion sorption equilibria of monovalent and divalent ions in commercial ion exchange membranes' [Water Research 175 (2020) 115681].</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/193f351c37429fb5a6415a943f5a7147168855bd</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/193f351c37429fb5a6415a943f5a7147168855bd</guid></item><item><title>Mechanically robust hydrophobized double network hydrogels and their fundamental salt transport properties</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3d9c7eecd706d20abbebe3da77ce5160bdaa2345</link><description>Water swollen polymer networks are attractive for applications ranging from tissue regeneration to water purification. For water purification, charged poly-mers provide excellent ion separation properties. However, many ion exchange membranes (IEMs) are brittle, necessitating the use of thick support materials that ultimately decrease throughput. To this end, novel double network hydrogels (DNHs) with variable water content are prepared and characterized in terms of mechanical and ion transport properties to evaluate their potential utility as tough membrane materials. The first network contains fixed anionic charges, while the other is comprised of a copolymer with varied ratios of hydrophobic ethyl acrylate (EA) and hydrophilic dimethyl acrylamide (DMA) repeat units. Characterization of freestanding DNH films reveals a reduction in water content from 88 to 53 wt% and a simultaneous increase in ultimate stress and strain by ~3.5 (cid:1) and ~4.5 (cid:1) , respectively, for 95%/5% EA/DMA, relative to 100% DMA. Fundamental salt transport properties relevant to water purification, including permeability, solubility, and diffusivity, are measured and systematically compared with conventional membrane materials to inform the development of DNHs for membrane applications. The ability to simultaneously reduce water content and increase mechanical integrity highlights the potential of DNHs as a synthetic platform for future</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3d9c7eecd706d20abbebe3da77ce5160bdaa2345</guid></item><item><title>Impact of humidity on gas transport in polybenzimidazole membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/49fcf669da9d670d5f0f63ec8d28ea39e82184c7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/49fcf669da9d670d5f0f63ec8d28ea39e82184c7</guid></item><item><title>Engineering Li/Na selectivity in 12-Crown-4–functionalized polymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1780ed3985885580d8a58f4d32a07a42b415e577</link><description>Significance Lithium is a key ingredient in batteries, which are integral components of next-generation automobiles, airplanes, grid energy storage, and electronic devices. Unfortunately, lithium extraction from natural sources is laborious, slow, and costly, motivating the search for more efficient isolation techniques. While polymeric membranes could reduce the cost of lithium recovery, current membrane materials lack sufficient lithium-ion selectivity. To address this challenge, we introduce a class of polymeric membranes that incorporate ion binding sites, which significantly increases the transport selectivity of LiCl over NaCl. These studies provide guidelines and practical considerations for incorporating specific interactants into polymers that mediate selective ion transport. Lithium is widely used in contemporary energy applications, but its isolation from natural reserves is plagued by time-consuming and costly processes. While polymer membranes could, in principle, circumvent these challenges by efficiently extracting lithium from aqueous solutions, they usually exhibit poor ion-specific selectivity. Toward this end, we have incorporated host–guest interactions into a tunable polynorbornene network by copolymerizing 1) 12-crown-4 ligands to impart ion selectivity, 2) poly(ethylene oxide) side chains to control water content, and 3) a crosslinker to form robust solids at room temperature. Single salt transport measurements indicate these materials exhibit unprecedented reverse permeability selectivity (∼2.3) for LiCl over NaCl—the highest documented to date for a dense, water-swollen polymer. As demonstrated by molecular dynamics simulations, this behavior originates from the ability of 12-crown-4 to bind Na+ ions more strongly than Li+ in an aqueous environment, which reduces Na+ mobility (relative to Li+) and offsets the increase in Na+ solubility due to binding with crown ethers. Under mixed salt conditions, 12-crown-4 functionalized membranes showed identical solubility selectivity relative to single salt conditions; however, the permeability and diffusivity selectivity of LiCl over NaCl decreased, presumably due to flux coupling. These results reveal insights for designing advanced membranes with solute-specific selectivity by utilizing host–guest interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1780ed3985885580d8a58f4d32a07a42b415e577</guid></item><item><title>Origins of Lithium/Sodium Reverse Permeability Selectivity in 12-Crown-4-Functionalized Polymer Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4664bcbe4efae6b1b4e237a60e122e9b30a8ef2f</link><description>Direct lithium extraction via membrane separations has been fundamentally limited by lack of monovalent ion selectivity exhibited by conventional polymeric membranes, particularly between sodium and lithium ions. Recently, a 12-Crown-4-functionalized polynorbornene membrane was shown to have the largest lithium/sodium permeability selectivity observed in a fully aqueous system to date. Using atomistic molecular dynamics simulations, we reveal that this selectivity is due to strong interactions between sodium ions and 12-Crown-4 moieties, which reduce sodium ion diffusivity while leaving lithium ion mobility relatively unaffected. Moreover, the ion diffusivities in the membrane, when scaled by their respective solution diffusivities and free ion fractions, can be collapsed to an almost universal relationship depending on solvent volume fraction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4664bcbe4efae6b1b4e237a60e122e9b30a8ef2f</guid></item><item><title>Pure- and mixed-gas transport properties of a microporous Tröger's Base polymer (PIM-EA-TB)</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/af15e5491daa1f8c9581b2a02846869b861bbd32</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/af15e5491daa1f8c9581b2a02846869b861bbd32</guid></item><item><title>Fundamental Limitations for Solid Polymer Electrolytes in Secondary Batteries</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ab7b231372ca8c1bb5476575c3e033b59df583e6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ab7b231372ca8c1bb5476575c3e033b59df583e6</guid></item><item><title>Boric acid removal with polyol-functionalized polyether membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1719cd3895dcc201c50d22f585e7d3ced00527b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1719cd3895dcc201c50d22f585e7d3ced00527b</guid></item><item><title>Aqueous ion partitioning in Nafion: Applicability of Manning's counter-ion condensation theory</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/206da99de2f89068caeee9b3fbfcf5559afe1b61</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/206da99de2f89068caeee9b3fbfcf5559afe1b61</guid></item><item><title>Selective Separation of Lithium Chloride by Organogels Containing Strapped Calix[4]pyrroles.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1064667bd523345648466ebb7d423d4841a4569e</link><description>Reported herein are two functionalized crown ether strapped calix[4]pyrroles, H1 and H2. As inferred from competitive salt binding experiments carried out in nitrobenzene-d5 and acetonitrile-d3, these hosts capture LiCl selectively over four other test salts, viz. NaCl, KCl, MgCl2, and CaCl2. Support for the selectivity came from density functional theory (DFT) calculations carried out in a solvent continuum. These theoretical analyses revealed a higher innate affinity for LiCl in the case of H1, but a greater selectivity relative to NaCl in the case of H2, recapitulating that observed experimentally. Receptors H1 and H2 were outfitted with methacrylate handles and subject to copolymerization with acrylate monomers and cross-linkers to yield gels, G1 and G2, respectively. These two gels were found to adsorb lithium chloride preferentially from an acetonitrile solution containing a mixture of LiCl, NaCl, KCl, MgCl2, and CaCl2 and then release the lithium chloride in methanol. The gels could then be recycled for reuse in the selective adsorption of LiCl. As such, the present study highlights the use of solvent polarity switching to drive separations with potential applications in lithium purification and recycling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1064667bd523345648466ebb7d423d4841a4569e</guid></item><item><title>Hydrogen Recovery by Mixed Matrix Membranes Made from 6FCl-APAF HPA with Different Contents of a Porous Polymer Network and Their Thermal Rearrangement</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/40869f7cef80c6e173a3561ffbde4fa701199cef</link><description>Mixed matrix membranes (MMMs) consisting of a blend of a hydroxypolyamide (HPA) matrix and variable loads of a porous polymer network (PPN) were thermally treated to induce the transformation of HPA to polybenzoxazole (β-TR-PBO). Here, the HPA matrix was a hydroxypolyamide having two hexafluoropropyilidene moieties, 6FCl-APAF, while the PPN was prepared by reacting triptycene (TRP) and trifluoroacetophenone (TFAP) in a superacid solution. The most probable size of the PPN particles was 75 nm with quite large distributions. The resulting membranes were analyzed by SEM and AFM. Up to 30% PPN loads, both SEM and AFM images confirmed quite planar surfaces, at low scale, with limited roughness. Membranes with high hydrogen permeability and good selectivity for the gas pairs H2/CH4 and H2/N2 were obtained. For H2/CO2, selectivity almost vanished after thermal rearrangement. In all cases, their hydrogen permeability increased with increasing loads of PPN until around 30% PPN with ulterior fairly abrupt decreasing of permeability for all gases studied. Thermal rearrangement of the MMMs resulted in higher permeabilities but lower selectivities. For all the membranes and gas pairs studied, the balance of permeability vs. selectivity surpassed the 1991 Robeson’s upper bound, and approached or even exceeded the 2008 line, for MMMs having 30% PPN loads. In all cases, the HPA-MMMs before thermal rearrangement provided good selectivity versus permeability compromise, similar to their thermally rearranged counterparts but in the zone of high selectivity. For H2/CH4, H2/N2, these nonthermally rearranged MMMs approach the 2008 Robeson’s upper bound while H2/CO2 gives selective transport favoring H2 on the 1991 Robeson’s bound. Thus, attending to the energy cost of thermal rearrangement, it could be avoided in some cases especially when high selectivity is the target rather than high permeability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/40869f7cef80c6e173a3561ffbde4fa701199cef</guid></item><item><title>Influence of fixed charge concentration and water uptake on ion sorption in AMPS/PEGDA membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/149054afa9d3872bae72a98d043d9f72f6afef55</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/149054afa9d3872bae72a98d043d9f72f6afef55</guid></item><item><title>Preparation of defect-free asymmetric gas separation membranes with dihydrolevoglucosenone (CyreneTM) as a greener polar aprotic solvent</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0f4ddafbf2e5278e94771ae0e495d056f7f2c703</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0f4ddafbf2e5278e94771ae0e495d056f7f2c703</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced Membrane Performance for Gas Separation by Coupling Effect of the Porous Aromatic Framework (PAF) Incorporation and Photo-Oxidation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/53aac402442a37c63f854a91f9671c0239884cb4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/53aac402442a37c63f854a91f9671c0239884cb4</guid></item><item><title>Gas Permeability, Fractional Free Volume and Molecular Kinetic Diameters: The Effect of Thermal Rearrangement on ortho-hydroxy Polyamide Membranes Loaded with a Porous Polymer Network</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6ad0e11199d8025973b06d96e27f3d6d73c5b964</link><description>Mixed-matrix membranes (MMMs) consisting of an ortho-hydroxy polyamide (HPA) matrix, and variable loads of a porous polymer network (PPN) were thermally treated to induce the transformation of HPA to polybenzoxazole (β-TR-PBO). Two different HPAs were synthesized to be used as a matrix, 6FCl-APAF and tBTpCl-APAF, while the PPN used as a filler was prepared by reacting triptycene and trifluoroacetophenone. The permeability of He, H2, N2, O2, CH4 and CO2 gases through these MMMs are analyzed as a function of the fraction of free volume (FFV) of the membrane and the kinetic diameter of the gas, allowing for the evaluation of the free volume. Thermal rearrangement entails an increase in the FFV. Both before and after thermal rearrangement, the free volume increases with the PPN content very similarly for both polymeric matrices. It is shown that there is a portion of free volume that is inaccessible to permeation (occluded volume), probably due to it being trapped within the filler. In fact, permeability and selectivity change below what could be expected according to densities, when the fraction of occluded volume increases. A higher filler load increases the percentage of inaccessible or trapped free volume, probably due to the increasing agglomeration of the filler. On the other hand, the phenomenon is slightly affected by thermal rearrangement. The fraction of trapped free volume seems to be lower for membranes in which the tBTpCl-APAF is used as a matrix than for those with a 6FCl-APAF matrix, possibly because tBTpCl-APAF could approach the PPN better. The application of an effective medium theory for permeability allowed us to extrapolate for a 100% filler, giving the same value for both thermally rearranged and non-rearranged MMMs. The pure filler could also be extrapolated by assuming the same tendency as in the Robeson’s plots for MMMs with low filler content.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6ad0e11199d8025973b06d96e27f3d6d73c5b964</guid></item><item><title>Cation–Ligand Interactions Dictate Salt Partitioning and Diffusivity in Ligand-Functionalized Polymer Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c063cd9ca4d785a20b8ed08e1e035b34223278d9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c063cd9ca4d785a20b8ed08e1e035b34223278d9</guid></item><item><title>Mining Air for Fuels and Fine Chemicals</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4a73a58dbef923422a8228d3c9d822f391cbe1cf</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4a73a58dbef923422a8228d3c9d822f391cbe1cf</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Cation–Ligand Interactions on the Permselectivity of Ligand-Functionalized Polymer Membranes in Single and Mixed Salt Systems</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/de337cde009736bfa10782408c9b0ec0a10a7ee8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/de337cde009736bfa10782408c9b0ec0a10a7ee8</guid></item><item><title>Multi-lab study on the pure-gas permeation of commercial polysulfone (PSf) membranes: Measurement standards and best practices</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b87146bb68ed57fe42c4a6a7139dc3cd56ccc955</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b87146bb68ed57fe42c4a6a7139dc3cd56ccc955</guid></item><item><title>Scalable Pillar[5]arene-Integrated Poly(arylate-amide) Molecular Sieve Membranes to Separate Light Gases</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b9bbf41372df43d05bbbf772250d2c4fcbd8cbb0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b9bbf41372df43d05bbbf772250d2c4fcbd8cbb0</guid></item><item><title>User Guide to Ring-Opening Metathesis Polymerization of endo-Norbornene Monomers with Chelated Initiators</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ce0a218fdd2843263ff9872d2e35923c5aa9a24d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ce0a218fdd2843263ff9872d2e35923c5aa9a24d</guid></item><item><title>Structure–Property Relationships for Polyether-Based Electrolytes in the High-Dielectric-Constant Regime</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2a0c50cbcd8bf2574b6b49435f47feb246e0ce3e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2a0c50cbcd8bf2574b6b49435f47feb246e0ce3e</guid></item><item><title>Free Volume and Permeability of Mixed Matrix Membranes Made from a Terbutil-M-terphenyl Polyamide and a Porous Polymer Network</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/df6ca992415e12a586400f7f597aeaceb3b4bc22</link><description>A set of thermally rearranged mixed matrix membranes (TR-MMMs) was manufactured and tested for gas separation. These membranes were obtained through the thermal treatment of a precursor MMM with a microporous polymer network and an o-hydroxypolyamide,(HPA) created through a reaction of 2,2-bis(3-amino-4-hydroxyphenyl)-hexafluoropropane (APAF) and 5′-terbutil-m-terfenilo-3,3″-dicarboxylic acid dichloride (tBTmCl). This HPA was blended with different percentages of a porous polymer network (PPN) filler, which produced gas separation MMMs with enhanced gas permeability but with decreased selectivity. The thermal treatment of these MMMs gave membranes with excellent gas separation properties that did not show the selectivity decreasing trend. It was observed that the use of the PPN load brought about a small decrease in the initial mass losses, which were lower for increasing PPN loads. Regarding the glass transition temperature, it was observed that the use of the filler translated to a slightly lower Tg value. When these MMMs and TR-MMMs were compared with the analogous materials created from the isomeric 5′-terbutil-m-terfenilo-4,4″-dicarboxylic acid dichloride (tBTpCl), the permeability was lower for that of tBTmCl, compared with the one from tBTpCl, although selectivity was quite similar. This fact could be attributed to a lower rigidity as roughly confirmed by the segmental length of the polymer chain as studied by WAXS. A model for FFV calculation was proposed and its predictions compared with those evaluated from density measurements assuming a matrix-filler interaction or ideal independence. It turns out that permeability as a function of FFV for TR-MMMs follows an interaction trend, while those not thermally treated follow the non-interaction trend until relatively high PPN loads were reached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/df6ca992415e12a586400f7f597aeaceb3b4bc22</guid></item><item><title>Current Status and Advances in Membrane Technology for Carbon Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a72e7e09ea79d73f86b6ae5256ddcfc970c62738</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a72e7e09ea79d73f86b6ae5256ddcfc970c62738</guid></item><item><title>The Donnan potential revealed</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ffad21d325874a05a0519ee5753dc8f5fb1ef49b</link><description>Selective transport of solutes across a membrane is critical for many biological, water treatment and energy conversion and storage systems. When a charged membrane is equilibrated with an electrolyte, an unequal distribution of ions arises between phases, generating the so-called Donnan electrical potential at the solution/membrane interface. The Donnan potential results in the partial exclusion of co-ion, providing the basis of permselectivity. Although there are well-established ways to indirectly estimate the Donnan potential, it has been widely reported that it cannot be measured directly. Here we report the first direct measurement of the Donnan potential of an ion exchange membrane equilibrated with salt solutions. Our results highlight the dependence of the Donnan potential on external salt concentration and counter-ion valence, and show a reasonable agreement with current theoretical models of IEMs, which incorporate ion activity coefficients. By directly measuring the Donnan potential, we eliminate ambiguities that arise from limitations inherent in current models. Donnan electrical potential is widely adopted to describe ion distribution between two solutions separated by a permeable membrane with implications for many chemical and biological systems. Aydogan Gokturk et al. directly measures this potential for the first time and compare the data with theoretical models.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ffad21d325874a05a0519ee5753dc8f5fb1ef49b</guid></item><item><title>Polymeric multimaterials by photochemical patterning of crystallinity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4c9075176b433215862656cf30957fad5171156e</link><description>An organized combination of stiff and elastic domains within a single material can synergistically tailor bulk mechanical properties. However, synthetic methods to achieve such sophisticated architectures remain elusive. We report a rapid, facile, and environmentally benign method to pattern strong and stiff semicrystalline phases within soft and elastic matrices using stereo-controlled ring-opening metathesis polymerization of an industrial monomer, cis-cyclooctene. Dual polymerization catalysis dictates polyolefin backbone chemistry, which enables patterning of compositionally uniform materials with seamless stiff and elastic interfaces. Visible light–induced activation of a metathesis catalyst results in the formation of semicrystalline trans polyoctenamer rubber, outcompeting the formation of cis polyoctenamer rubber, which occurs at room temperature. This bottom-up approach provides a method for manufacturing polymeric materials with promising applications in soft optoelectronics and robotics. Description A reactive way to make a composite Blending different materials to form a composite is a way to tune properties to achieve something not possible in a single material. However, it can be challenging to mix or pattern dissimilar materials. Rylski et al. developed a way to produce multimaterials by patterning a strong domain within an elastic domain. They used a dual-catalyst system that polymerizes cis-polycyclooctene in the dark but forms trans-polycyclooctene when exposed to light. This approach led to a polyoctenamer with cohesively connected viscoelastic (soft) and semicrystalline (hard) domains and provided the ability to spatially control the properties of the polymer. —MSL Spatially synthesizing stiff and elastic domains from a single monomer forms robust synthetic plastics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4c9075176b433215862656cf30957fad5171156e</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Ion-Ion Correlated Motion on Salt Transport in Solvated Ion Exchange Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/39c6113d9289819c93af6611933ebc158bbfc159</link><description>The influence of dynamical ion-ion correlations and ion pairing on salt transport in ion exchange membranes remain poorly understood. In this study, we use the framework of Onsager transport coefficients within atomistic molecular dynamics simulations to study the impact of ion-ion correlated motion on salt transport in hydrated polystyrene sulfonate membranes and compare with the results from aqueous salt solutions. At sufficiently high salt concentrations, cation-anion dynamical correlations exert a significant influence on both salt diffusivities and conductivities. Anion-anion distinct correlations, arising from the imbalance between the concentration of free (mobile) cations and anions, and the retarding effect of the fixed charge groups on cations, proves to be an additional important feature for polymer membranes. Our results demonstrate that dynamical correlations should become an important consideration in experimental measurements of salt diffusivities and conductivities for non-dilute salt solutions in polymer membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/39c6113d9289819c93af6611933ebc158bbfc159</guid></item><item><title>Ionic Liquid Facilitated Solvent‐Phase Polymerization of Ultrasmooth Coatings of Polycatecholamines</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3cb0a3f878e487b1be0af2f401675445de10cf12</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3cb0a3f878e487b1be0af2f401675445de10cf12</guid></item><item><title>Surface Modification of Ultrafiltration Membranes with 1,4-Benzoquinone and Polyetheramines to Improve Fouling Resistance.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3e500c543903af2a0d8da81d95002dd4c131d6c3</link><description>Membrane fouling remains a key challenge for membrane separations. Hydrophilic membrane surface modification can mitigate irreversible foulant deposition, thereby improving fouling resistance. We report new hydrophilic membrane coatings based on 1,4-benzoquinone and various commercially available polyetheramines. These coatings, prepared from 1,4-benzoquinone and Jeffamine EDR 148, poly(benzoquinone-Jeffamine EDR 148) (p(BQ-EDR 148)), were used to modify polysulfone (PS) ultrafiltration membranes. In fouling experiments using an oil/water emulsion, membranes exhibited comparable fouling resistance to that of polydopamine (pDA)-modified membranes. Based on contact angle measurements, p(BQ-EDR 148) and pDA-modified membranes have similar levels of hydrophilicity, and both exhibited higher threshold flux values than those of their unmodified analogues. Based on their similar threshold flux values, p(BQ-EDR 148)-modified (76 LMH) and pDA-modified membranes (74 LMH) should have similar fouling resistance. Moreover, the mean pore size of p(BQ-EDR 148)-modified membranes can be tuned, while keeping the pure water permeance constant, by changing the deposition time and molar ratio of benzoquinone to EDR 148 in the modification solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3e500c543903af2a0d8da81d95002dd4c131d6c3</guid></item><item><title>Multimorphic Materials: Spatially Tailoring Mechanical Properties via Selective Initiation of Interpenetrating Polymer Networks</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4196659ec7e560a06a5763f5fc95cb85160757bd</link><description>Access to multimaterial polymers with spatially localized properties and robust interfaces is anticipated to enable new capabilities in soft robotics, such as smooth actuation for advanced medical and manufacturing technologies. Here, orthogonal initiation is used to create interpenetrating polymer networks (IPNs) with spatial control over morphology and mechanical properties. Base catalyzes the formation of a stiff and strong polyurethane, while blue LEDs initiate the formation of a soft and elastic polyacrylate. IPN morphology is controlled by when the LED is turned “on”, with large phase separation occurring for short time delays (≈1–2 min) and a mixed morphology for longer time delays (&gt;5 min), which is supported by dynamic mechanical analysis, small angle X‐ray scattering, and atomic force microscopy. Through tailoring morphology, tensile moduli and fracture toughness can be tuned across ≈1–2 orders of magnitude. Moreover, a simple spring model is used to explain the observed mechanical behavior. Photopatterning produces “multimorphic” materials, where morphology is spatially localized with fine precision (&lt;100 µm), while maintaining a uniform chemical composition throughout to mitigate interfacial failure. As a final demonstration, the fabrication of hinges represents a possible use case for multimorphic materials in soft robotics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4196659ec7e560a06a5763f5fc95cb85160757bd</guid></item><item><title>An artificial sodium-selective subnanochannel</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7a89f2a5296f0439929733f8c239f3683eb9f51c</link><description>Single-ion selectivity with high precision has long been pursued for fundamental bioinspired engineering and applications such as in ion separation and energy conversion. However, it remains a challenge to develop artificial ion channels to achieve single-ion selectivity comparable to their biological analogs, especially for high Na+/K+ selectivity. Here, we report an artificial sodium channel by subnanoconfinement of 4′-aminobenzo-15-crown-5 ethers (15C5s) into ~6-Å-sized metal-organic framework subnanochannel (MOFSNC). The resulting 15C5-MOFSNC shows an unprecedented Na+/K+ selectivity of tens to 102 and Na+/Li+ selectivity of 103 under multicomponent permeation conditions, comparable to biological sodium channels. A co–ion-responsive single-file transport mechanism in 15C-MOFSNC is proposed for the preferential transport of Na+ over K+ due to the synergetic effects of size exclusion, charge selectivity, local hydrophobicity, and preferential binding with functional groups. This study provides an alternative strategy for developing potential single-ion selective channels and membranes for many applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7a89f2a5296f0439929733f8c239f3683eb9f51c</guid></item><item><title>Construction of angstrom-scale ion channels with versatile pore configurations and sizes by metal-organic frameworks</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/35fe453ba22d443eef31b132ec1952206ce35284</link><description>The fabrication of synthetic nanochannels for ion separation is challenging. Here, the authors synthesize angstrom-scale ion channels featuring one-dimensional to three-dimensional pore configurations by growing metal‒organic frameworks into nanochannels; the structure of the pore influences the ion transport performance. Controllable fabrication of angstrom-size channels has been long desired to mimic biological ion channels for the fundamental study of ion transport. Here we report a strategy for fabricating angstrom-scale ion channels with one-dimensional (1D) to three-dimensional (3D) pore structures by the growth of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) into nanochannels. The 1D MIL-53 channels of flexible pore sizes around 5.2 × 8.9 Å can transport cations rapidly, with one to two orders of magnitude higher conductivities and mobilities than MOF channels of hybrid pore configurations and sizes, including Al-TCPP with 1D ~8 Å channels connected by 2D ~6 Å interlayers, and 3D UiO-66 channels of ~6 Å windows and 9 − 12 Å cavities. Furthermore, the 3D MOF channels exhibit better ion sieving properties than those of 1D and 2D MOF channels. Theoretical simulations reveal that ion transport through 2D and 3D MOF channels should undergo multiple dehydration-rehydration processes, resulting in higher energy barriers than pure 1D channels. These findings offer a platform for studying ion transport properties at angstrom-scale confinement and provide guidelines for improving the efficiency of ionic separations and nanofluidics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/35fe453ba22d443eef31b132ec1952206ce35284</guid></item><item><title>Influencing Molecular Dynamics Simulations of Ion-Exchange Membranes by Considering Comonomer Propagation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9b2fc236d7bd795c22732f291ebc8961435d5342</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9b2fc236d7bd795c22732f291ebc8961435d5342</guid></item><item><title>A Reduced-Order Model of Concentration Polarization in Reverse Osmosis Systems with Feed Spacers</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9f39b0f4d4981c597556c996daf236582aa11046</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9f39b0f4d4981c597556c996daf236582aa11046</guid></item><item><title>Accounting for Ion Pairing Effects on Sulfate Salt Sorption in Cation Exchange Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a3c25d2443b65f840f3e93092f8208321a81689e</link><description>Ion exchange membranes (IEMs) are frequently used in water treatment and electrochemical applications, with their ion separation properties largely governed by equilibrium ion partitioning between a membrane and contiguous solution. Despite an expansive literature on IEMs, the influence of electrolyte association (i.e., ion pairing) on ion sorption remains relatively unexplored. In this study, salt sorption in two commercial cation exchange membranes equilibrated with 0.01-1.0 M MgSO4 and Na2SO4 is investigated experimentally and theoretically. Association measurements of salt solutions using conductometric experiments and the Stokes-Einstein approximation show significant concentrations of ion pairs in MgSO4 and Na2SO4 relative to those in simple electrolytes (i.e., NaCl), which is consistent with prior studies of sulfate salts. The Manning/Donnan model, developed and validated for halide salts in previous studies, substantially underpredicts sulfate sorption measurements, presumably due to ion pairing effects not accounted for in this established theory. These findings suggest that ion pairing can enhance salt sorption in IEMs due to partitioning of reduced valence species. By reformulating the Donnan and Manning models, a theoretical framework for predicting salt sorption in IEMs that explicitly considers electrolyte association is developed. Remarkably, theoretical predictions of sulfate sorption are improved by over an order of magnitude by accounting for ion speciation. In some cases, good quantitative agreement is observed between theoretical and experimental values for external salt concentrations between 0.1 and 1.0 M using no adjustable parameters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a3c25d2443b65f840f3e93092f8208321a81689e</guid></item><item><title>Nanostructure‐Derived Antireflectivity in Leafhopper Brochosomes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0fbd4da09d53b3cb98c710590c0fe78fecf9ac28</link><description>Understanding how insect‐derived biomaterials interact with light has led to new advances and interdisciplinary insights in entomology and physics. Leafhoppers are insects that coat themselves with highly ordered biological nanostructures known as brochosomes. Brochosomes are thought to provide a range of protective properties to leafhoppers, such as hydrophobicity and antireflectivity, which has inspired the development of synthetic brochosomes that mimic their structures. Despite recent progress, the high antireflective properties of brochosome structures are not fully understood. Herein, a combination of experiments and computational modeling is used to understand the structure‐, material‐, and polarization‐dependent optical properties of brochosomes modeled on the geometries found in three leafhopper species. The results qualitatively represent that light interference interaction with nanostructures naturally occurring in brochosomes is responsible for the spectral tuning and the asymmetric line shape of the reflectance spectra. Whereas prior work has focused on the computational modeling of idealized pitted particles, this work shows that light–matter interactions with brochosome structures can be tuned by varying the geometry of their cage‐like nanoscale features and by changing the arrangement of multiparticle assemblies. Broadly, this work establishes principles for the guided design of new optically active materials inspired by these unique insect nanostructures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0fbd4da09d53b3cb98c710590c0fe78fecf9ac28</guid></item><item><title>FUNDAMENTAL STRUCTURE/PROPERTY STUDIES OF GAS SEPARATION MEMBRANE POLYMERS</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a791bf2d73342b1686df10fb274d51dfbcd2a9cb</link><description>Work in 2012-2013 focused on studying gas permeability, diffusivity and solubility of polyimides and thermally rearranged (TR) polymers based on 3,3’-dihydroxy-4,4’diaminobiphenyl (HAB) and 2,2’-bis-(3,4-dicarboxyphenyl) hexafluoropropane dianhydride (6FDA). To determine the effect of temperature on gas sorption, we studied H2 sorption in the HAB-6FDA polyimide and 3 partially converted HAB-6FDA TR polymers. Increasing conversion increased gas solubility by approximately a factor of 2.6, which is similar to that of other nonpolar gases. Furthermore, in comparing H2 sorption in HAB-6FDA with that of other polymers commonly considered for membrane applications, the HAB-6FDA TR polymers had the highest H2 sorption. Similar studies are under way with other gases relevant for gas separations applications. We also investigated the effect of the size of the reactive leaving group and synthesis route on transport properties in TR polymers. In general, bulkier reactive leaving groups contribute to increased gas permeability in TR polymers compared to TR polymers synthesized from hydroxyl-functional leaving groups. Furthermore, we investigated samples with identical leaving groups but synthesized from two different routes. These tests showed that the leaving group on the polyimide has more of an effect on gas transport than that of synthesis route. We are also measuring mixed gas performance of these polymers and have found, in many cases, situations where CO2/CH4 mixed gas selectivity is actually higher than the selectivity calculated based on pure gas permeability values. The fundamental basis for this observation is under investigation. Fundamental Structure/Property Studies of Gas Separation Membrane Polymers Freeman – University of Texas at Austin Hydrogen Fuel Cells 2 DOE Hydrogen and Fuel Cells Program 2013 Annual Merit Review and Peer Evaluation Meeting To broaden the framework of this study, we investigated H2 sorption in other polymers commonly studied for membrane applications (c.f., Figure 1B). Matrimid, which is of the same family of polymers as HAB-6FDA (i.e., polyimides), had nearly identical gas sorption to that of the HAB-6FDA polyimide. Amorphous Teflon (AF 2400) had H2 sorption between that of the TR 350 60min and TR 400 60min sample. Polysulfone had the lowest H2 sorption, and poly(dimethylsiloxane) (PDMS), which was the only rubbery polymer considered, had a slightly endothermic enthalpy of sorption, as indicated by the negative correlation between gas solubility and 1000/T. From these results, accurate diffusion coefficients for H2 sorption in these polymers can be determined. As we have shown for other gases in TR polymers, increases in gas permeability from thermal rearrangement for H2 are largely a result of increases in gas diffusivity. Effect of Reactive Leaving and Synthesis Route Group on Transport Properties Thermal rearrangement occurs at elevated temperatures for precursor polyimides with reactive ortho-position functional groups. We have previously reported that there is an effect of precursor synthesis route and/or the reactive leaving group on TR polymer transport properties. To decouple these two variables, we pursued a unique organic synthesis approach to synthesize TR polymer precursors from identical synthesis routes but with different reactive Progress Report Hydrogen Sorption Polymers for Membrane Applications Hydrogen separation is used in many industrially significant gas separation applications such as oxo-chemical synthesis, refinery off-gas purification, and syngas ratio adjustment. However, because H2 has a small kinetic diameter (2.89Å) and one of the lowest critical temperatures, Tc (33K), the effect of polymer structure on hydrogen diffusion and solubility is difficult to determine because solubility is so low. Challenges in determining these fundamental gas transport parameters have hindered the polymer membrane field from advancing our understanding of polymer structure on hydrogen transport. To investigate H2 sorption, we used a high precision magnetic suspension balance to determine H2 sorption as a function of temperature in a series of HAB-6FDA TR polymers with increasing conversion. As shown in Figure 1A, gas solubility increased by approximately a factor of 2.6 between the polyimide and most highly converted TR polymer (TR 450 30min), so the relative change in H2 sorption as a function of thermal rearrangement is similar to that of other nonpolar gases such as O2, N2, and CH4. Notably, the increase in H2 sorption does not track with increases in gas sorption for quadrupolar gases, such as CO2, whose solubility increases by a factor of 1.7 between the HAB6FDA polyimide and TR 450 30min sample. Figure 1. Hydrogen solubility in (A) HAB-6FDA as a function of thermal rearrangement, and (B) additional polymers frequently used for membrane applications. In Figure A, Polyimide stands for the HAB-6FDA polyimide, and partially converted TR polymers are represented by the temperature and time at which they have been rearranged. For example, TR 450 30min indicates a sample of HAB-6FDA that has been converted at 450°C for 30min. For Figure B, AF 2400 is amorphous Teflon AF 2400 and PDMS is poly(dimethylsiloxane). A 0.04 0.06 0.08 0.1 0.3 0.5 2.6 2.8 3 3.2 3.4 3.6 3.8 4 S (c m 3 ( ST P) /c m 3 ( po ly m er ) a tm ) 1000/T (K) TR 450 30min TR 400 60min</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a791bf2d73342b1686df10fb274d51dfbcd2a9cb</guid></item><item><title>Cation-polymer interactions and local heterogeneity determine the relative order of alkali cation diffusion coefficients in PEGDA hydrogels</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e918d3d028194c2d6f0b0116a592d79c71dc2dc7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e918d3d028194c2d6f0b0116a592d79c71dc2dc7</guid></item><item><title>Moisture-driven CO2 pump for direct air capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a7a03c796d40a3fa7c27b0ddcb1d28b19718b409</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a7a03c796d40a3fa7c27b0ddcb1d28b19718b409</guid></item><item><title>Quaternary Ammonium-Functionalized Poly(Arylene Ether Sulfone) Random Copolymers for Direct Air Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6fb5229775233cfd3e8867c5036671168171170a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6fb5229775233cfd3e8867c5036671168171170a</guid></item></channel></rss>