<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Chuyang Tang</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/2237102582</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Chuyang Tang</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:48:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MOF-derived Co3O4/g-C3N4 membrane with synergistic Photo-Fenton-like effect: Overcoming the reactivity-permeability trade-off for high-performance water purification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/50220f57d085c742a7bc0abd33367c64f43a8602</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/50220f57d085c742a7bc0abd33367c64f43a8602</guid></item><item><title>A facile preparation of novel positively charged MOF/chitosan nanofiltration membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/38164dd7351d1bfb85f0ef29d57b30d74a757c4a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/38164dd7351d1bfb85f0ef29d57b30d74a757c4a</guid></item><item><title>Atmospheric pressure atomic layer deposition for tight ceramic nanofiltration membranes: Synthesis and application in water purification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9b39ab15004bda26739f8f40bc3aaf0635625426</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9b39ab15004bda26739f8f40bc3aaf0635625426</guid></item><item><title>Nanofoaming of Polyamide Desalination Membranes To Tune Permeability and Selectivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/43f1f8de49f0a4a1910982afb60bdec88f0d5ba1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/43f1f8de49f0a4a1910982afb60bdec88f0d5ba1</guid></item><item><title>Optimization of Self-Adaptive INR-MPPT for R-Mode RED Stacks</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6b849c836242d40659e01939b8b93875236cbdf4</link><description>This paper presents a self-adaptive incremental-resistance maximum-power-point-tracking (INR-MPPT) method to achieve maximum power extraction from a recycle-mode (R-mode) operating reverse-electrodialysis (RED) stack. By considering the electrical characteristics of the R-mode RED stack, the design principle of the INR-MPPT method, which involves its scaling factor and sampling period, to ensure both fast response and system stability, is discussed. The validity of the proposed INR-MPPT method is verified by simulation and experiments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6b849c836242d40659e01939b8b93875236cbdf4</guid></item><item><title>Gas station in blood vessels: An endothelium mimicking, self-sustainable nitric oxide fueling stent coating for prevention of thrombosis and restenosis.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3fa16e5113dbe7576cb654507ad2ace93b30a7ca</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3fa16e5113dbe7576cb654507ad2ace93b30a7ca</guid></item><item><title>Enhancing the removal of organic micropollutants by nanofiltration membrane with Fe (III)-tannic acid interlayer: Mechanisms and environmental implications.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ee6a62f041444246dfb436fc45bc5875f4a95aba</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ee6a62f041444246dfb436fc45bc5875f4a95aba</guid></item><item><title>Precisely regulated in-plane pore sizes of Co-MOF nanosheet membranes for efficient dye recovery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1dc7cd6c68f0ff37cd967602866e8cdfd0d660e6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1dc7cd6c68f0ff37cd967602866e8cdfd0d660e6</guid></item><item><title>Precise Regulation of Monomer Reactive Sites Enhances the Water Permeance and Membrane Selectivity of Polyamide Nanofiltration Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98f8975e6dc2d6809483789a3a9f56fc4edbe703</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98f8975e6dc2d6809483789a3a9f56fc4edbe703</guid></item><item><title>Lamellar crosslinking reinforced strategy to prepare 2D metal-organic framework membranes for ultra-fast and robust molecules/ions separation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ad8ab0583e6e38080eedf364151a7f53e72fddf8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ad8ab0583e6e38080eedf364151a7f53e72fddf8</guid></item><item><title>New directions on membranes for removal and degradation of emerging pollutants in aqueous systems.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b2f5ebbbc5f61dfa97aa8964f6a0dfb60b021e5</link><description>Emerging pollutants (EPs) refer to a group of non-regulated chemical or biological substances that have been recently introduced or detected in the environment. These pollutants tend to exhibit resistance to conventional treatment methods and can persist in the environment for prolonged periods, posing potential adverse effects on ecosystems and human health. As we enter a new era of managing these pollutants, membrane-based technologies hold significant promise in mitigating impact of EPs on the environment and safeguarding human health due to their high selectivity, efficiency, cost-effectiveness and capability for simultaneous separation and degradation. Moreover, these technologies continue to evolve rapidly with the development of new membrane materials and functionalities, advanced treatment strategies, and analyses for effectively treating EPs of more recent concerns. The objective of this review is to present the latest directions and advancements in membrane-based technologies for addressing EPs. By highlighting the progress in this field, we aim to share valuable perspectives with researchers and contribute to the development of future directions in sustainable treatments for EPs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b2f5ebbbc5f61dfa97aa8964f6a0dfb60b021e5</guid></item><item><title>Photogenerated outer electric field induced electrophoresis of organic nanocrystals for effective solid-solid photocatalysis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/baf2320e60031919c879ddb7411cf41ab7b067c2</link><description>Charge accumulation in organic photocatalysts leads to an overlooked macroscopic particle migration, crucial for heterogeneous photocatalytic kinetics. Authors demonstrate self-driven electrophoresis of organic nanocrystals via rationally designed photogenerated outer electric field (OEF). Rapid mass transfer in solid-solid reactions is crucial for catalysis. Although phoretic nanoparticles offer potential for increased collision efficiency between solids, their implementation is hindered by limited interaction ranges. Here, we present a self-driven long-range electrophoresis of organic nanocrystals facilitated by a rationally designed photogenerated outer electric field (OEF) on their surface. Employing perylene-3,4,9,10-tetracarboxylic dianhydride (PTCDA) molecular nanocrystals as a model, we demonstrate that a directional OEF with an intensity of 13.6-0.4 kV m^−1 across a range of 25–200 μm. This OEF-driven targeted electrophoresis of PTCDA nanocrystals onto the microplastic surface enhances the activity for subsequent decomposition of microplastics (196.8 mg h^−1) into CO_2 by solid-solid catalysis. As supported by operando characterizations and theoretical calculations, the OEF surrounds PTCDA nanocrystals initially, directing from the electron-rich (0 1 1) to the hole-rich $$(11\bar{2})$$ ( 11 2 ¯ ) surface. Upon surface charge modulation, the direction of OEF changes toward the solid substrate. The OEF-driven electrophoretic effect in organic nanocrystals with anisotropic charge enrichment characteristics indicates potential advancements in realizing effective solid-solid photocatalysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/baf2320e60031919c879ddb7411cf41ab7b067c2</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced metronidazole removal in seawater using a single-chamber bioelectrochemical system.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ef52856bed6902e193ca35824d7d375d09e94ce5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ef52856bed6902e193ca35824d7d375d09e94ce5</guid></item><item><title>Efficient oil recovery from emulsions through PDMS decorated nanofibrous membranes via aggregation-release demulsification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/983be635f45ba2c269b84f5a330d449be5ec27ba</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/983be635f45ba2c269b84f5a330d449be5ec27ba</guid></item><item><title>Generation of holes from intra-valence band for enhanced oxidation potentials under visible light</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2cd8252d7291a300760847cf2e238dcf5d348a08</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2cd8252d7291a300760847cf2e238dcf5d348a08</guid></item><item><title>Resource utilization of coal chemical waste salt by bipolar membrane electrodialysis with thermal pretreatment</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99a948b1efac2aff68e98143100794404fc4e55e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99a948b1efac2aff68e98143100794404fc4e55e</guid></item><item><title>Empowering ultrathin polyamide membranes at the water-energy nexus: strategies, limitations, and future perspectives.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a7de01fbfea592330f854e7045176010f7551b91</link><description>Membrane-based separation is one of the most energy-efficient methods to meet the growing need for a significant amount of fresh water. It is also well-known for its applications in water treatment, desalination, solvent recycling, and environmental remediation. Most typical membranes used for separation-based applications are thin-film composite membranes created using polymers, featuring a top selective layer generated by employing the interfacial polymerization technique at an aqueous-organic interface. In the last decade, various manufacturing techniques have been developed in order to create high-specification membranes. Among them, the creation of ultrathin polyamide membranes has shown enormous potential for achieving a significant increase in the water permeation rate, translating into major energy savings in various applications. However, this great potential of ultrathin membranes is greatly hindered by undesired transport phenomena such as the geometry-induced "funnel effect" arising from the substrate membrane, severely limiting the actual permeation rate. As a result, the separation capability of ultrathin membranes is still not fully unleashed or understood, and a critical assessment of their limitations and potential solutions for future studies is still lacking. Here, we provide a summary of the latest developments in the design of ultrathin polyamide membranes, which have been achieved by controlling the interfacial polymerization process and utilizing a number of novel manufacturing processes for ionic and molecular separations. Next, an overview of the in-depth assessment of their limitations resulting from the substrate membrane, along with potential solutions and future perspectives will be covered in this review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a7de01fbfea592330f854e7045176010f7551b91</guid></item><item><title>Ultrastable ceramic-based metal–organic framework membranes with missing linkers for robust desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7ca9d40ea9de365eb179ee629a5546d0678c79a9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7ca9d40ea9de365eb179ee629a5546d0678c79a9</guid></item><item><title>Energy harvesting from acid mine drainage using a highly proton/ion-selective thin polyamide film.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/32441497db3a7a7356869e8ed2864fa8e1d68f08</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/32441497db3a7a7356869e8ed2864fa8e1d68f08</guid></item><item><title>Engraving Polyamide Layers by In Situ Self-Etchable CaCO3 Nanoparticles Enhances Separation Properties and Antifouling Performance of Reverse Osmosis Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d91dabe6a648f83bebd3f15317ad53a1413621bb</link><description>Nanovoids within a polyamide layer play an important role in the separation performance of thin-film composite (TFC) reverse osmosis (RO) membranes. To form more extensive nanovoids for enhanced performance, one commonly used method is to incorporate sacrificial nanofillers in the polyamide layer during the exothermic interfacial polymerization (IP) reaction, followed by some post-etching processes. However, these post-treatments could harm the membrane integrity, thereby leading to reduced selectivity. In this study, we applied in situ self-etchable sacrificial nanofillers by taking advantage of the strong acid and heat generated in IP. CaCO3 nanoparticles (nCaCO3) were used as the model nanofillers, which can be in situ etched by reacting with H+ to leave void nanostructures behind. This reaction can further degas CO2 nanobubbles assisted by heat in IP to form more nanovoids in the polyamide layer. These nanovoids can facilitate water transport by enlarging the effective surface filtration area of the polyamide and reducing hydraulic resistance to significantly enhance water permeance. The correlations between the nanovoid properties and membrane performance were systematically analyzed. We further demonstrate that the nCaCO3-tailored membrane can improve membrane antifouling propensity and rejections to boron and As(III) compared with the control. This study investigated a novel strategy of applying self-etchable gas precursors to engrave the polyamide layer for enhanced membrane performance, which provides new insights into the design and synthesis of TFC membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d91dabe6a648f83bebd3f15317ad53a1413621bb</guid></item><item><title>Membrane capacitive deionization (MCDI) for selective ion separation and recovery: Fundamentals, challenges, and opportunities</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/65253ed795815e62a88b99b2bb0ba0e139ced9dc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/65253ed795815e62a88b99b2bb0ba0e139ced9dc</guid></item><item><title>Covalent organic framework membranes modified by end-capping monomers for organic solvent nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b2043804de8ac20737c0df4d9a8219a847e1a9ae</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b2043804de8ac20737c0df4d9a8219a847e1a9ae</guid></item><item><title>Polar Solvent-Induced Spontaneous Nanofoaming for Synthesizing Ultra-High-Performance Polyamide Nanofiltration Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/56690181a80eb2a1665303d1beb84e70a087a55a</link><description>Nanofiltration membranes with both high water permeance and selectivity are perpetually studied because of their applications in water purification. However, these two critical attributes are considered to be mutually exclusive. Here, we introduce a polar solvent, dichloromethane, in place of the apolar hexane used for decades as the organic phase for membrane interfacial polymerization synthesis to solve this dilemma. When a polar solvent as the organic phase is combined with a solvent-resistant aramid nanofibrous hydrogel film as the water phase, monomer enrichment in the reaction zone leads to a polyamide nanofiltration membrane with densely distributed nanobubble features, enhanced nanoporosity, and a loosened backbone. Benefiting from these structural features, the resulting membrane exhibits superior properties with a combination of high water permeance (52.7 L m-2 h-1 bar-1) and selectivity (water/Na2SO4, 36 bar-1; NaCl/Na2SO4, 357 bar-1), outperforming traditional nanofiltration membranes. We envision that this novel technology involving polar solvent systems and the water phase of nanofibrous hydrogel would provide new opportunities for membrane development for environmental engineering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/56690181a80eb2a1665303d1beb84e70a087a55a</guid></item><item><title>Covalently modified MoS2 for the fabrication of interlayered thin film composite membranes with excellent structural stability against swelling and drying in organic solvent nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e68a3d16da3b19e94e3fbbf3c1f3bd1e7b900edd</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e68a3d16da3b19e94e3fbbf3c1f3bd1e7b900edd</guid></item><item><title>Electricity-driven synergistic sulfur recovery and sulfate elimination in seawater</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7e477ff27de7312a8579a569d109950fe601a16f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7e477ff27de7312a8579a569d109950fe601a16f</guid></item><item><title>Activating Biocake Communities Retards Jumps of Transmembrane Pressure in Membrane Bioreactors.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4756d0972132ec105263a0331c31d5add241cce6</link><description>Sudden jump of transmembrane pressure (TMP) in membrane bioreactors (MBRs), associated with abrupt aggravation of membrane fouling, limits practical applications of MBRs and calls for effective mitigation strategies. While the TMP jump is generally related to the bacterial activity of biocakes, the mechanisms underlying the TMP jump remain unclear. Herein, we conducted various backwash protocols with different nutrient (e.g., nitrate and sodium acetate) loadings on fouled membranes in MBRs to reveal the critical role of bacterial activity of biocakes for the TMP jump. The filtration tests showed a lower TMP jump rate for the membrane backwashed with a nutrient solution (a mixture of 180 mg/L NaNO3 and 200 mg/L NaAc, averaged at 1.40 kPa/d) than that backwashed with tap water (averaged at 3.56 kPa/d), implying that TMP jump could be efficiently mitigated by providing sufficient nutrients to biocake bacteria. The characterization of biocakes showed that high-nutrient solution backwash considerably increased bacterial viability and activity, while considerably reducing biomolecule accumulation on membranes. The keystone taxa (e.g., g_Aeromonas and o_Chitinophagaceae) in the network of nutrient-enriched biocake communities were involved in nitrate reduction and biomolecule degradation. Ecological null model analyses revealed that the deterministic manner mainly shaped biocake communities with high-nutrient availability. Overall, this study highlights the significance of the bacterial activity of biocakes for TMP development and provides potential alternatives for controlling membrane fouling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4756d0972132ec105263a0331c31d5add241cce6</guid></item><item><title>Reconstructing Electrically Conductive Nanofiltration Membranes with an Aniline-Functionalized Carbon Nanotubes Interlayer for Highly Effective Toxic Organic Treatment.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cd4dfb951907474993777c0b3ef469fda5e40cfc</link><description>Conductive nanofiltration (CNF) membranes hold great promise for removing small organic pollutants from water through enhanced Donnan exclusion and electrocatalytic degradation. However, current CNF membranes face limitations in conductivity, structural stability, and nanochannel control strategies. This work addresses these challenges by introducing aniline-functionalized carbon nanotubes (NH2-CNTs) as an interlayer. NH2-CNTs enhance the dispersibility and adhesion of pristine carbon nanotubes, leading to a more conductive and stable composite nanofiltration membrane. The redesigned NH2-CNTs interlayered conductive nanofiltration (NICNF) membrane exhibits a 10-fold increase in conductivity and a high response degree (80%) with excellent cyclic stability, surpassing existing CNF membranes. The synergistic effects of enhanced Donnan exclusion, voltage switching, and electrocatalysis enable the NICNF membrane to achieve selective recovery of mixed dyes, 98.97% removal of residual wastewater toxicity, and a 5.2-fold increase in permeance compared to the commercial NF270 membrane. This research paves the way for next-generation multifunctional membranes capable of the efficient recovery and degradation of toxic organic pollutants in wastewater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cd4dfb951907474993777c0b3ef469fda5e40cfc</guid></item><item><title>Metallic 1T/1T′ phase TMD nanosheets with enhanced chemisorption sites for ultrahigh-efficiency lead removal</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b1f3b427852daa3e5700e1692c418530746a9153</link><description>Two-dimensional (2D) materials, as adsorbents, have garnered great attention in removing heavy metal ions (HMIs) from drinking water due to their extensive exposed adsorption sites. Nevertheless, there remains a paucity of experimental research to remarkably unlock their adsorption capabilities and fully elucidate their adsorption mechanisms. In this work, exceptional lead ion (Pb2+) (a common HMI) removal capacity (up to 758 mg g−1) is achieved using our synthesized metallic 1T/1T′ phase 2D transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD, including MoS2, WS2, TaS2, and TiS2) nanosheets, which hold tremendous activated S chemisorption sites. The residual Pb2+ concentration can be reduced from 2 mg L−1 to 2 μg L−1 within 0.5 min, meeting the drinking water standards following World Health Organization guideline (Pb2+ concentrations &lt;10 μg L−1). Atomic-scale characterizations and calculations based on density functional theory unveil that Pb2+ bond to the top positions of transition metal atoms in a single-atom form through the formation of S-Pb bonds. Point-of-use (POU) devices fabricated by our reported metallic phase MoS2 nanosheets exhibit treatment capacity of 55 L-water g−1-adsorbent for feed Pb2+ concentration of 1 mg L−1, which is 1-3 orders of magnitude higher than other 2D materials and commercial activated carbon. 2D materials are known for their ability to remove heavy metal ions from water, however their adsorption mechanism is not well-understood. Here the authors prepared metallic 1T/1T′ phase 2D transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets, with activated sulfur sites, for rapid removal of Pb2+ ions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b1f3b427852daa3e5700e1692c418530746a9153</guid></item><item><title>Strong and high-conductivity hydrogels with all-polymer nanofibrous networks for applications as high-capacitance flexible electrodes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9118356b1293cc8fd36e80880f27512600806436</link><description>Flexible devices, such as soft bioelectronics and stretchable supercapacitors, have their practical performance limited by electrodes which are desired to have high conductivity and capacitance, outstanding mechanical flexibility and strength, great electrochemical stability, and good biocompatibility. Here, we report a simple and efficient method to synthesize a nanostructured conductive hydrogel to meet such criteria. Specifically, templated by a hyperconnective nanofibrous network from aramid hydrogels, the conducting polymer, polypyrrole, assembles conformally onto nanofibers through in-situ polymerization, generating continuous nanostructured conductive pathways. The resulting conductive hydrogel shows superior conductivity (72 S cm−1) and fracture strength (27.2 MPa). Supercapacitor electrodes utilizing this hydrogel exhibit high specific capacitance (240 F g−1) and cyclic stability. Furthermore, bioelectrodes of patterned hydrogels provide favorable bioelectronic interfaces, allowing high-quality electrophysiological recording and stimulation in physiological environments. These high-performance electrodes are readily scalable to applications of energy and power systems, healthcare and medical technologies, smart textiles, and so forth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9118356b1293cc8fd36e80880f27512600806436</guid></item><item><title>Iron Nanoparticles-Confined Graphene Oxide Membranes Coupled with Sulfite-Based Advanced Reduction Processes for Highly Efficient and Stable Removal of Bromate.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7964ae1b63b93def8affa9d3c988e0b3ebc9506c</link><description>Advanced reduction processes (ARPs) are promising for pollutant removal in drinking water treatment. In this study, we demonstrated highly efficient reduction of bromate, a harmful disinfection byproduct, by coupling ARPs with an iron nanoparticles-intercalated graphene oxide (GO@FeNPs) catalytic membrane. In the presence of 1.0 mM sulfite (S(IV)), the GO@FeNPs membrane/S(IV) system achieved nearly complete removal of 80 μg/L bromate in 3 min. The first-order reaction rate constant for bromate removal in this system was 420 ± 42 min-1, up to 5 orders of magnitude faster than previously reported ARPs. The GO@FeNPs catalytic membrane may offer potential advantages of nanoconfinement and facilitated electron shuttling in addition to the high surface area of the fine FeNPs, leading to the remarkable ARP performance. The GO@FeNPs membrane showed excellent stability, maintaining &gt;97.0% bromate removal over 20 cycles of repeated runs. The membrane can also be applied for fast catalytic reduction of other oxyanions, showing &gt;98.0% removal of nitrate and chlorate. This work may present a viable option for utilizing high-performance reductive catalytic membranes for water decontamination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7964ae1b63b93def8affa9d3c988e0b3ebc9506c</guid></item><item><title>Ultra-permeable silk-based polymeric membranes for vacuum-driven nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f8354351bcc90cec215dc30b6c0692b267be8acc</link><description>Nanofiltration (NF) membranes are commonly supplied in spiral-wound modules, resulting in numerous drawbacks for practical applications (e.g., high operating pressure/pressure drop/costs). Vacuum-driven NF could be a promising and low-cost alternative by utilizing simple components and operating under an ultra-low vacuum pressure (&lt;1 bar). Nevertheless, existing commercial membranes are incapable of achieving practically relevant water flux in such a system. Herein, we fabricated a silk-based membrane with a crumpled and defect-free rejection layer, showing water permeance of 96.2 ± 10 L m−2 h−1 bar−1 and a Na2SO4 rejection of 96.0 ± 0.6% under cross-flow filtration mode. In a vacuum-driven system, the membrane demonstrates a water flux of 56.8 ± 7.1 L m−2 h−1 at a suction pressure of 0.9 bar and high removal rate against various contaminants. Through analysis, silk-based ultra-permeable membranes may offer close to 80% reduction in specific energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions compared to a commercial benchmark, holding great promise for advancing a more energy-efficient and greener water treatment process and paving the avenue for practical application in real industrial settings. Vacuum-driven nanofiltration (NF) is a promising and low-cost alternative to pressure driven NF but existing commercial membranes currently not achieve any relevant water flux in such a system. Here, the authors fabricate a silk-based membrane with a crumpled and defect-free rejection layer, showing high flux and salt rejection rate under cross-flow filtration mode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f8354351bcc90cec215dc30b6c0692b267be8acc</guid></item><item><title>Ultrafast complete dechlorination enabled by ferrous oxide/graphene oxide catalytic membranes via nanoconfinement advanced reduction</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9efff063340e27ef58270caf5154424dbc983f22</link><description>Chlorinated organic pollutants widely exist in aquatic environments and threaten human health. Catalytic approaches are proposed for their elimination, but sluggish degradation, incomplete dechlorination, and catalyst recovery remain extremely challenging. Here we show efficient dechlorination using ferrous oxide/graphene oxide catalytic membranes with strong nanoconfinement effects. Catalytic membranes are constructed by graphene oxide nanosheets with integrated ultrafine and monodisperse sub-5 nm nanoparticles through simple in-situ growth and filtration assembly. Density function theory simulation reveals that nanoconfinement effects remarkably reduce energy barriers of rate-limiting steps for iron (III)-sulfite complex dissociation to sulfite radicals and dichloroacetic acid degradation to monochloroacetic acid. Combining with nanoconfinement effects of enhancing reactants accessibility to catalysts and increasing catalyst-to-reactant ratios, the membrane achieves ultrafast and complete dechlorination of 180 µg L−1 dichloroacetic acid to chloride, with nearly 100% reduction efficiency within a record-breaking 3.9 ms, accompanied by six to seven orders of magnitude greater first-order rate constant of 51,000 min−1 than current catalysis. Meanwhile, the membranes exhibit quadrupled permeance of 48.6 L m−2 h−1 bar−1 as GO ones, because nanoparticles adjust membrane structure, chemical composition, and interlayer space. Moreover, the membranes show excellent stability over 20 cycles and universality for chlorinated organic pollutants at environmental concentrations. Catalytic removal of chlorinated pollutants is hampered by sluggish degradation, incomplete dechlorination, and poor catalyst recovery. Here, a catalytic membrane with strong nanoconfinement effects is developed for achieving ultrafast, complete, and stable dechlorination of those pollutants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9efff063340e27ef58270caf5154424dbc983f22</guid></item><item><title>Nanofoamed Polyamide Membranes: Mechanisms, Developments, and Environmental Implications.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e83d5a90334a44597fa809cdfe4c4bd6c56db635</link><description>Thin film composite (TFC) polyamide membranes have been widely applied for environmental applications, such as desalination and water reuse. The separation performance of TFC polyamide membranes strongly depends on their nanovoid-containing roughness morphology. These nanovoids not only influence the effective filtration area of the polyamide film but also regulate the water transport pathways through the film. Although there have been ongoing debates on the formation mechanisms of nanovoids, a nanofoaming theory─stipulating the shaping of polyamide roughness morphology by nanobubbles of degassed CO2 and the vapor of volatile solvents─has gained much attention in recent years. In this review, we provide a comprehensive summary of the nanofoaming mechanism, including related fundamental principles and strategies to tailor nanovoid formation for improved membrane separation performance. The effects of nanovoids on the fouling behaviors of TFC membranes are also discussed. In addition, numerical models on the role of nanovoids in regulating the water transport pathways toward improved water permeance and antifouling ability are highlighted. The comprehensive summary on the nanofoaming mechanism in this review provides insightful guidelines for the future design and optimization of TFC polyamide membranes toward various environmental applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e83d5a90334a44597fa809cdfe4c4bd6c56db635</guid></item><item><title>Hydrogel-embedded vertically aligned metal-organic framework nanosheet membrane for efficient water harvesting</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/00504e7652b76bc1001971f8c6575d10c6dc7ce0</link><description>Highly porous metal-organic framework (MOF) nanosheets have shown promising potential for efficient water sorption kinetics in atmospheric water harvesting (AWH) systems. However, the water uptake of single-component MOF absorbents remains limited due to their low water retention. To overcome this limitation, we present a strategy for fabricating vertically aligned MOF nanosheets on hydrogel membrane substrates (MOF-CT/PVA) to achieve ultrafast AWH with high water uptake. By employing directional growth of MOF nanosheets, we successfully create superhydrophilic MOF coating layer and pore channels for efficient water transportation to the crosslinked flexible hydrogel membrane. The designed composite water harvester exhibits ultrafast sorption kinetics, achieving 91.4% saturation within 15 min. Moreover, MOF-CT/PVA exhibits superior solar-driven water capture-release capacity even after 10 cycles of reuse. This construction approach significantly enhances the water vapor adsorption, offering a potential solution for the design of composite MOF-membrane harvesters to mitigate the freshwater crisis. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have shown promising potential in water harvesting, but the water uptake of single-component MOFs remains limited. Here, authors fabricate vertically aligned MOF nanosheets on hydrogel membranes to achieve ultrafast water harvesting with high water uptake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/00504e7652b76bc1001971f8c6575d10c6dc7ce0</guid></item><item><title>A Novel Shear-Detachment Approach for Modeling Dynamics of Membrane Cleaning.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b0dc8233611498227cf3288b0643090dac3db0c8</link><description>We report a novel shear-detachment (SD) approach to simulate the dynamics of flux recovery in the membrane cleaning process. In this model, the rate of foulant detachment away from the membrane is governed by both the shear intensity and the probability of successful foulant detachment, with the latter modeled by Boltzmann distribution. Our SD predictions exhibit good agreement with experimental results, accurately capturing the dynamics of flux recovery. Modeling outcomes reveal that the time required for fully restoring water flux is largely independent of the initial cake mass but significantly dependent on crossflow-flushing velocity and adhesive energy of foulant to membrane. Higher flushing velocity and/or lower adhesive energy can create a shear-limited condition where almost all shear events bring about successful foulant detachment, facilitating rapid flux recovery. Conversely, a smaller flushing velocity or greater adhesive energy can result in increasingly detachment-limited situations, where the cleaning efficiency is primarily dictated by the probability of foulant detachment. Our study offers profound insights into the importance of shear rate and detachment probability in governing foulant detachment kinetics and self-cleaning behavior, which carry significant implications for membrane preparation and process operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b0dc8233611498227cf3288b0643090dac3db0c8</guid></item><item><title>Precise manipulation of iron spin states in single-atom catalytic membranes for singlet oxygen selective production.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/438a2d298ffa6ca4800530ac7b7f837f085fd6e1</link><description>Heterogeneous single-atom catalysts are attracting substantial attention for selectively generating singlet oxygen (1O2). However, precise manipulation of atom coordination structures remains challenging. Here, the fine coordination structure of iron single-atom carbon-nitride catalysts (Fe-CNs) was manipulated by precisely tuning the heating rate with 1 °C min-1 difference. Multiple techniques in combination with density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that FeN6 coordination sites with high Fe spin states promote the adsorption, electron transfer, and dissociation of peroxymonosulfate (PMS), resulting in nearly 100% selection of 1O2 generation. A lamellar single atom catalytic membrane is constructed, exhibiting high permeance, high degradation, high-salinity resistance and sustained operation stability. This work provides ideas for regulating spin states of the metal site to fabricate catalysts with selective 1O2 generation for membrane separation and environment catalysis applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/438a2d298ffa6ca4800530ac7b7f837f085fd6e1</guid></item><item><title>Effect of Reaction Interface Structure on the Morphology and Performance of Thin-Film Composite Membrane.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c57d572fdc862cdf6326fc139003ad87b43fc31d</link><description>Thin-film composite (TFC) membrane has been extensively utilized and investigated for its excellent properties. Herein, we have constructed an active layer (AL) containing cave-like structures utilizing large meniscus interface. Furthermore, the impact of interface structure on the growth process, morphology, and effective surface area of AL has been fully explored with the assistance of sodium dodecyl benzenesulfonate (SDBS). The SDBS-induced nanobubbles continuously facilitated the migration of the top layer of AL toward the upper space. During this process, the surface area of sunken AL in the cave-like structures initially exhibited an increase and then a decrease. Additionally, the larger interface significantly enhanced the surface area and delayed the rise in the top layer of AL in the cave-like structures. Therefore, the TFC membrane, utilizing a substrate with a pore size of 1.00 μm and assisted by 0.30 mM SDBS, exhibited remarkable flux enhancement (&gt;63%) and reduced reverse sodium salt flux (&gt;35%) in a forward osmosis system. Moreover, the roughness factor was introduced to directly quantify the effective surface area, which had a good correlation with the water flux. Our findings demonstrated the significant potential of utilizing substrates with a large pore size to overcome the inherent limitations of the TFC membrane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c57d572fdc862cdf6326fc139003ad87b43fc31d</guid></item><item><title>A filter inspired by deep-sea glass sponges for oil cleanup under turbulent flow</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fb542ea9a7b75668fbae834433dcb7c28fd5ad23</link><description>Oil spill disasters lead to widespread and long-lasting social, economical, environmental and ecological impacts. Technical challenges remain for conventional static adsorption due to hydrodynamic instability under complex water-flow conditions, which results in low oil-capture efficiency, time delay and oil escape. To address this issue, we design a vortex-anchored filter inspired by the anatomy of deep-sea glass sponges (E. aspergillum) by mimicking their exceptional skeletal features and filter-feeding patterns. Results demonstrate that the vortex-anchored filter can retain external turbulent-flow kinetic energy in low-speed vortical flow with small Kolmogorov microscale (85 μm) in the cavity of skeleton, leading to enhanced interfacial mass transfer and residence time by physical field synergy. It improves hydrodynamic stability by reducing Reynolds stresses in nearly quiescent wake flow. The vortex-anchored filter can realize &gt;97% capture of floating, underwater and emulsified oils stably at Reynolds numbers ranging from subcritical to supercritical regimes. This study not only highlights the importance of vortex-anchored mechanism in enhancing interfacial mass transfer and hydrodynamic stability during oil capture beyond previously known benefits of increased residence time, but also represents a paradigm shift to advance biophysically inspired strategies for in-situ, dynamic and robust cleanup of spilled oil, environmental remediation and resource recovery. The authors develop a filter for oil cleaning in turbulent flows, inspired by the skeletal structures and filter patterns of deep-sea glass sponges. This filter could capture over 97% of floating and underwater oil, even under complex hydrodynamic conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fb542ea9a7b75668fbae834433dcb7c28fd5ad23</guid></item><item><title>Lignin alkali regulated interfacial polymerization towards ultra-selective and highly permeable nanofiltration membrane</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73ab2dfb164709e7736d45aaaf9f9c95f142b85e</link><description>Thin-film composite polyamide (TFC PA) membranes hold promise for energy-efficient liquid separation, but achieving high permeance and precise separation membrane via a facile approach that is compatible with present manufacturing line remains a great challenge. Herein, we demonstrate the use of lignin alkali (LA) derived from waste of paper pulp as an aqueous phase additive to regulate interfacial polymerization (IP) process for achieving high performance nanofiltration (NF) membrane. Various characterizations and molecular dynamics simulations revealed that LA can promote the diffusion and partition of aqueous phase monomer piperazine (PIP) molecules into organic phase and their uniform dispersion on substrate, accelerating the IP reaction and promoting greater interfacial instabilities, thus endowing formation of TFC NF membrane with an ultrathin, highly cross-linked, and crumpled PA layer. The optimal membrane exhibited a remarkable water permeance of 26.0 L m-2 h-1 bar-1 and Cl-/SO42- selectivity of 191.0, which is superior to the state-of-the-art PA NF membranes. This study provides a cost-effective scalable strategy for fabricating ultra-selective and highly permeable NF membrane for precise ion-ion separation and small organic compounds removal. Achieving high permeance and precise separation in thin-film composite polyamide (TFC PA) membranes remains challenging. Here, the authors demonstrate the use of lignin alkali derived from waste of paper pulp as an aqueous phase additive to regulate interfacial polymerization process for achieving high performance nanofiltration membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73ab2dfb164709e7736d45aaaf9f9c95f142b85e</guid></item><item><title>Riding a Vascular Time Train to Spatiotemporally Attenuate Thrombosis and Restenosis by Double Presentation of Therapeutic Gas and Biomacromolecules</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a8eafa8ebcd583329e71852028f78d980af8c5f6</link><description>Endothelial injury is a common occurrence following stent implantation, often leading to complications such as restenosis and thrombosis. To address this issue, we have developed a multi‐functional stent coating that combines a dopamine‐copper (DA‐Cu) base with therapeutic biomolecule modification, including nitric oxide (NO) precursor L‐arginine, endothelial glycocalyx heparin, and endothelial cell (EC) catcher vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF). In our stent coating, the incorporated Cu acts as a sustainable catalyst for converting endogenous NO donors into NO, and the immobilized arginine serves as a precursor for NO generation under the effect of endothelial nitric oxide synthase (eNOS). The presence of heparin endows the stent coating with anticoagulant ability and enhances eNOS activity, whilst rapid capture of EC by VEGF accelerates re‐endothelialization. After in vivo implantation, the antioxidant elements and produced NO alleviate the inflammatory response, establishing a favorable healing environment. The conjugated VEGF contributes to the formation of a new and intact endothelium on the stent surface to counteract inappropriate vascular cell behaviors. The long‐lasting NO flux inhibits smooth muscle cell (SMC) migration and prevents its excessive proliferation, reducing the risk of endothelial hyperplasia. This innovative coating enables the dual delivery of VEGF and NO to target procedural vascular repair phases: promoting rapid re‐endothelialization, effectively preventing thrombosis, and suppressing inflammation and restenosis. Ultimately, this innovative coating has the potential to improve therapeutic outcomes following stent implantation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a8eafa8ebcd583329e71852028f78d980af8c5f6</guid></item><item><title>Predicting the Penetration Behavior of Colloidal Foulants into Membrane Pore Channels Using A Collision-Attachment-based Particle Capture Model</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/909fd41cdf92b143e6842ac795eae1528a9b855f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/909fd41cdf92b143e6842ac795eae1528a9b855f</guid></item><item><title>Electrostatically Enhanced Surface Segregation Boosts Anti-fouling Performance of Mixed Matrix Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8d68919570cf94cee8cd6a95b4aa0bb852d0238d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8d68919570cf94cee8cd6a95b4aa0bb852d0238d</guid></item><item><title>Ceramic-carbon Janus membrane for robust solar-thermal desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/232d97e80984cee11c6982047a0c01b53d9a27f6</link><description>The desalination performance of conventional distillation membranes is limited by insufficient stability and energy efficiency, impeding their application in sustainable water production. Herein, we report a ceramic-carbon Janus membrane with solar-thermal functionality for enhanced desalination performance, energy efficiency, and stability for hypersaline water treatment. The feed and permeate sides of this Janus membrane are designed with different properties such as wettability, conductivity, and solar-thermal conversion to enhance performance. We demonstrate that this membrane exhibits higher solar-thermal efficiency (66.8–68.8%) and water flux (3.3–5.1 L m–2 h–1) than most existing polymeric solar-thermal distillation membranes. Simulation results ascribe enhanced performance to an increased membrane surface temperature, which mitigates temperature polarization and attenuation, thus enhancing the desalination driving force. The nano-carbon membrane surface accelerates water evaporation by inducing a transition from free water to intermediate water with decreased hydrogen bonding and a lower evaporation energy barrier. Water vapor molecules transport through the membrane pores by a combined mechanism of Knudsen diffusion and viscous flow. Even for seawater and hypersaline water, the membrane exhibits stable water flux and salt rejection due to its scaling-resistant surface and stable interfacial temperature. This work provides a strategy for rationally designing next-generation Janus membranes for sustainable water purification. Conventional desalination membranes suffer from insufficient performance, stability and energy efficiency, impeding their application. Here, authors design a ceramic-carbon Janus membrane with enhanced desalination performance, energy efficiency, and operation stability for hypersaline desalination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/232d97e80984cee11c6982047a0c01b53d9a27f6</guid></item><item><title>Nanofiltration and reverse osmosis technologies for disinfection by-product removal</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/88c17f280d8697ed21ef9f2447f6770989afa7df</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/88c17f280d8697ed21ef9f2447f6770989afa7df</guid></item><item><title>Time-evolved Growth of Semi-aromatic Polyamide Nanofilms and Their Structure-performance Relationship: Mechanistic Insights and Implications for Nanofiltration Membrane Synthesis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8ffe214828f87584bc6cf6642f8a6f7e75815d55</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8ffe214828f87584bc6cf6642f8a6f7e75815d55</guid></item><item><title>Assessment of permeance and selectivity of thin-film composite polyamide membranes for diverse applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1197ddf8af18902ee9cefd8e0bd7e34d3b5a7412</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1197ddf8af18902ee9cefd8e0bd7e34d3b5a7412</guid></item><item><title>Design Ultrathin Polyamide Membranes against Funnel Effect: A Novel Zone-of-Influence-Based Approach</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3a196b2d358f6703526b9934861d5c6e347f2d55</link><description>Ultrathin polyamide membranes have gained significant attention due to their potential to achieve high water permeance. Nevertheless, their water permeance is constrained by the substrate-induced funnel effect. For years, researchers have been investigating how substrates impact membrane water permeance. However, these studies generally rely on a trial-and-error approach to find the optimal substrate porosity, which is often time-consuming and offers limited insights. To establish a more intuitive framework for membrane design, we introduced a novel zone-of-influence (ZOI)-based approach for the first time. We first analyze the distinctively different funnel behaviors for thin and thick films through numerical simulations. Thin films, characterized by small ratios of film thickness over substrate pore size (i.e., aspect ratio θ ≤ 0.5), show a highly localized influence of substrate pores and present a more severe funnel effect than thick films with θ ≫ 1. This analysis leads to the concept of ZOI–a region of polyamide over a single substrate pore with water permeation efficiency exceeding a predefined threshold value. A linear relationship between ZOI and θ was observed, which enables an intuitive design to achieve a target water permeance by simply overlapping ZOIs of multiple pores, making it far more efficient than the traditional trial-and-error approach. We further developed an analytical model based on the superposition principle to unravel the fundamental structure-performance relationship between water permeation efficiency, aspect ratio and substrate porosity. This study provides convenient design tools for optimizing ultrathin membrane structure, offering critical guidance and deep insights for the advancement of high-performance membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3a196b2d358f6703526b9934861d5c6e347f2d55</guid></item><item><title>Optical coherence tomography (OCT) as a robust technique for the non-invasive imaging in membrane-based water treatment</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6c23734c5227efae838d20289500ce5acf07a670</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6c23734c5227efae838d20289500ce5acf07a670</guid></item><item><title>Unraveling the role of funnel effect vs. gutter effect in water permeance and antifouling performance of polyamide nanofiltration membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4bc045c6f6c2538400328aa6f2ff933fb9d818a0</link><description>Conventional thin-film composite (TFC) membranes often face the inherent limitation of the funnel effect. The funnel-like transport pathway, arising from water traveling transversely in the polyamide (PA) film to reach substrate pores, greatly increases the effective transport length and impairs the available water permeance. This curved transport pathway further raises a fundamental challenge for determining PA material's intrinsic water permeability. Herein, for the first time, we present a novel method to calibrate the intrinsic water permeability by accounting for this critical phenomenon. We found that the calibrated value can be several times of the apparent permeability (calculated using PA thickness without calibration). Furthermore, prompt by the disparate literature reports on the effectiveness of interlayers for mitigating funnel effect, we systematically investigated the interplay of several crucial factors (e.g., porosity and PA thickness) on the gutter/funnel effect through both experimental and modelling works. We demonstrated that the gutter effect is far more effective in enhancing water permeance and antifouling performance for membranes suffering from more severe funnel effect. For the thin-PA membrane with a low-porosity substrate, the water permeance was enhanced by approximately 75 % with the interlayer incorporation, while the flux reduction during the fouling test was significantly mitigated (i.e., from 33 % to 13 %). This work provides critical guidance on the future development of high-permeance and anti-fouling TFC membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4bc045c6f6c2538400328aa6f2ff933fb9d818a0</guid></item><item><title>Chlorination-properties-performance of polyamide nanofiltration membranes for the rejection of emerging contaminants.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/256075a9d18913b5fde42bd916a275e2f78211a1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/256075a9d18913b5fde42bd916a275e2f78211a1</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced hydrogen peroxide photosynthesis via charge-complementary π-electron sites</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d15f54af33471a8bb360f5a8f1cd50916f6359c6</link><description>Organic photocatalysts with porphyrin conjugated chromophore core are promising for artificial hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) photosynthesis, but the lack of bottom-up paradigm for oxygen (O2) adsorption sites hinders their activity. Here, we introduce imidazole groups as π-electron sites with charge-complementarity to the O2 molecules, enhancing O2 binding via sub-atomically mirrored electrostatic cooperative π-π dispersion forces. In situ spectroscopy and theory reveal that the ~2 Å linear δ+-δ−-δ+ domain of the imidazole substituent exhibits 2.8-folds stronger O2 adsorption than neutral π-electron substituents, accompanied by the generation of energetically peroxide intermediates. Consequently, imidazole-substituted porphyrin photocatalysts achieve a solar-to-chemical conversion efficiency of 1.85% using only H2O and O2. In scalable membranes with photocatalysts, enabling daily photosynthetic production of 80 L m−2 of Fenton-applicable H2O2 solution. This work offers a strategy to modulate the electrostatic distribution of oxygen photoreduction sites, providing insights into overcoming gas activation rate-limiting steps in photocatalytic processes. Introducing imidazole groups into porphyrin structures creates charge-complementary π-electron sites for O2 molecules which enhances binding force via electrostatic cooperative dispersion, thereby improving the efficiency of H2O2 photosynthesis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d15f54af33471a8bb360f5a8f1cd50916f6359c6</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced Thin-Film Composite Nanofiltration Membranes via Substrate Pore Structure Engineering: Performance and Mechanistic Insights.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b79371574910d944eccd05fd15ffeb586475cba</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b79371574910d944eccd05fd15ffeb586475cba</guid></item><item><title>Vacancy Functionalized MoS2 Nanolaminated Membranes for Efficient Sieving in Forward Osmosis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e2dd736c7a7a6a7b540627b2653ea64513d81233</link><description>2D transition‐metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) based nanolaminates are promising candidates for water purification. However, fabricating nanochannels with tunable capillary widths remain a challenge. This study proposed a sulfur vacancy functionalization strategy for fabricating high performance nanolaminate membranes by grafting three kinds of thiol (S‐H) containing molecules (Cysteine, 3‐Mercapto‐1,2‐propanediol, 1‐Propanethiol) on MoS2 nanosheets, in which propanethiol functionalized MoS2 membrane exhibited best salt rejection (99.3%) and water/salt selectivity (800 bar−1) in forward osmosis (draw solution: sucrose solution). It is found the capillary width increased from 0.2 Å in pristine MoS2 to ≈5 Å in propanethiol functionalized MoS2 membranes. Numerical simulations suggest that nanofluidic properties of the functionalized membranes are governed by the fundamental interaction between water and the corresponding S‐H functional group, and the interlayer distance. Importantly, since the S‐H containing molecules can repair MoS2 nanosheets by fitting into the sulfur vacancies, the stability of the membranes is also improved with minimal swelling, which is promising for their practical applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e2dd736c7a7a6a7b540627b2653ea64513d81233</guid></item><item><title>Smart Membrane with Reversible Superwetting Transition for On-Demand Antifouling and Self-Cleaning.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db43e7c497b782c57c0bfd99bcdcc91a3f21fbd8</link><description>Membrane wettability is crucial for filtration performance when treating feedwater containing inorganic particles, organic macromolecules, and microorganisms. Superhydrophilic membranes excel in resisting fouling during filtration, while superhydrophobic membranes are prized for their self-cleaning properties during maintenance. To address these contrasting needs, we herein propose a novel strategy by developing membranes with switchable superhydrophilicity and superhydrophobicity, enabling on-demand antifouling and self-cleaning. This membrane was created by electrodepositing copper oxides onto a copper mesh, resulting in the formation of hierarchical micro- and nanoscale structures. By applying a reduction voltage of -20 V, the copper oxides were converted into hydrophilic metallic copper, transforming the mesh into a superhydrophilic membrane. This transformation not only facilitated water permeation but also effectively repelled foulants during filtration. Remarkably, the gravity-driven permeation flux of the superhydrophilic membrane reached as high as 30,000 L·m-2·h-1. Furthermore, this superhydrophilic membrane demonstrated reasonable separation efficiency, achieving removal rates of 60.0% for total suspended solids, 93.1% for Melosira, and 83.0% for poly(vinyl alcohol). Upon heating at 100 °C for 1 h, the membrane surface reverted to a superhydrophobic state, enabling self-cleaning during membrane maintenance. With its facile preparation and smart electro- and thermo-responsive properties, this copper-based membrane, featuring reversibly switchable wettability, holds great promise for scalable applications in water treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db43e7c497b782c57c0bfd99bcdcc91a3f21fbd8</guid></item><item><title>Temporospatial Confined Catalytic Membranes with Controlled Diffusion-Reaction for Ultrafast Water Purification.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/06d3fbf0b0161723983acd2e5fda0c6a0d19eccc</link><description>Catalytic membrane is an appealing technology for eliminating refractory organic pollutants in comparison to conventional advanced oxidation methods. However, the application of this technology is constrained by the trade-off between membrane permeability and reactivity. Herein, we prepared a tubular macroporous catalytic membrane (MCM), which activated peroxymonosulfate to produce dominant singlet oxygen (1O2) and hydroxyl radicals (•OH) in the macropore channel (∼130 nm). The optimized MCM membrane demonstrated catalytic filtration performance far beyond the state-of-the-art, achieving &gt;99% degradation of antibiotics, dyes, and phenolic compounds while simultaneously exhibiting ultrafast permeance (645.3 L m-2 h-1 bar-1). For the first time, we reveal the spatial distribution of shorter-lived •OH and long-lived 1O2 in the macropore channel via a diffusion-reaction kinetic model, which provides fundamental insights into how these two reactive oxygen species work synergistically to offer opportunities for breaking the permeability-reactivity trade-off. Furthermore, the MCM achieved robust and stable removal of total organic carbon for a real high-salinity wastewater, verifying its practical potential for treating refractory organics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/06d3fbf0b0161723983acd2e5fda0c6a0d19eccc</guid></item><item><title>Ion-gel constrained single atom catalytic membranes with ultrahigh loading Fe-N3P1 sites for advanced oxidation processes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/855b4274d1ad75f2cc583b23e47c31696f8899be</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/855b4274d1ad75f2cc583b23e47c31696f8899be</guid></item><item><title>Resolving Hydraulic Resistances in Thin-Film Composite Polyamide Nanofiltration Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a945a72ddd13505d6b615f775de96739f76e5d38</link><description>Thin-film composite (TFC) nanofiltration (NF) membranes are widely used in water treatment and resource recovery. Researchers generally take for granted that the dense polyamide rejection film dictates the overall hydraulic resistance of these membranes, neglecting the contributions of the substrate and the transverse transport of water to reach substrate pores. To address this critical gap, we developed a resistance-in-series model to quantify the resistances from the polyamide film, substrate, and transverse transport. Calibration with multiple experimental data sets revealed that the polyamide film resistance varied over a wide range of 2.90 × 1012 to 40.15 × 1012 m-1, strongly correlating to film thicknesses (correlation coefficients &gt;0.95), with a thickness-normalized resistance of (0.44 ± 0.12) × 1012 m-1 nm-1. Contrarily, the intrinsic water permeability of polyamide material showed less variation (0.53 × 103 to 1.56 × 103 LMH bar-1 nm). Contrary to common belief, both the substrate and transverse transport contributed significant resistances of (2.4 ± 1.3) × 1012 and 5 × 1012 m-1, respectively. These two resistances became particularly non-negligible for membranes with thinner polyamide films. Our study provides the first detailed quantitative analysis of key contributors to hydraulic resistance and provides valuable insights for high-permeable NF membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a945a72ddd13505d6b615f775de96739f76e5d38</guid></item><item><title>Probing selective pollutant removal in nanofiltration processes: Critical insights from separation factor and removal difference.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b06b3d9989865d12a87bb959b45f584311ca5068</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b06b3d9989865d12a87bb959b45f584311ca5068</guid></item><item><title>Direct effects of interlayer on organic micropollutants removal by thin-film nanocomposite membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a27fa92d001902b5a3bd91fc04c9ff1c5f7491e0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a27fa92d001902b5a3bd91fc04c9ff1c5f7491e0</guid></item><item><title>Lithium Ion-Regulated Monomer Reactive Sites Heighten Selectivity of Polyamide Nanofiltration Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a10091ab3561e2305186a2312a134d627dc6c1ae</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a10091ab3561e2305186a2312a134d627dc6c1ae</guid></item><item><title>Plasmonic nanoheating for versatile water purification membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fe49e6fbe8d493e70e3e2b9df0c725ef16380a5d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fe49e6fbe8d493e70e3e2b9df0c725ef16380a5d</guid></item><item><title>Molecularly Welded “Cellulose‐Like” Membrane with Extensive H‐Bond Networks Enabling Robust and Tunable Nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/18896bd0c688227e39ae61129f1f45e5a360eeeb</link><description>Targeted removal of ionic species presents a bottleneck in designing advanced water purification technologies. Nanofiltration (NF) holds potential yet suffers from the trade‐off between fractionation efficiency and operational stability. Here a “cellulose‐like” composite membrane is developed using D (+)‐glucosamine (DGA) as the primary building block via molecular‐welding‐mediated interfacial polymerization (IP). Trace aliphatic diamines with different pendant functional groups are incorporated to both create an aperture‐tunable structure and facilitate the formation of extensive hydrogen‐bond networks. Specially, the optimized membrane, cross‐linked with 1,3‐diamino‐2‐propanol (DAP), featured an ultrathin polyester‐amide layer with high water permeance, smooth surface, strong hydrophilicity, near‐neutral charge, exceptional NO3− removal (84.1%), and tunable NaCl rejection (30–90%), outperforming the state‐of‐the‐art polyamide membranes. Detailed characterization revealed that ester/amide and H‐bonds conferred desirable anti‐fouling ability, superior chlorine resistance, and robust pH stability. This study offers a versatile platform for designing high‐performance NF membranes addressing critical needs in sustainable water management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/18896bd0c688227e39ae61129f1f45e5a360eeeb</guid></item><item><title>Thermal-intensified interfacial polymerization enables ultra-selective reverse osmosis membrane for toxic micropollutant removal</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/157f40ea9eb50fc50f25d993db8fba4d3dae695e</link><description>Polyamide reverse osmosis (RO) membranes are widely used in seawater desalination and wastewater reuse, yet often fail to remove small toxic micropollutants. Herein, we develop a thermal-intensified interfacial polymerization (TIP) strategy to fabricate highly selective RO membranes against various micropollutants. Facile heating accelerates amine monomer diffusion, intensifying interfacial polymerization to form a highly crosslinked polyamide membrane. The resultant TIP membrane achieves rejection of 90.8%, 98.0%, and &gt; 99% for boron, arsenite, organic micropollutants at neutral pH, respectively. Meanwhile, high temperature facilitates interfacial degassing and promotes the formation of more extensive nanovoids within the polyamide. These nanovoids increase membrane surface area and optimize water transport pathways, thereby boosting water permeance. The combination of high solute rejection and water permeance enables the membrane to achieve high water-micropollutant selectivity (e.g., water-boron). Our study demonstrates that TIP technique holds a great promise to fabricate ultra-selective polyamide membranes for desalination and wastewater reuse. Polyamide reverse osmosis membranes are widely used for desalination and wastewater treatment, though it is challenging to remove toxic micropollutants. Here the authors use a thermal-intensified interfacial polymerization method affording a membrane removing micropollutants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/157f40ea9eb50fc50f25d993db8fba4d3dae695e</guid></item><item><title>Virus-induced redox cycling in Fe(II)/peracetic acid systems: dual roles as reactant and catalytic promoter.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/42471123c40ce41b94dd118ce7bb281bc74646dc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/42471123c40ce41b94dd118ce7bb281bc74646dc</guid></item><item><title>Boosting organic micropollutant removal and separation performance of polyamide nanofiltration membranes through hydrogel interlayer construction.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2a07ca74811525dfbf549ca8c3095a030509470b</link><description>The widespread occurrence of organic micropollutants (OMPs) has become a critical issue for water safety and the protection of public health. While nanofiltration (NF) offers a promising solution for OMP removal, most NF membranes prioritize high OMP rejection at the expense of water permeance, limiting their scalability. In this study, we presented highly selective NF membranes featuring a chitosan/polyvinyl alcohol/polyethylene glycol hydrogel interlayer that achieved both efficient OMP rejection and enhanced water permeance. The hydrogel interlayer facilitated the formation of a thinner, less cross-linked polyamide selective layer with optimized pore size, which synergistically enhanced water permeance. As a result, the pure water permeance increased substantially to 21.5 LMH/bar, more than double that of the control membrane (9.4 LMH/bar). Additionally, Na2SO4 rejection improved from 98.3 % to 99.3 %, and NaCl/Na2SO4 selectivity increased from 38 to 107, attributed to the enhanced negative charge. Molecular dynamics simulations indicated that the hydrogel interlayer modulated membrane properties by retarding piperazine monomer diffusion during interfacial polymerization. Additionally, the optimized membrane exhibited enhanced OMP rejection compared to control membrane, attributed to stronger electrostatic repulsion and reduced hydrophobic interactions due to enhanced negative surface charge and hydrophilicity. This work demonstrates an effective strategy for developing NF membranes with tailored properties, enabling advanced OMP removal and high water permeance for sustainable water reuse and production.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2a07ca74811525dfbf549ca8c3095a030509470b</guid></item><item><title>EQCM-D assisted characterization of polyamide nanofiltration membrane: Mechanistic insights of solutes transport under various pH conditions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c824687561f8e66237140d8b202fccfaef07cb41</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c824687561f8e66237140d8b202fccfaef07cb41</guid></item><item><title>In-situ vacuum-assisted fabrication of highly selective hollow fiber nanofiltration membranes for removing polyfluoroalkyl substances.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/80d756c8270151bc3f041f4213f0357c24289e2c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/80d756c8270151bc3f041f4213f0357c24289e2c</guid></item><item><title>Lithium-ion battery recycling through an integrated electro-membrane crystallization technology</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a87cfbef9434c6ffceb45bebbe006df5da936b31</link><description>Lithium-ion battery (LIB) recycling is crucial for energy security, environmental sustainability, and economic viability, as the finite lifespan of LIBs results in a significant annual accumulation of spent units. However, effectively and precisely recovering valuable metal ions such as Li+, Mn2+, Ni2+ and Co2+ from complex LIB leaching solutions remains a major challenge. Here, we present a scalable electro-membrane crystallization-assisted general recycling (e-MCGR) technology for the selective and efficient recovery of those metal ions from LIB leaching solutions. By synergistically integrating electrochemical and electro-membrane technologies, our proposed technology incorporates four key configurations: selective membrane dual-stage distillation, bipolar membrane in-situ crystallization, membrane metal-complexing ex-situ crystallization, and membrane metal-extracting temporal crystallization. We systematically analyze the metal-ion transfer kinetics of electro-membranes (ion selectivity and permeation rates) and the performance of electro-membrane crystallization systems (recovery rates and product purity), alongside evaluating energy consumption, economic viability, and environmental benefits. Our optimized e-MCGR process achieves a recovery of 95.5% for Li+, 99.5% for Mn2+, 83.1% for Ni2+, and 87.3% for Co2+, yielding high product purities of 99.9% for Li2CO3, 99.9% for Mn3O4, 99.5% for Ni(OH)2 and 92.5% for Co(OH)2. The e-MCGR technology demonstrates significant potential to reshape LIB recycling paradigms, aligning technological efficiency with energy, environmental and economic sustainability. This study presents a scalable and sustainable electro-membrane crystallization-assisted general recycling technology that efficiently recovers high-purity lithium, manganese, nickel, and cobalt from spent lithium-ion batteries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a87cfbef9434c6ffceb45bebbe006df5da936b31</guid></item><item><title>Fractal-inspired ultrapermeable membranes for electricity-free portable nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c61abb0853ed4b9b529f56628482a967c9dbb28c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c61abb0853ed4b9b529f56628482a967c9dbb28c</guid></item><item><title>Carbon composites with photo-allosteric switch for waterborne virus removal.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f29dc25d039c933123b735fb6c5d73d7895aa2c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f29dc25d039c933123b735fb6c5d73d7895aa2c</guid></item><item><title>Synergistic non-Faradaic and Faradaic Processes for Efficient Phosphate Recovery and Fouling Control in Capacitive Deionization</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ce7a8b3c0d977f861d51c77109f2c22bd2ac4f2b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ce7a8b3c0d977f861d51c77109f2c22bd2ac4f2b</guid></item><item><title>Scalable Production and Covalent Functionalization of WS2 Nanosheets for Membrane Fabrication and Ion Separation.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/52208207c82bcb741dc84127991ce632c1d18c66</link><description>Transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) membranes offer a promising solution to freshwater scarcity by desalinating seawater through ion blocking. However, research has largely focused on MoS2 due to its efficient exfoliation via n-butyl lithium intercalation, unlike other TMDs. Here, we report scalable production of WS2 nanosheets by increasing the Li+ intercalation driving force (increasing current density up to 10 mA g-1 and decreasing cutoff voltage down to 0.7 V) of the electrochemical intercalation method. WS2 membranes were then fabricated by organohalide functionalization followed by vacuum filtration. The resulting membranes exhibit a high rejection rate of up to 90% for divalent and trivalent cations. The selectivity for monovalent/divalent and monovalent/trivalent cations reaches up to 8.7 and 9.9, respectively, in both single and binary cation solutions. Theoretical calculations reveal that the improved rejection rates of divalent and trivalent cations compared to those of monovalent cations originate from the stronger binding preferences of monovalent cations with functionalized WS2 membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/52208207c82bcb741dc84127991ce632c1d18c66</guid></item><item><title>In-situ construction of ZIF-embedded hydrogel electro-driven membranes for lithium selectivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ebe66465536ca113df2db48a49ba5dce3be95db3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ebe66465536ca113df2db48a49ba5dce3be95db3</guid></item></channel></rss>