<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jay Werber</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/35255441</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Jay Werber</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:43:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>One Resin, Multiple Products: A Green Approach to Purification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5527a5a6432a26a190c50a935eccd6a5eb90f8df</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5527a5a6432a26a190c50a935eccd6a5eb90f8df</guid></item><item><title>Using a fiber-optic probe for the measurement of volumetric expansion of liquids</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e02eee9b49497a0891a0ce301f28caa2444dba4a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e02eee9b49497a0891a0ce301f28caa2444dba4a</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of 2,2'-azobis (2-amidinopropane) dihydrochloride degradation and hydrolysis in aqueous solutions.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d9aa259978dd162049bb0a9c25df428d51456e08</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d9aa259978dd162049bb0a9c25df428d51456e08</guid></item><item><title>Forward osmosis: Where are we now?</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fed030fce485efced8683b9e3783153dca9bf122</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fed030fce485efced8683b9e3783153dca9bf122</guid></item><item><title>Application of membrane dewatering for algal biofuel</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e772db2c5335a6fcf59bf4e36e74d29811f77a34</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e772db2c5335a6fcf59bf4e36e74d29811f77a34</guid></item><item><title>The Critical Need for Increased Selectivity, Not Increased Water Permeability, for Desalination Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/acd2d3e82efb116c9d8bb738034d80d92878a8d8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/acd2d3e82efb116c9d8bb738034d80d92878a8d8</guid></item><item><title>Materials for next-generation desalination and water purification membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/97fa41b209e1e86a38c26c9a8c5f17f429cace1d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/97fa41b209e1e86a38c26c9a8c5f17f429cace1d</guid></item><item><title>Can batch or semi-batch processes save energy in reverse-osmosis desalination?</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c967ef4435b976823032a7e2c6afb3ab8d89927</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c967ef4435b976823032a7e2c6afb3ab8d89927</guid></item><item><title>A facile method to quantify the carboxyl group areal density in the active layer of polyamide thin-film composite membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c622826ee19eba27978b5e35edee570c05ae950</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c622826ee19eba27978b5e35edee570c05ae950</guid></item><item><title>Acyl-chloride quenching following interfacial polymerization to modulate the water permeability, selectivity, and surface charge of desalination membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b316610d06bbfac93a26fc0f498d4e92846f8945</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b316610d06bbfac93a26fc0f498d4e92846f8945</guid></item><item><title>Loss of Phospholipid Membrane Integrity Induced by Two-Dimensional Nanomaterials</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2944053232b684e37187ac3f117d458a5f27300a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2944053232b684e37187ac3f117d458a5f27300a</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced antibacterial activity through the controlled alignment of graphene oxide nanosheets</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/88a3552d01166937b84621ea55de6a3297733624</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/88a3552d01166937b84621ea55de6a3297733624</guid></item><item><title>The role of nanotechnology in tackling global water challenges</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/486856b125f08014d9e3e2bc1421ff36804964ae</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/486856b125f08014d9e3e2bc1421ff36804964ae</guid></item><item><title>Permselectivity limits of biomimetic desalination membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3c76a99a3ef87f6cd7808b4df8c25349bdf6b909</link><description>Biomimetic desalination membranes could achieve ultraselectivity for water over ions, but not over neutral solutes. Water scarcity and inadequate membrane selectivity have spurred interest in biomimetic desalination membranes, in which biological or synthetic water channels are incorporated in an amphiphilic bilayer. As low channel densities (0.1 to 10%) are required for sufficient water permeability, the amphiphilic bilayer matrix will play a critical role in separation performance. We determine selectivity limits for biomimetic membranes by studying the transport behavior of water, neutral solutes, and ions through the bilayers of lipid and block-copolymer vesicles and projecting performance for varying water channel densities. We report that defect-free biomimetic membranes would have water/salt permselectivities ~108-fold greater than current desalination membranes. In contrast, the solubility-based permeability of lipid and block-copolymer bilayers (extending Overton’s rule) will result in poor rejection of hydrophobic solutes. Defect-free biomimetic membranes thus offer great potential for seawater desalination and ultrapure water production, but would perform poorly in wastewater reuse. Potential strategies to limit neutral solute permeation are discussed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3c76a99a3ef87f6cd7808b4df8c25349bdf6b909</guid></item><item><title>High-Pressure Reverse Osmosis for Energy-Efficient Hypersaline Brine Desalination: Current Status, Design Considerations, and Research Needs</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a4666593d9e62d52f9e118e7b6ffd2db23c54174</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a4666593d9e62d52f9e118e7b6ffd2db23c54174</guid></item><item><title>A Path to Ultraselectivity: Support Layer Properties To Maximize Performance of Biomimetic Desalination Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cdd0eadaae5d5759d2126109fba65cad38eb3d0e</link><description>Reverse osmosis (RO) has become a premier technology for desalination and water purification. The need for increased selectivity has incentivized research into novel membranes, such as biomimetic membranes that incorporate the perfectly selective biological water channel aquaporin or synthetic water channels like carbon nanotubes. In this study, we consider the performance of composite biomimetic membranes by projecting water permeability, salt rejection, and neutral-solute retention based on the permeabilities of the individual components, particularly the water channel, the amphiphilic bilayer matrix, and potential support layers that include polymeric RO, nanofiltration (NF), and porous ultrafiltration membranes. We find that the support layer will be crucial in the overall performance. Selective, relatively low-permeability supports minimize the negative impact of defects in the biomimetic layer, which are currently the main performance-limiting factor for biomimetic membranes. In particular, RO membranes as support layers would enable &gt;99.85% salt rejection at ∼10000-fold greater biomimetic-layer defect area than for porous supports. By fundamentally characterizing neutral-solute permeation through RO and NF membranes, we show that RO membranes as support layers would enable high rejection of organic pollutants based on molecular size, overcoming the rapid permeation of hydrophobic solutes through the biomimetic layer. A biomimetic membrane could also achieve exceptionally high boron rejections of ∼99.7%, even with 1% defect area in the biomimetic layer. We conclude by discussing the implications of our findings for biomimetic membrane design.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cdd0eadaae5d5759d2126109fba65cad38eb3d0e</guid></item><item><title>AWWA Scholarships in Action</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c9fbeeb49c21e87c7a7715298993f81145561e71</link><description>N ote from Joseph Goodwill, column coordinator: Financially supporting students with scholarships is one of the more important ways AWWA supports future generations of water professionals. The impact of these scholarships is difficult to overstate. I speak from firsthand experience as I was fortunate to win two scholarships from AWWA during my PhD work (American Water Scholarship, 2013; Larson Aquatic Research Support [LARS] Scholarship, 2014). AWWA annually funds more than 20 scholarships open to anyone and supports countless Section-level awards that make it possible for students of all funding backgrounds to engage in learning and research. The larger research-based scholarships are competitive and in 2018 received 543 applications across the various categories with awards of $209,000. It’s important to emphasize that the funding for many of these scholarships comes from generous sponsor organizations, including utilities, consultants, and equipment manufacturers and suppliers, while a handful are directly supported by AWWA. But the scholarship programs provide more than just financial support—they also contribute a sense of belonging and acceptance. Having your work and future prospects acknowledged by AWWA increases confidence and camaraderie; winning an AWWA scholarship is often an early step at the beginning of a long and storied career in water. This Researcher to Researcher column showcases observations from three recent AWWA scholarship winners: Lucas Alexandre Djehdian, Alexander S. Gorzalski, and Jay R. Werber. It includes how they achieved their current professional positions as well as paths they might take in the future. This small selection of young professionals highlights the promise of the water industry and the specific potential of these outstanding individuals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c9fbeeb49c21e87c7a7715298993f81145561e71</guid></item><item><title>Monte Carlo Simulations of Framework Defects in Layered Two-Dimensional Nanomaterial Desalination Membranes: Implications for Permeability and Selectivity.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/32a13203b3fdfdca54cb842e9c8eb86cd9596800</link><description>Two-dimensional nanomaterial (2-D NM) frameworks, especially those comprising graphene oxide, have received extensive research interest for membrane-based separation processes and desalination. However, the impact of horizontal defects in 2-D NM frameworks, which stem from nonuniform deposition of 2-D NM flakes during layer build-up, has been almost entirely overlooked. In this work, we apply Monte Carlo simulations, under idealized conditions wherein the vertical interlayer spacing allows for water permeation while perfectly excluding salt, on both the formation of the laminate structure and molecular transport through the laminate. Our simulations show that 2-D NM frameworks are extremely tortuous (tortuosity ≈103), with water permeability decreasing from 20 to &lt;1 L m-2 h-1 bar-1 as thickness increased from 8 to 167 nm. Additionally, we find that framework defects allow salt to percolate through the framework, hindering water-salt selectivity. 2-D NM frameworks with a packing density of 75%, representative of most 2-D NM membranes, are projected to achieve &lt;92% NaCl rejection at a water permeability of &lt;1 L m-2 h-1 bar-1, even with ideal interlayer spacing. A high packing density of 90%, which to our knowledge has yet to be achieved, could yield comparable performance to current desalination membranes. Maximizing packing density is therefore a critical technical challenge, in addition to the already daunting challenge of optimizing interlayer spacing, for the development of 2-D NM membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/32a13203b3fdfdca54cb842e9c8eb86cd9596800</guid></item><item><title>Capillary-driven desalination in a synthetic mangrove</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1cb891cc32a9820ccb3109d841efb2965093f02</link><description>Large negative pressures (&lt;−338 bar) generated by evaporation from nanopores allow for passive desalination of hypersaline water. According to the cohesion-tension theory, mangrove trees desalinate salty water using highly negative pressure (or tension) that is generated by evaporative capillary forces in mangrove leaves. Here, we demonstrate a synthetic mangrove that mimics the main features of the natural mangrove: capillary pumping (leaves), stable water conduction in highly metastable states (stem), and membrane desalination (root). When using nanoporous membranes as leaves, the maximum osmotic pressures of saline feeds (10 to 30 bar) allowing pure water uptake precisely correspond to expected capillary pressures based on the Young-Laplace equation. Hydrogel-based leaves allow for stable operation and desalination of hypersaline solutions with osmotic pressures approaching 400 bar, fivefold greater than the pressure limits of conventional reverse osmosis. Our findings support the applicability of the cohesion-tension theory to desalination in mangroves, provide a new platform to study plant hydraulics, and create possibilities for engineered membrane separations using large, passively generated capillary pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1cb891cc32a9820ccb3109d841efb2965093f02</guid></item><item><title>Controlled grafting of polymer brush layers from porous cellulosic membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8be50d3de983239af1f94e8d1201784f785c185d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8be50d3de983239af1f94e8d1201784f785c185d</guid></item><item><title>Pathways and Challenges for Biomimetic Desalination Membranes with Sub-Nanometer Channels.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4a52d0353bce082a250a8e2a8ab6a4bd062835d5</link><description>Transmembrane protein channels, including ion channels and aquaporins that are responsible for fast and selective transport of water, have inspired membrane scientists to exploit and mimic their performance in membrane technologies. These biomimetic membranes comprise discrete nanochannels aligned within amphiphilic matrices on a robust support. While biological components have been used directly, extensive work has also been conducted to produce stable synthetic mimics of protein channels and lipid bilayers. However, the experimental performance of biomimetic membranes remains far below that of biological membranes. In this review, we critically assess the status and potential of biomimetic desalination membranes. We first review channel chemistries and their transport behavior, identifying key characteristics to optimize water permeability and salt rejection. We compare various channel types within an industrial context, considering transport performance, processability, and stability. Through a re-examination of previous vesicular stopped-flow studies, we demonstrate that incorrect permeability equations result in overestimation of the water permeability of nanochannels. We find in particular that the most optimized aquaporin-bearing bilayer had a pure water permeability of 2.1 L m-2 h-1 bar-1, which is comparable to that of current state-of-the-art polymeric desalination membranes. Through a quantitative assessment of biomimetic membrane formats, we analytically show that formats incorporating intact vesicles offer minimal benefit, whereas planar biomimetic selective layers could allow for dramatically improved salt rejections. We then show that the persistence of nanoscale defects explains observed subpar performance. We conclude with a discussion on optimal strategies for minimizing these defects, which could enable breakthrough performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4a52d0353bce082a250a8e2a8ab6a4bd062835d5</guid></item><item><title>Co-Casting Highly Selective Dual-Layer Membranes with Disordered Block Polymer Selective Layers.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6bd035b7a761abcb64c01205c2b81dbc508c4f81</link><description>Highly selective and water permeable dual-layer ultrafiltration (UF) membranes comprising a disordered poly(methyl methacrylate-stat-styrene)-block-poly(lactide) selective layer and a polysulfone (PSF) support layer were fabricated using a co-casting technique. A dilute solution of diblock polymer was spin coated onto a solvent-swollen PSF layer, rapidly heated to dry and disorder the block polymer layer, and subsequently immersed into an ice water coagulation bath to kinetically trap the disordered state in the block polymer selective layer and precipitate the support layer by nonsolvent-induced phase separation. Subsequent removal of the polylactide block generated porous membranes suitable for UF. The permeability of these dual-layer membranes was modulated by tuning the concentration of the PSF casting solution, while the size-selectivity was maintained because of the narrow pore size distribution of the self-assembled block polymer selective layer. Elimination of the thermal annealing step resulted in a dramatic increase in the water permeability without adversely impacting the size-selectivity, as the disordered nanostructure present in the concentrated casting solution was kinetically trapped upon rapid drying. The co-casting strategy outlined in this work may enable the scalable fabrication of block polymer membranes with both high permeability and high selectivity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6bd035b7a761abcb64c01205c2b81dbc508c4f81</guid></item><item><title>Ionization behavior of nanoporous polyamide membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d63d3b7a415dee1358dd3ee1cda70f7fc0528f14</link><description>Significance Novel membrane processes and materials are needed to combat global water scarcity. The advancement of membrane materials for water purification processes such as desalination is hindered by our limited understanding of structure–property–performance relationships. We address this knowledge gap by elucidating the mechanisms which govern the ionization behavior of nanoporous polyamide films and their influence on membrane performance. Polyamide ionization is key to enhancing the separation efficiency of charged constituents in aqueous solutions. Our results illustrate that a large portion of the ionizable moieties in polyamide films remain uncharged during typical operation due to extreme confinement effects, thus going unutilized. Complete ionization of state-of-the-art polyamide membranes offers selectivity improvements that could markedly improve desalination process efficiency. Escalating global water scarcity necessitates high-performance desalination membranes, for which fundamental understanding of structure–property–performance relationships is required. In this study, we comprehensively assess the ionization behavior of nanoporous polyamide selective layers in state-of-the-art nanofiltration (NF) membranes. In these films, residual carboxylic acids and amines influence permeability and selectivity by imparting hydrophilicity and ionizable moieties that can exclude coions. We utilize layered interfacial polymerization to prepare physically and chemically similar selective layers of controlled thickness. We then demonstrate location-dependent ionization of carboxyl groups in NF polyamide films. Specifically, only surface carboxyl groups ionize under neutral pH, whereas interior carboxyl ionization requires pH &gt;9. Conversely, amine ionization behaves invariably across the film. First-principles simulations reveal that the low permittivity of nanoconfined water drives the anomalous carboxyl ionization behavior. Furthermore, we report that interior carboxyl ionization could improve the water–salt permselectivity of NF membranes over fourfold, suggesting that interior charge density could be an important tool to enhance the selectivity of polyamide membranes. Our findings highlight the influence of nanoconfinement on membrane transport properties and provide enhanced fundamental understanding of ionization that could enable novel membrane design.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d63d3b7a415dee1358dd3ee1cda70f7fc0528f14</guid></item><item><title>Next-Generation Ultrafiltration Membranes Enabled by Block Polymers.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f7aac3ef061225edebdb00a4ae734cc0b1f942aa</link><description>Reliable and equitable access to safe drinking water is a major and growing challenge worldwide. Membrane separations represent one of the most promising strategies for the energy-efficient purification of potential water sources. In particular, porous membranes are used for the ultrafiltration (UF) of water to remove contaminants with nanometric sizes. However, despite exhibiting excellent water permeability and solution processability, existing UF membranes contain a broad distribution of pore sizes that limit their size selectivity. To maximize the potential utility of UF membranes and allow for precise separations, improvements in the size selectivity of these systems must be achieved. Block polymers represent a potentially transformative solution, as these materials self-assemble into well-defined domains of uniform size. Several different strategies have been reported for integrating block polymers into UF membranes, and each strategy has its own set of materials and processing considerations to ensure that uniform and continuous pores are generated. This Review aims to summarize and critically analyze the chemistries, processing techniques, and properties required for the most common methods for producing porous membranes from block polymers, with a particular focus on the fundamental mechanisms underlying block polymer self-assembly and pore formation. Critical structure-property-performance metrics will be analyzed for block polymer UF membranes to understand how these membranes compare to commercial UF membranes and to identify key research areas for continued improvements. This Review is intended to inform readers of the capabilities and current challenges of block polymer UF membranes, while stimulating critical thought on strategies to advance these technologies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f7aac3ef061225edebdb00a4ae734cc0b1f942aa</guid></item><item><title>Functionalized Polymersomes from a Polyisoprene-Activated Polyacrylamide Precursor.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/06879505869c0a77462f08cd656f78bd6e695a7d</link><description>Self-assembled polymer nanoparticles have tremendous potential in biomedical and environmental applications. For all applications, tailored polymer chemistries are critical. In this study, we demonstrate a precursor approach in which an activated, organic solvent-soluble block polymer precursor is modified through mild postpolymerization modifications to access new polymer structures. We synthesized and characterized poly(isoprene)-block-poly(di-Boc acrylamide) diblock polymers. This activated-acrylamide-based polymer was then reacted with amines or reductants in the absence of catalysts to yield the hydrophilic blocks polyacrylamide, poly(hydroxypropylene), and poly(N-ethyl acrylamide). The resulting amphiphilic block polymers self-assembled in water to form polymersomes, as confirmed by cryo-electron microscopy and confocal microscopy. The approach also enables simple functionalization with specialized ligands, which we demonstrated by tagging polymers with an amino-fluorophore and imaging by confocal microscopy. We expect that the methodologies established in this study will open doors to new and useful solution nanostructures with surface chemistries that can be optimized for various applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/06879505869c0a77462f08cd656f78bd6e695a7d</guid></item><item><title>Tailored Mesoporous Microspheres by Polymerization-Induced Microphase Separation in Suspension</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ca0aceb659025765e21825215bbe5a3f3984d5ae</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ca0aceb659025765e21825215bbe5a3f3984d5ae</guid></item><item><title>Polymeric Microcapsules as Robust Mimics of Emulsion Liquid Membranes for Selective Ion Separations.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7471dc237d54587afcba72ba50572950a5363935</link><description>Selective ion separations are increasingly needed to combat water scarcity, recover resources from wastewater, and enable the efficient recycling of electronics waste. Emulsion liquid membranes (ELMs) have received interest due to rapid kinetics, high selectivities, and low solvent requirements but are too unstable for industrial usage. We demonstrate that polymeric microcapsules can serve as robust, solvent-free mimics of ELMs. As a proof of concept, we incorporated the copper-selective ligand Lix 84-I in the walls of microcapsules formed from a commercial polystyrene-b-polybutadiene-b-polystyrene triblock polymer. The microcapsules were formed from a double-emulsion template, resulting in particles typically 20-120 μm in diameter that encapsulated even smaller droplets of a dilute (≤0.5 M) H2SO4 solution. Batch experiments demonstrated facilitated-transport behavior, with equilibrium reached in as little as 10 min for microcapsules with 1% ligand, and with ∼15-fold selectivity for Cu2+ over Ni2+. Furthermore, the microcapsules could be packed readily in columns for flow-through operation, thus enabling near-complete Cu2+ removal in ∼2 min under certain conditions, recovery of Cu2+ by flowing through fresh dilute H2SO4, and reuse for at least 10 cycles. The approach in this work can serve as a template for using selective ligands to enable robust and simple flow-through processes for a variety of selective ion separations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7471dc237d54587afcba72ba50572950a5363935</guid></item><item><title>Rapid Reconstruction of 3-D Membrane Pore Structure Using a Single 2-D Micrograph</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0d5160304d38386d26275c4b7cb05a3254029e5</link><description>Conventional 2-D scanning electron microscopy (SEM) is commonly used to rapidly and qualitatively evaluate membrane pore structure. Quantitative 2-D analyses of pore sizes can be extracted from SEM, but without information about 3-D spatial arrangement and connectivity, which are crucial to the understanding of membrane pore structure. Meanwhile, experimental 3-D reconstruction via tomography is complex, expensive, and not easily accessible. Here, we employ data-science tools to demonstrate a proof-of-principle reconstruction of the 3-D structure of a membrane using a single 2-D image pulled from a 3-D tomographic data set. The reconstructed and experimental 3-D structures were then directly compared, with important properties such as mean pore radius, mean throat radius, coordination number and tortuosity differing by less than 15%. The developed algorithm will dramatically improve the ability of the membrane community to characterize membranes, accelerating the design and synthesis of membranes with desired structural and transport properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0d5160304d38386d26275c4b7cb05a3254029e5</guid></item><item><title>Data-science-based reconstruction of 3-D membrane pore structure using a single 2-D micrograph</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fd391d1af0a675abc684130ccee4205db8d9ec8f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fd391d1af0a675abc684130ccee4205db8d9ec8f</guid></item><item><title>Interfacial Crosslinking to Prepare Ultra-Thin Polydimethylsiloxane Thin-Film Composite Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d7c25a5064b95c83c79684635b9e51642337e195</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d7c25a5064b95c83c79684635b9e51642337e195</guid></item><item><title>Ultra-Thin Cation Exchange Membranes: Sulfonated Polyamide Thin-Film Composite Membranes with High Charge Density</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1f8b1c4b172465d2be2bf34103ad1c498934b9c6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1f8b1c4b172465d2be2bf34103ad1c498934b9c6</guid></item><item><title>Ocean Alkalinity Enhancement Using Bipolar Membrane Electrodialysis: Technical Analysis and Cost Breakdown of a Full-Scale Plant</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/380aeb91b617176233ab3cae2c55be4feae0f306</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/380aeb91b617176233ab3cae2c55be4feae0f306</guid></item><item><title>Digital generation of the 3-D pore architecture of isotropic membranes using 2-D cross-sectional scanning electron microscopy images</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e5d45f1c3e956d7abb11a203dba99c5a7e196bda</link><description>A major limitation of two-dimensional scanning electron microscopy (SEM) in imaging porous membranes is its inability to resolve three-dimensional pore architecture and interconnectivity, which are critical factors governing membrane performance. Although conventional tomographic 3-D reconstruction techniques can address this limitation, they are often expensive, technically challenging, and not widely accessible. We previously introduced a proof-of-concept method for reconstructing a membrane's 3-D pore network from a single 2-D SEM image, yielding statistically equivalent results to those obtained from 3-D tomography. However, this initial approach struggled to replicate the diverse pore geometries commonly observed in real membranes. In this study, we advance the methodology by developing an enhanced reconstruction algorithm that not only maintains essential statistical properties (e.g., pore size distribution), but also accurately reproduces intricate pore morphologies. Applying this technique to a commercial microfiltration membrane, we generated a high-fidelity 3-D reconstruction and derived key membrane properties. Validation with X-ray tomography data revealed excellent agreement in structural metrics, with our SEM-based approach achieving superior resolution in resolving fine pore features. The tool can be readily applied to isotropic porous membrane structures of any pore size, as long as those pores can be visualized by SEM. Further work is needed for 3-D structure generation of anisotropic membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e5d45f1c3e956d7abb11a203dba99c5a7e196bda</guid></item><item><title>Oxidation-controlled nanoporous graphene laminate membranes via intercalation chemistry for desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/25563fa08fca59e2a61b5ad287d2e4018be26e7a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/25563fa08fca59e2a61b5ad287d2e4018be26e7a</guid></item><item><title>Training-Free Active Learning Framework in Materials Science with Large Language Models</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/686ea87e8c4002381c4df0a09fc137a44dc1bc35</link><description>Active learning (AL) accelerates scientific discovery by prioritizing the most informative experiments, but traditional machine learning (ML) models used in AL suffer from cold-start limitations and domain-specific feature engineering, restricting their generalizability. Large language models (LLMs) offer a new paradigm by leveraging their pretrained knowledge and universal token-based representations to propose experiments directly from text-based descriptions. Here, we introduce an LLM-based active learning framework (LLM-AL) that operates in an iterative few-shot setting and benchmark it against conventional ML models across four diverse materials science datasets. We explored two prompting strategies: one using concise numerical inputs suited for datasets with more compositional and structured features, and another using expanded descriptive text suited for datasets with more experimental and procedural features to provide additional context. Across all datasets, LLM-AL could reduce the number of experiments needed to reach top-performing candidates by over 70% and consistently outperformed traditional ML models. We found that LLM-AL performs broader and more exploratory searches while still reaching the optima with fewer iterations. We further examined the stability boundaries of LLM-AL given the inherent non-determinism of LLMs and found its performance to be broadly consistent across runs, within the variability range typically observed for traditional ML approaches. These results demonstrate that LLM-AL can serve as a generalizable alternative to conventional AL pipelines for more efficient and interpretable experiment selection and potential LLM-driven autonomous discovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/686ea87e8c4002381c4df0a09fc137a44dc1bc35</guid></item><item><title>Modeling Scaling Prevention and Attainable Recovery Using Hypothetical Calcium-Permeable Reverse Osmosis Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/31cab812f9f0d03aad75095d08bd873186ba25b1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/31cab812f9f0d03aad75095d08bd873186ba25b1</guid></item></channel></rss>