<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jovan Kamcev</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/7646506</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Jovan Kamcev</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 01:39:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Microtubule nanospool formation by active self-assembly is not initiated by thermal activation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/924479afe8dcdd3a5b17117a5c5d77abe6b2ef70</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/924479afe8dcdd3a5b17117a5c5d77abe6b2ef70</guid></item><item><title>Nanoscale transport enables active self-assembly of millimeter-scale wires.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7d6fc67f1ee4ef6013cd485a639441d748310e72</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7d6fc67f1ee4ef6013cd485a639441d748310e72</guid></item><item><title>Chemically enhancing block copolymers for block-selective synthesis of self-assembled metal oxide nanostructures.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b8e5ddb399f5dfaf937f7081514c2dff8f3a1bb</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b8e5ddb399f5dfaf937f7081514c2dff8f3a1bb</guid></item><item><title>Enhancing Water Splitting Activity and Chemical Stability of Zinc Oxide Nanowire Photoanodes with Ultrathin Titania Shells</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/30f22d3021e22cfa7f83fc718bfc75cd4b25e69c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/30f22d3021e22cfa7f83fc718bfc75cd4b25e69c</guid></item><item><title>Effect of ambient carbon dioxide on salt permeability and sorption measurements in ion-exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5d20461196e485aa065a8f7c20d175845f9797f5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5d20461196e485aa065a8f7c20d175845f9797f5</guid></item><item><title>Fundamental Studies of Ion Sorption, Diffusion and Transport in Polyelectrolyte Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/91563b434def07c43ec4d8d66e95b188c16dd97f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/91563b434def07c43ec4d8d66e95b188c16dd97f</guid></item><item><title>Ion Activity Coefficients in Ion Exchange Polymers: Applicability of Manning’s Counterion Condensation Theory</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5001f9f3cfa452667418d98707a19157e8c114a7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5001f9f3cfa452667418d98707a19157e8c114a7</guid></item><item><title>Partitioning of mobile ions between ion exchange polymers and aqueous salt solutions: importance of counter-ion condensation.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5d088d31dd3f7039b861ea845d65c5cd5a3c642d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5d088d31dd3f7039b861ea845d65c5cd5a3c642d</guid></item><item><title>Materials science: Cracks help membranes to stay hydrated</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2854e8bc968d242d9e1f1deba97ae93c56f60e38</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2854e8bc968d242d9e1f1deba97ae93c56f60e38</guid></item><item><title>Charged Polymer Membranes for Environmental/Energy Applications.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1c9f4b59bfa3bf33224ba195000b044a1bd652ed</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1c9f4b59bfa3bf33224ba195000b044a1bd652ed</guid></item><item><title>Ion sorption and transport in ion exchange membranes : importance of counter-ion condensation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9cd2de84da1e34abe10985c69a830fe6e03477b3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9cd2de84da1e34abe10985c69a830fe6e03477b3</guid></item><item><title>Predicting Salt Permeability Coefficients in Highly Swollen, Highly Charged Ion Exchange Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/304bd6f7636154cde15edb5186f381a8313548da</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/304bd6f7636154cde15edb5186f381a8313548da</guid></item><item><title>Effect of fixed charge group concentration on equilibrium ion sorption in ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f695c6154a51ecb9bc52f84710ef5f5fdf152a35</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f695c6154a51ecb9bc52f84710ef5f5fdf152a35</guid></item><item><title>Maximizing the right stuff: The trade-off between membrane permeability and selectivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6424164dac6018f287a78ea59a5f6a22c73d58b5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6424164dac6018f287a78ea59a5f6a22c73d58b5</guid></item><item><title>Accounting for frame of reference and thermodynamic non-idealities when calculating salt diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5473a3395d7d27aae44e4460da01fbf4eacb2667</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5473a3395d7d27aae44e4460da01fbf4eacb2667</guid></item><item><title>Salt concentration dependence of ionic conductivity in ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e48a17a333689ddb734daa2253e0be64afcc3fcb</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e48a17a333689ddb734daa2253e0be64afcc3fcb</guid></item><item><title>Ion Diffusion Coefficients in Ion Exchange Membranes: Significance of Counterion Condensation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/816baad3130cb78e9904aee0f79820ec09fb5e7c</link><description>This study presents a new framework for extracting single ion diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes from experimental ion sorption, salt permeability, and ionic conductivity data. The framework was used to calculate cation and anion diffusion coefficients in a series of commercial ion exchange membranes contacted by aqueous NaCl solutions. Counterion diffusion coefficients were greater than co-ion diffusion coefficients for all membranes after accounting for inherent differences due to ion size. A model for ion diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes, incorporating ideas from counterion condensation theory, was proposed to interpret the experimental results. The model predicted co-ion diffusion coefficients reasonably well with no adjustable parameters, while a single adjustable parameter was required to accurately describe counterion diffusion coefficients. The results suggest that for cross-linked ion exchange membranes in which counterion condensation occurs condensed counterions mi...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/816baad3130cb78e9904aee0f79820ec09fb5e7c</guid></item><item><title>Equilibrium ion partitioning between aqueous salt solutions and inhomogeneous ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0ce73033c17d9740df2af22127f6d3924785c1b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0ce73033c17d9740df2af22127f6d3924785c1b</guid></item><item><title>Effect of fixed charge group concentration on salt permeability and diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bdcdf8ccc23f0f433d1148e4fbd74b5ed1b88aa</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bdcdf8ccc23f0f433d1148e4fbd74b5ed1b88aa</guid></item><item><title>Influence of concentration polarization and thermodynamic non-ideality on salt transport in reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2d65b4b592b9caab663d71b5e6932fb5edf2ae7a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2d65b4b592b9caab663d71b5e6932fb5edf2ae7a</guid></item><item><title>Effect of Water Content on Sodium Chloride Sorption in Cross-Linked Cation Exchange Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ce7c8b7a9417224c0afbb20539a64a7ff8e6366</link><description>Ion exchange membranes used for energy generation and water purification selectively transport ions, and this characteristic is strongly influenced by ion sorption in such membranes. Although water content and fixed charge group concentration are key factors affecting ion sorption in ion exchange membranes, their individual effects on ion sorption are not often studied. Here, a series of cross-linked cation exchange membranes (CEMs) were synthesized with different water uptake values and similar fixed charge group concentrations to study the effect of water content on ion sorption in such materials. Equilibrium co-ion concentrations in all membranes were very similar at a given external salt concentration, suggesting that co-ion sorption in these materials was mainly influenced by fixed charge group concentration rather than water content per se. Equilibrium co-ion sorption data were interpreted using a thermodynamic model based on Donnan theory and Manning’s counterion condensation theory. The inhomogene...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ce7c8b7a9417224c0afbb20539a64a7ff8e6366</guid></item><item><title>Functionalized Porous Aromatic Frameworks as High‐Performance Adsorbents for the Rapid Removal of Boric Acid from Water</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/30e689feed9cde08289d2190638e5c7d347d67b0</link><description>This study demonstrates that functionalized, highly porous polymers are promising for the adsorptive capture of boric acid, a neutral contaminant that is difficult to remove from seawater using conventional reverse osmosis membranes. Appending N‐methyl‐d‐glucamine (NMDG) to the pore walls of high‐surface‐area porous aromatic frameworks (PAFs) yields the adsorbents PAF‐1‐NMDG and P2‐NMDG in a simple two‐step synthesis. The boron‐selective PAFs demonstrate adsorption capacities that are up to 70% higher than those of a commercial boron‐selective resin, Amberlite IRA743, and markedly faster adsorption rates, owing to their higher NMDG loadings and greater porosities relative to the resin. Remarkably, PAF‐1‐NMDG is able to reduce the boron concentration in synthetic seawater from 2.91 to &lt;0.5 ppm in less than 3 min at an adsorbent loading of only 0.3 mg mL−1. The boron adsorption rate constants of both frameworks, determined via a pseudo‐second‐order rate model, represent the highest values reported in the literature—in most cases orders of magnitude higher than those of other boron‐selective adsorbents. The frameworks can also be readily regenerated via mild acid/base treatment and maintain constant boron adsorption capacities for at least 10 regeneration cycles. These results highlight the numerous advantages of PAFs over traditional porous polymers in water treatment applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/30e689feed9cde08289d2190638e5c7d347d67b0</guid></item><item><title>Correction to Effect of Water Content on Sodium Chloride Sorption in Cross-Linked Cation Exchange Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f9c464a8655221ddaa43930f24a1a035262e3784</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f9c464a8655221ddaa43930f24a1a035262e3784</guid></item><item><title>Influence of water content on alkali metal chloride transport in cross-linked Poly(ethylene glycol) Diacrylate.1. Ion sorption</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98c0a85a48d0c000980c242ae3747e5b786d17a5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98c0a85a48d0c000980c242ae3747e5b786d17a5</guid></item><item><title>A Single‐Ion Conducting Borate Network Polymer as a Viable Quasi‐Solid Electrolyte for Lithium Metal Batteries</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/62ea8635456c65a434ab251c479de1da973c7e98</link><description>Lithium‐ion batteries have remained a state‐of‐the‐art electrochemical energy storage technology for decades now, but their energy densities are limited by electrode materials and conventional liquid electrolytes can pose significant safety concerns. Lithium metal batteries featuring Li metal anodes, solid polymer electrolytes, and high‐voltage cathodes represent promising candidates for next‐generation devices exhibiting improved power and safety, but such solid polymer electrolytes generally do not exhibit the required excellent electrochemical properties and thermal stability in tandem. Here, an interpenetrating network polymer with weakly coordinating anion nodes that functions as a high‐performing single‐ion conducting electrolyte in the presence of minimal plasticizer, with a wide electrochemical stability window, a high room‐temperature conductivity of 1.5 × 10−4 S cm−1, and exceptional selectivity for Li‐ion conduction (tLi+ = 0.95) is reported. Importantly, this material is also flame retardant and highly stable in contact with lithium metal. Significantly, a lithium metal battery prototype containing this quasi‐solid electrolyte is shown to outperform a conventional battery featuring a polymer electrolyte.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/62ea8635456c65a434ab251c479de1da973c7e98</guid></item><item><title>Influence of water content on alkali metal chloride transport in cross-linked Poly(ethylene glycol) diacrylate.2. Ion diffusion</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed52b2f69bbf98235416b14f1c765ed2f3daf54f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed52b2f69bbf98235416b14f1c765ed2f3daf54f</guid></item><item><title>Ionic conductivity of ion-exchange membranes: Measurement techniques and salt concentration dependence</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b48a54ae21b025424b9e649ac86d4fda751ebea2</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b48a54ae21b025424b9e649ac86d4fda751ebea2</guid></item><item><title>Ion-capture electrodialysis using multifunctional adsorptive membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6a199a9fd35ae4b98e442e99e62d033baf749e50</link><description>One-step purification and desalination The purification of water for drinking purposes can require multiple filtration steps and technologies to remove contaminants such as salts and heavy metals. Some contaminants could have value if recovered, but these are often discharged in the waste streams. Uliana et al. describe a general approach for the fabrication of robust, tunable, adsorptive membranes through the incorporation of porous aromatic framework (PAF) nanoparticles into ion exchange membranes such as those made from sulfonated polymers. Salts are removed using a series of cation and anion exchange membranes, and the PAF particles can be selected to capture specific target ions, such as those of copper, mercury, or iron. This allows for simultaneous desalination and decontamination of the water. Science, this issue p. 296 High-performance adsorptive membranes enable one-step desalination of complex water sources and target solute capture. Technologies that can efficiently purify nontraditional water sources are needed to meet rising global demand for clean water. Water treatment plants typically require a series of costly separation units to achieve desalination and the removal of toxic trace contaminants such as heavy metals and boron. We report a series of robust, selective, and tunable adsorptive membranes that feature porous aromatic framework nanoparticles embedded within ion exchange polymers and demonstrate their use in an efficient, one-step separation strategy termed ion-capture electrodialysis. This process uses electrodialysis configurations with adsorptive membranes to simultaneously desalinate complex water sources and capture diverse target solutes with negligible capture of competing ions. Our methods are applicable to the development of efficient and selective multifunctional separations that use adsorptive membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6a199a9fd35ae4b98e442e99e62d033baf749e50</guid></item><item><title>Reformulating the
 permselectivity‐conductivity
 tradeoff relation in
 ion‐exchange
 membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f95372d2f8d7d24ba6e000ab46c2d3b359676c02</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f95372d2f8d7d24ba6e000ab46c2d3b359676c02</guid></item><item><title>Influence of fixed charge concentration and water uptake on ion sorption in AMPS/PEGDA membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/149054afa9d3872bae72a98d043d9f72f6afef55</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/149054afa9d3872bae72a98d043d9f72f6afef55</guid></item><item><title>Manning condensation in ion exchange membranes: A review on ion partitioning and diffusion models</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c8100f76fea9eb9f6fc39daec8c1e64fc4168162</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c8100f76fea9eb9f6fc39daec8c1e64fc4168162</guid></item><item><title>Salt and Ion Transport in a Series of Crosslinked Amps/Pegda Hydrogel Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9197762c0094448899d72d306aea92a3f62a788e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9197762c0094448899d72d306aea92a3f62a788e</guid></item><item><title>Interfacial interactions between polymers and selective adsorbents influence ion transport properties of boron scavenging ion-exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c279fc6b75e4bc6fb509e23c586097e12259de93</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c279fc6b75e4bc6fb509e23c586097e12259de93</guid></item><item><title>Accurately measuring the ionic conductivity of membranes via the direct contact method</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a910b930efe2712557417f383086af65b35304d0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a910b930efe2712557417f383086af65b35304d0</guid></item><item><title>The need for ion-exchange membranes with high charge densities</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/50496565e9757b918ad2c18c31d875ac73ffe47a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/50496565e9757b918ad2c18c31d875ac73ffe47a</guid></item><item><title>Electrosorption Integrated with Bipolar Membrane Water Dissociation: A Coupled Approach to Chemical-free Boron Removal.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1402a8988b9c31039e40c40b3fcf7baba756930c</link><description>Boron removal from aqueous solutions has long persisted as a technological challenge, accounting for a disproportionately large fraction of the chemical and energy usage in seawater desalination and other industrial processes like lithium recovery. Here, we introduce a novel electrosorption-based boron removal technology with the capability to overcome the limitations of current state-of-the-art methods. Specifically, we incorporate a bipolar membrane (BPM) between a pair of porous carbon electrodes, demonstrating a synergized BPM-electrosorption process for the first time. The ion transport and charge transfer mechanisms of the BPM-electrosorption system are thoroughly investigated, confirming that water dissociation in the BPM is highly coupled with electrosorption of anions at the anode. We then demonstrate effective boron removal by the BPM-electrosorption system and verify that the mechanism for boron removal is electrosorption, as opposed to adsorption on the carbon electrodes or in the BPM. The effect of applied voltage on the boron removal performance is then evaluated, revealing that applied potentials above ∼1.0 V result in a decline in process efficiency due to the increased prevalence of detrimental Faradaic reactions at the anode. The BPM-electrosorption system is then directly compared with flow-through electrosorption, highlighting key advantages of the process with regard to boron sorption capacity and energy consumption. Overall, the BPM-electrosorption shows promising boron removal capability, with a sorption capacity &gt;4.5 μmol g-C-1 and a corresponding specific energy consumption of &lt;2.5 kWh g-B-1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1402a8988b9c31039e40c40b3fcf7baba756930c</guid></item><item><title>Counter-ion Conductivity and Selectivity Trade-Off for Commercial Ion-Exchange Membranes at High Salinities</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1c8ec5ae19f061b60ff3dcd18b5f3bde594607da</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1c8ec5ae19f061b60ff3dcd18b5f3bde594607da</guid></item><item><title>Understanding Monovalent Cation Diffusion in Negatively Charged Membranes and the Role of Membrane Water Content</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c8e6f3bc82b392074a47321f1c96065335d2aa9e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c8e6f3bc82b392074a47321f1c96065335d2aa9e</guid></item><item><title>Predicting the Conductivity–Selectivity Trade-Off and Upper Bound in Ion-Exchange Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5f7fd06501c9a6ab98b17981643052b0847c868a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5f7fd06501c9a6ab98b17981643052b0847c868a</guid></item><item><title>Bound Water Enhances the Ion Selectivity of Highly Charged Polymer Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6905a032073daf16811e51da318fe07057061873</link><description>Electrochemical technologies for water treatment, resource recovery, energy generation, and energy storage rely on charged polymer membranes to selectively transport ions. With the rise of applications involving hypersaline brines, such as management of desalination brine or the recovery of ions from brines, there is an urgent need for membranes that can sustain high conductivity and selectivity under such challenging conditions. Current membranes are constrained by an inherent trade-off between conductivity and selectivity, alongside concerns regarding their high costs. Moreover, a gap in the fundamental understanding of ion transport within charged membranes at high salinities prevents the development of membranes that could meet these stringent requirements efficiently. Here, we present the synthesis of scalable, highly charged membranes that demonstrate high conductivity and selectivity while contacting 1 and 5 molal NaCl solutions. A detailed analysis of the membrane transport properties reveals that the high proportion of bound water in the membranes, enabled by the high charge content and hydrophilic structure of the polymers, enhances both the ion partitioning and diffusion selectivities of the membranes. These structure/property relationships derived from this study offer valuable guidance for designing next-generation membranes that simultaneously achieve exceptional conductivity and selectivity in high-salinity conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6905a032073daf16811e51da318fe07057061873</guid></item><item><title>Coordination, hydration, and diffusion of vanadyl cations in negatively charged polymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/61eae5c6fd84948bc1016e465952a1053c79cae6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/61eae5c6fd84948bc1016e465952a1053c79cae6</guid></item><item><title>Modeling insights to navigate limitations in bipolar membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2d556877108f9b028c2e51a22873181e006383c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2d556877108f9b028c2e51a22873181e006383c</guid></item><item><title>A highly selective and energy efficient approach to boron removal overcomes the Achilles heel of seawater desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1d054dbfc06a17dffa432ce0da94a02bcbca233f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1d054dbfc06a17dffa432ce0da94a02bcbca233f</guid></item><item><title>Techno-economic perspective on the limitations and prospects of ion-exchange membrane technologies</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ff2f469b6181b07f5f7770ee9d3ed5c5ed31ee89</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ff2f469b6181b07f5f7770ee9d3ed5c5ed31ee89</guid></item><item><title>Fast and selective ion transport in ultrahigh-charge-density membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c43e43b2d2095c6ab91af75c072662605b8edee0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c43e43b2d2095c6ab91af75c072662605b8edee0</guid></item><item><title>Self‐Assembled Membranes for High Ion Selectivity and Proton Blocking in Electrochemical Applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2f20e2edb5e5ad18a664ab91ca6482d8d58590aa</link><description>Anion‐exchange membranes (AEMs) with high anion/cation selectivity and exceptional proton‐blocking ability are critical for applications such as bipolar membrane electrodialysis and electrochemical acid recovery. However, existing AEMs are constrained by a trade‐off between ionic conductivity and selectivity, largely due to the intrinsic coupling between charge density and water content, and they suffer from excessive proton leakage facilitated by the Grotthuss hopping mechanism. In this work, poly(vinylimidazolium) membranes functionalized with long alkyl side chains that self‐assemble into well‐defined microphase‐separated morphologies stabilized by hydrophobic and electrostatic interactions are reported. These unique structures localize the charge density along the polymer backbone to promote fast and selective ion transport. As a result, these membranes exhibit ionic conductivities and counter‐ion diffusivities surpassing those of conventional homogeneous membranes, along with unprecedented counter‐ion/co‐ion selectivity and proton‐blocking ability. These results establish a new design paradigm for high‐performance, phase separated charged polymer membranes that overcome the limitations of homogeneous membranes, with broad implications for advanced electrochemical technologies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2f20e2edb5e5ad18a664ab91ca6482d8d58590aa</guid></item><item><title>Optimized Ion-Transport Properties of Diallylammonium-Cyclopolymerized Anion-Exchange Membranes for High-Performance Water Electrolysis.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ad526c616a4693465fbb0b70e8aec6bca563369f</link><description>Anion-exchange membranes (AEMs) are the key components of AEM-based water electrolysis (AEMWE) for green hydrogen production. Unfortunately, many AEMs have unsatisfactory ion conductivity, and the factors governing their ion transport remain unclear. To address these limitations, herein, a new pyrrolidinium-containing diallylammonium-cyclopolymerized (PDT) AEM is proposed. Cyclopolymerization between diallyldimethylammonium chloride and tetraallylammonium bromide (TAAB, crosslinker) monomers in a porous polytetrafluoroethylene support yielded a pore-filled crosslinked PDT membrane, whose structure is controlled by adjusting its TAAB content. The OH- conductivity of the PDT membrane is more strongly correlated with its OH- diffusivity (determined by its internal water content) than its OH- partitioning (determined by its internal charge content). The optimized PDT membrane exhibited low gas crossover and high thermomechanical stability. Importantly, it displayed excellent AEMWE performance in both pure water (0.71 A cm-2 at 1.8 V) and 1 m KOH (5.25 A cm-2 at 1.8 V) at 80 °C with half-platinum-group metal electrodes, outperforming many previously reported and commercial AEMs, owing to its significantly high OH- conductivity. The PDT membrane also demonstrated stable AEMWE performance in 1 m KOH at 60 °C for 300 h. This study offers an effective means to fabricate high-performance AEMs and sheds light on their ion-transport mechanisms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ad526c616a4693465fbb0b70e8aec6bca563369f</guid></item><item><title>Current developments in electrochemical separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1ccad676e35912be2c0638d2a87f34a80ff02e6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1ccad676e35912be2c0638d2a87f34a80ff02e6</guid></item><item><title>Electrostatic Limits on Charge Selectivity in Ultrahigh Charge Density Polymer Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34506a8dd7c31bffd6703c120c30c6f51d2015b6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34506a8dd7c31bffd6703c120c30c6f51d2015b6</guid></item><item><title>Selective partitioning and uphill transport enable effective Li/Mg ion separation by negatively charged membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bca9735b302e201ea0b798faec791d0909309ce</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9bca9735b302e201ea0b798faec791d0909309ce</guid></item><item><title>Selective boron removal from water by functional-polymer-film-assisted electrosorption</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f906acfe32d847d60e166829d941b37b3fd9013</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f906acfe32d847d60e166829d941b37b3fd9013</guid></item></channel></rss>