<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Manish Kumar</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/2109944022</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Manish Kumar</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:35:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Beyond the carbon footprint: Virtual conferences increase diversity, equity, and inclusion</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/492dc7f82cfca86242df5eaf5a7323662462b2ad</link><description>
 Among many roles, conferences disseminate research, grow professional networks, and train employees. They also significantly contribute to climate change due to their sizable carbon footprint. More recently, additional negative aspects have surfaced. Namely, they present significant barriers to achieving Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI). Here, we perform a meta-analysis of events that transitioned to virtual formats during the COVID-19 pandemic and show that this approach may provide a solution. Our analysis compared demographic and travel data of the same scientific conferences. When evaluating DEI, we considered factors including cost, gender, career stage, and geographic location. Costs associated with attending in-person conferences varied between 3% to 142% of attendees’ regional annual per capita Gross Domestic Product (GDP). An increase in the fractional make-up of 2020 virtual conference delegations was observed for students (29% to 43%). Notable increases in attendance were observed for women (66% to 253% increase) and non-research-intensive countries (29% to 482% increase).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/492dc7f82cfca86242df5eaf5a7323662462b2ad</guid></item><item><title>Conference demographics and footprint changed by virtual platforms</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/90db16b2525670394e9b79842205e2f8af2a1114</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/90db16b2525670394e9b79842205e2f8af2a1114</guid></item><item><title>Harnessing blue energy with COF membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/93ecf17d755d851042c49b742368b845fb2a38ba</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/93ecf17d755d851042c49b742368b845fb2a38ba</guid></item><item><title>Water vapor sorption and transport in carbon molecular sieve membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4f93f9dbbfa190d45f481a4eec236be825de2be7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4f93f9dbbfa190d45f481a4eec236be825de2be7</guid></item><item><title>2D Materials for Combination Therapy to Address Challenges in the Treatment of Cancer</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/19a529290a1bc80da81260d759c91f361a833356</link><description>2D materials exhibit a variety of characteristics that make them appealing platforms for cancer treatment such as high drug loading capacity and photothermal and photodynamic properties. A key advantage of 2D material platforms for oncological applications is the ability to harness multiple modalities including drug delivery, photothermal therapy, photodynamic therapy, chemodynamic therapy, gene delivery, and immunotherapy approaches for improved efficacy. In this review, a comparison of the unique properties of different classes of 2D materials that enable their usage as platforms for multimodal therapy is provided. Further, the benefits and drawbacks of different platforms are also highlighted. Finally, current challenges and emerging opportunities for future development of 2D materials to further enable combination therapy and translation from the bench to clinical oncology applications are discussed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/19a529290a1bc80da81260d759c91f361a833356</guid></item><item><title>Dehydrated Biomimetic Membranes with Skinlike Structure and Function.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b5aeea8f8cf03471fafcab7b0e2eec1b116202bb</link><description>Novel vapor-permeable materials are sought after for applications in protective wear, energy generation, and water treatment. Current impermeable protective materials effectively block harmful agents but trap heat due to poor water vapor transfer. Here we present a new class of materials, vapor permeable dehydrated nanoporous biomimetic membranes (DBMs), based on channel proteins. This application for biomimetic membranes is unexpected as channel proteins and biomimetic membranes were assumed to be unstable under dry conditions. DBMs mimic human skin's structure to offer both high vapor transport and small molecule exclusion under dry conditions. DBMs feature highly organized pores resembling sweat pores in human skin, but at super high densities (&gt;1012 pores/cm2). These DBMs achieved exceptional water vapor transport rates, surpassing commercial breathable fabrics by up to 6.2 times, despite containing &gt;2 orders of magnitude smaller pores (1 nm vs &gt;700 nm). These DBMs effectively excluded model biological agents and harmful chemicals both in liquid and vapor phases, again in contrast with the commercial breathable fabrics. Remarkably, while hydrated biomimetic membranes were highly permeable to liquid water, they exhibited higher water resistances after dehydration at values &gt;38 times that of commercial breathable fabrics. Molecular dynamics simulations support our hypothesis that dehydration induced protein hydrophobicity increases which enhanced DBM performance. DBMs hold promise for various applications, including membrane distillation, dehumidification, and protective barriers for atmospheric water harvesting materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b5aeea8f8cf03471fafcab7b0e2eec1b116202bb</guid></item><item><title>Effective Removal of Enteric Viruses by Moringa oleifera Seed Extract Functionalized Cotton Filter</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ae0cbbb793f17d9831bfb3f7d0925813f0403e50</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ae0cbbb793f17d9831bfb3f7d0925813f0403e50</guid></item><item><title>Approaching Ideal Selectivity with Bioinspired and Biomimetic Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/65e558008d34250d834abe34ad6d56ccc83fea9f</link><description>The applications of polymeric membranes have grown rapidly compared to traditional separation technologies due to their energy efficiency and smaller footprint. However, their potential is not fully realized due, in part, to their heterogeneity, which results in a "permeability-selectivity" trade-off for most membrane applications. Inspired by the intricate architecture and excellent homogeneity of biological membranes, bioinspired and biomimetic membranes (BBMs) aim to emulate biological membranes for practical applications. This Review highlights the potential of BBMs to overcome the limitations of polymeric membranes by utilizing the "division of labor" between well-defined permeable pores and impermeable matrix molecules seen in biological membranes. We explore the exceptional performance of membranes in biological organisms, focusing on their two major components: membrane proteins (biological channels) and lipid matrix molecules. We then discuss how these natural materials can be replaced with artificial mimics for enhanced properties and how macro-scale BBMs are developed. We highlight key demonstrations in the field of BBMs that draw upon the factors responsible for transport through biological membranes. Additionally, current state-of-the-art methods for fabrication of BBMs are reviewed with potential challenges and prospects for future applications. Finally, we provide considerations for future research that could enable BBMs to progress toward scale-up and enhanced applicability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/65e558008d34250d834abe34ad6d56ccc83fea9f</guid></item><item><title>Rapid Heat-Driven Formation of 2D Nanosheets from Membrane Proteins and Block Copolymers</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/55cff9a059e3f7d611556fce8eae7cafd5631a0e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/55cff9a059e3f7d611556fce8eae7cafd5631a0e</guid></item><item><title>Side-Chain and Ring-Size Effects on Permeability in Artificial Water Channels.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c1ddd1c17766bb2f74eaf140d60d683638ece89d</link><description>Artificial water channels (AWCs) have emerged as a promising framework for stable water permeation, with water transport rates comparable to aquaporins (3.4-40.3 × 108 H2O/channel/s). In this study, we probe the influence of ring-size and side-chain length on the water permeability observed within a class of AWCs termed ligand-appended pillar[n]arenes (LAPs) that have an adjustable ring-size (m) and side-chain length (n). Through all-atom molecular dynamics simulations, we calculate the permeability of these channels using the collective diffusion model and find their permeabilities. We characterize the mechanistic influence of pillar[n]arene ring-size and side-chain length on the channel water permeability by analyzing the characteristics of the internal permeating water-wire and the surrounding channel structure. We observe that water permeability decreases as a function of increasing ring-size due to increases in hydrophilic contacts between the permeating water-wire and the oxygen groups on the channel wall. Further, we observe an increase in water permeability as a function of side-chain length due to increased partitioning of the channel terminal groups into the hydrophilic blocks of the surrounding bilayer. For the LAP6 channel, with increase in side-chain length, the distance between terminal groups increases and leads to an increase in pore size, thereby enhancing water permeability. In the case of LAP5, as side-chain length increases, the channel displays a compensatory effect between tilt and bend angle due to the flexible side-chains. Such flexibility leads to higher terminal group partitioning in the hydrophilic blocks of the bilayer and extends the permeating water-wire. This increase in water-wire length and hydrophilic block access overcomes the nonmonotonic pore size trend in pillar[5]arene channels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c1ddd1c17766bb2f74eaf140d60d683638ece89d</guid></item><item><title>Moringa oleifera Protein-Functionalized Diatomaceous Earth for Nanoparticle Removal</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1385ee9343630e1922fa0f11ff591f42be0d9061</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1385ee9343630e1922fa0f11ff591f42be0d9061</guid></item><item><title>Highly Breathable and Protective Carbon Fabrics.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ca53f4753ebe6f0a0d8969c1cf82f4b349f866bd</link><description>Achieving high water vapor transport while maintaining selective barrier properties in a single material is a crucial property desired in various fields. Breathable protective fabrics is one such area. This study specifically investigates the water vapor transport characteristics and barrier performance of carbon molecular sieve (CMS) membranes for potential applications in breathable protective fabrics. CMS membranes were fabricated by pyrolyzing precursor membranes with a focus on exploring the impact of different pyrolysis temperatures, membrane structures, and polymer concentrations on the properties of such membranes. A series of symmetric and asymmetric Matrimid CMS membranes were synthesized and tested. Samples pyrolyzed at 550 °C with 10% polymer concentration exhibited remarkable water vapor transport capability, outperforming commercial breathable fabrics by a factor of 2.6 despite having 3 orders of magnitude smaller pores. Owing to these small pores, they provide 7.5 times higher protective capacity compared to commercial breathable fabrics, which is comparable to that of the standard vapor impermeable protective material─butyl rubber.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ca53f4753ebe6f0a0d8969c1cf82f4b349f866bd</guid></item><item><title>3D Nanoscale Structures of Hydrated Polyamide Desalination Membranes Revealed by Cryogenic Transmission Electron Microscopy Tomography.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac8ff8f118a377659d374686756f8be1919e7af8</link><description>Desalination via reverse osmosis (RO) membrane technology is a preferred solution to the ongoing global challenges of freshwater scarcity. The active separation layer of RO membranes is a polyamide thin film (&lt;200 nm), whose morphology critically influences membrane performance. However, conflicting descriptions of trends between morphology and performance abound in the literature due to the lack of a rigorous morphological description of these membranes. Notably, comprehensive three-dimensional (3D) morphological characterization of these membranes has so far been conducted exclusively under dry conditions, which contrasts with the operational, hydrated state of these membranes. Here, we present, for the first time, characterization of the hydrated 3D nanoscale morphology of polyamide films from commercial brackish water (BW) and seawater (SW) membranes using cryo-transmission electron microscopy (cryo-TEM) tomography. Our findings reveal significant morphological differences between hydrated and dry membranes, resulting in variations in key structural parameters that impact performance. Both SW and BW membranes swell and increase in total volume and thickness upon hydration, with BW membranes exhibiting more pronounced swelling (32% vs 7% in volume and 35% vs 11% in effective thickness), primarily due to the lower degree of cross-linking of BW membranes. Additionally, while the surface area decreases upon hydration for both SW and BW membranes, indicating a smoothing of surface nodules and cavities, surface roughness remains unchanged, suggesting that current roughness measurement methods such as atomic force microscopy do not capture intrinsic morphological features. Overall, this study demonstrates the feasibility of employing cryo-TEM tomography techniques to characterize RO membrane morphology under operation relevant conditions, thus enabling a better linkage between membrane morphology and performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac8ff8f118a377659d374686756f8be1919e7af8</guid></item><item><title>Lanthanide-Selective Artificial Channels.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3706cc353ad4b758df56bad3d57a632e81f5cc26</link><description>Lanthanides serve as essential elements for modern technology, playing critical roles in batteries, wind turbines, portable electronics, and energy-efficient lighting. Purifying lanthanides from ores and recycling them from end-of-life consumer materials are costly and damaging to the environment due to inefficient separation technologies. In this study, we present a new approach for lanthanide separations using supramolecular membrane channel nanopores based on a pillar[5]arene scaffold with appended diphenylphosphine oxide (DPP) ligands. These channels show high transport selectivity (&gt;18:1) of the middle lanthanides, europium (Eu3+) and terbium (Tb3+) ions, over monovalent K+ ions and also excluded other common mono- and divalent metal ions (Na+, Ca2+, and Mg2+) including protons. These membrane channels also have high lanthanide-lanthanide transport selectivity with Eu3+/La3+ selectivity of &gt;40 and Eu3+/Yb3+ selectivity of ∼30. Additionally, they demonstrated significantly higher selectivities between middle lanthanides and both light and heavy lanthanides: Tb3+/La3+ (∼140), Tb3+/Yb3+ (∼72), Tb3+/Nd3+ (∼58), and Eu3+/Nd3+ (∼17), which are considerably higher than selectivities reported in studies using traditional solvent extraction methods. Molecular dynamics simulations indicate that the high selectivity observed is due to specific water-mediated interactions between the hydrated ions and the channel. Our findings could contribute to ongoing efforts to improve lanthanide separation efficiency and reduce the environmental impact associated with current methods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3706cc353ad4b758df56bad3d57a632e81f5cc26</guid></item><item><title>ACS ES&amp;T Engineering’s 2024 Excellence in Review Awards</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4190697c34a3c2d358c85be09d62b74ad5bec800</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4190697c34a3c2d358c85be09d62b74ad5bec800</guid></item><item><title>Impact of Ligands on the Ion-Ion Selectivity of Ligand-Appended-Pillar[n]arene Channels.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d0b6efef503e2ee5de3f4db6e1d1dd2bccd28c04</link><description>Ligand-appended pillar[5]arene (LAP) channels are emerging as a promising platform for ion-selective membranes. In this study, we investigated the ion selectivities of three LAP channels functionalized with distinct ligands: diglycolamine, carbamoylmethyl phosphine oxide, and propionamide phosphonic acid. These ligands were chosen based on their demonstrated affinities for lanthanides in solvent extraction studies. We examined the selectivity of each channel toward a series of monovalent, divalent, and trivalent ions: Li+, Na+, K+, Mg2+, Ca2+, La3+, Eu3+, and Yb3+. To quantify ion-channel interactions and the energetics of translocation, we computed the potential of mean force (PMF) profiles for each ion. These PMFs were subsequently recast into permeability coefficients, enabling a direct evaluation of ion permselectivity. Our results reveal distinct selectivity patterns governed by the chemical nature of the appended ligands. The diglycolamine-functionalized channel exhibits strong interactions with monovalent ions, leading to replication of the Li+ bulk hydration shell within the channel. This promotes preferential transport Li+ ions while effectively excluding divalent and trivalent species. In contrast, the carbamoylmethyl phosphine oxide-functionalized channel displays a reduced selectivity between monovalent ions while similarly exhibiting an effective rejection of divalent and trivalent ions. This arises from steric hindrance around channel-lining oxygens imposed by the ligand's bulky phenyl groups which limits heavy ion coordination and promotes retention of hydration shells effectively increasing effective ion size. The propionamide phosphonic acid-functionalized channel exhibits a different trend, favoring ions with lower hydration free energies, with K+ ions showing enhanced permeation. These findings highlight the critical role of ligand-ion interactions in modulating ion selectivity within LAP channels. In particular, the strong coordination exhibited by diglycolamine and propionamide phosphonic acid ligands significantly influences the ion transport energetics and selectivity profiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d0b6efef503e2ee5de3f4db6e1d1dd2bccd28c04</guid></item><item><title>Highly Selective Molecular-Sieving Membranes by Interfacial Polymerization for H2 Purification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e5fcefe06f1a3383cb877b5fdaacbabbf93658b7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e5fcefe06f1a3383cb877b5fdaacbabbf93658b7</guid></item><item><title>Spontaneous Formation of Oil-Rich Polymer-Only Droplet Interface Bilayers Assembled from PB-PEO Block Copolymers.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4cb2d04b13d41ad64c43d7668f661a1dc35ab7f9</link><description>Droplet interface bilayers (DIBs) are versatile membrane models that have traditionally relied on phospholipids for mimicking the structure and transport properties of biological membranes. However, lipid-based DIBs are often limited by their mechanical fragility and restricted compositions. Here, we report the spontaneous formation and characterization of polymer-only DIBs (pDIBs) assembled from amphiphilic polybutadiene-block-poly(ethylene oxide) (PB-PEO) diblock copolymers in hydrocarbon oils. Using a combination of interfacial tensiometry, electrophysiology, and imaging, we show that PB-PEO amphiphiles form stable monolayers and thick interfacial bilayer membranes in both hexadecane and squalene without the need for external bias, additional lipids, or cosolvents. These pDIBs exhibit high values of membrane resistance (10-50 MΩ·cm2), negligible permeability to small hydrophilic solutes, and substantially larger hydrophobic thicknesses (18-23 nm) than their lipid analogs. Under applied voltage, PB-PEO membranes undergo reversible thinning and lateral expansion, with extracted electrocompression and electrowetting coefficients exceeding those reported for lipid membranes by up to 1000-fold. These characteristics indicate a significant amount of hexadecane or squalene remains within the hydrophobic core of the membrane upon bilayer formation. Incorporation of valinomycin and alamethicin resulted in voltage-responsive ion transport, demonstrating that even thick polymer membranes can support bioinspired ion conduction. These findings demonstrate PB-PEO-based pDIBs as an alternative option for constructing model membranes and motivate continued work to examine a wider variety of amphiphilic block copolymers and oils necessary for achieving thinner polymer membranes useful in diverse applications such as synthetic biology, programmable biomimetic materials, and bioinspired tissue-like assemblies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4cb2d04b13d41ad64c43d7668f661a1dc35ab7f9</guid></item><item><title>Recognizing Excellence in Environmental Engineering Research: The 2024
 ACS ES&amp;T Engineering
 ’s Best Paper Awards</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/46f6677629cb8913e35f57912e7e5a392cb006bc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/46f6677629cb8913e35f57912e7e5a392cb006bc</guid></item><item><title>Quantitative Nanoscale Structure Determination in Polymer Desalination Membranes by Correlated Electron Tomography and Spectroscopy.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a12a00bba50970ef16faf3d41ca2ba269e9eb369</link><description>A complete and thorough understanding of the complicated heterogeneous structure of polyamide separation membranes is crucial to improving their performance. Electron tomography has been used to study density variations in dense polymer membranes; however, the nonuniformity of membrane thickness and surface morphology present major challenges to the accuracy of that method. In this article, we show that nanoscale 2D electron energy loss spectroscopy (EELS) maps can be correlated with 3D scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) tomography to improve the quantitative mapping of density. We reveal quantitative nanoscale structural differences between commercial seawater and brackish water polyamide thin film composite reverse osmosis membranes and compare them to thin uniform printed membranes. To reduce electron beam damage, we employ a high-speed direct electron detector for low-dose EELS, which allows for membrane thickness and electron scattering measurements to be spatially correlated to improve the measurement of density. We resolve nanoscale differences between three polyamide membranes which have distinctly different separation performances. Our work provides a framework for the use of STEM and EELS to extract heterogeneous density variations in structurally complex membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a12a00bba50970ef16faf3d41ca2ba269e9eb369</guid></item><item><title>CO2 Sorption in Moisture Swing Anion Exchange Resins for Direct Air Capture: Experimental Isotherm Determination and Modeling.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6e5ced4a6798afc46e6554d202fa5171fb08c310</link><description>Moisture swing (MS) sorption is a promising direct air capture (DAC) technology to achieve negative CO2 emissions and counter global warming. In this study, MS CO2 sorption in a model MS sorbent, IRA900, was investigated. IRA900 is a macroporous commercial strong-base anion exchange resin (AER) with quaternary ammonium functional groups. A rigorous CO2 desorption process was developed to desorb all CO2 from the sample and obtain CO2 sorption isotherms as a function of relative humidity, CO2 partial pressure, and temperature. CO2 sorption increased with decreasing relative humidity, decreasing temperature, and increasing CO2 partial pressure. Remarkably, the total CO2 uptake from the sorption isotherms matched the ion exchange capacity (IEC) of the material, suggesting a stoichiometry of one CO2 molecule reacting per active site. An isotherm model for CO2 sorption starting with empty sorption sites (i.e., with the AER in the OH- form) described the experimental data well, supporting the hypothesis that the bicarbonate-loaded AER fully unloaded to the OH- state following rigorous CO2 desorption. CO2 sorption kinetics were studied, and carbon diffusion coefficients were estimated as a function of %RH and CO2 partial pressure. Overall, this study provides a roadmap for the systematic evaluation of MS CO2 DAC materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6e5ced4a6798afc46e6554d202fa5171fb08c310</guid></item></channel></rss>