<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Menachem Elimalech</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/2896168</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Menachem Elimalech</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:40:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tethered electrolyte active-layer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c439a730e81a442a6bcb93eb25413bef6e94a657</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c439a730e81a442a6bcb93eb25413bef6e94a657</guid></item><item><title>A Mechanistic Model for Salt and Water Transport in Low-Salt-Rejection Reverse Osmosis Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a250bc0f166de697e3f49f5ee195695f3a04ce4e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a250bc0f166de697e3f49f5ee195695f3a04ce4e</guid></item><item><title>Directing the Research Agenda on Water and Energy Technologies with Process and Economic Analysis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/473854167f5b3369c7a51b25c257cc90809850d8</link><description>Climate change is directly impacting energy consumption, water availability, and agricultural production. Among the global efforts to address the root causes of carbon emissions, numerous emerging technologies have been proposed...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/473854167f5b3369c7a51b25c257cc90809850d8</guid></item><item><title>Machine learning reveals key ion selectivity mechanisms in polymeric membranes with subnanometer pores</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/84d509ecba4a998dc2b2518620c8bb9c6c85e438</link><description>Machine learning unveils molecular transport mechanisms obscured by entropy-enthalpy compensation in polymeric membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/84d509ecba4a998dc2b2518620c8bb9c6c85e438</guid></item><item><title>The open membrane database: Synthesis–structure–performance relationships of reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/06fdaa0c6374543ec3f82d6a1328387d74c95951</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/06fdaa0c6374543ec3f82d6a1328387d74c95951</guid></item><item><title>Reply to “A resurrection of the Haber-Weiss reaction”</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/51414dd3f4742e67804344d18a697f92298004ca</link><description>In our recent published paper 1, we presented an entirely new design of a Janus electrocatalytic membrane and demonstrated its efficient water decontamination performance. The Janus electrocatalytic membrane demonstrated in situ singlet oxygen (O2) formation inside the membrane porous structure, enabling enhanced removal of contaminants from water in a single-pass electrofiltration at very low energy consumption and without the addition of chemical precursors. The enhanced water decontamination performance was ascribed to the electrocatalytic membrane design. The Janus membrane integrates both the anodic and cathodic reactions within the membrane porous structure during flow-through filtration. This unique membrane structure induces spatial confinement within the membrane inner pores and enhances convective mass transport of reactants. In contrast to traditional electrofiltration designs with membranes functioning either as cathode or anode, using a Janus membrane makes full use of electrical energy, thus promoting energy efficiency. In the accompanying Comment, Dr. Koppenol raised concerns regarding the O2 formation pathways in the Janus electrocatalytic membrane. In our work, we proposed potential O2 formation pathways in the membrane. Due to limitations of in situ characterization techniques inside a porous membrane, we were not able to provide the exact reaction pathways for O2 formation without solid experimental evidence. We appreciate Dr. Koppenol’s effort in proposing an alternative hypothesis for the O2 formation pathway in the Janus electrocatalytic membrane, which involves O2 generation at the cathode followed by anodic O2 oxidation for O2 formation. The second concern raised by Dr. Koppenol is whether •OH exists in the Janus electrocatalytic membrane. As stated in our manuscript, the Pt anode is inherently an “active” anode. With its low oxygen evolution overpotential, the “active” anode readily transforms the generated physisorbed •OH into a higher oxide. This analysis has been proven by both theoretical and experimental studies2,3. If •OH is generated in the Janus electrocatalytic membrane, it would be readily converted to the higher oxide PtO. Therefore, free •OH would not be detected in the membrane. The third concern raised by Dr. Koppenol is the suitability of electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) measurement using 2,2,6,6-tetramethylpiperidine (TEMP) as the trapping agent for O2 detection. The general consensus is that TEMP is able to react with O2, forming 2,2,6,6-tetramethyl-1-piperidinyloxy (TEMPO). The TEMPO product exhibits a characteristic 1:1:1 triplet signal in the EPR spectrum, serving as an indicator for O2 existence. This method has been widely applied in the field of environmental science as an indicator method for O2 detection4,5. Nevertheless, the EPR-TEMP detection method is currently being discussed6, as it cannot exclusively indicate O2 formation. This is because TEMPO may possibly be generated by another route, wherein TEMP•+ intermediate radical is first formed, then undergoes deprotonation and reaction with molecular oxygen6. As we stated above, in situ characterization techniques of stepwise transformations of the intermediates inside the porous membrane structure are challenging. Hence, at present, we cannot confirm the TEMP transformation pathway inside the membrane. Given this situation, we employed other detection agents—furfuryl alcohol (FFA) and sulfamethoxazole (SMX)—to confirm O2 formation. The oxidized products of FFA and SMX by O2 (Figs. S11 and S17 in the Supporting Information of our article1) were in agreement with previously reported results7,8. Overall, we adopted different detection methods to collectively confirm O2 formation in the membrane. Regarding the ROS terminology, Dr. Koppenol states that neither O2 nor H2O2 are reactive. We clarify that although H2O2 and O2 are not highly reactive species as •OH, they are reactive with contaminants in water. H2O2 has been demonstrated as an effective disinfectant for inactivating bacteria and mitigating membrane fouling in water treatment9. In addition, the use of the term “ROS” or “reactive oxygen species” for describing H2O2, O2, •OH, and O2 is widely known in the fields of chemistry and environmental science10. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-27824-1 OPEN</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/51414dd3f4742e67804344d18a697f92298004ca</guid></item><item><title>Laser Interferometry for Precise Measurement of Ultralow Flow Rates from Permeable Materials</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8cafd7ef9326eacd9cd81e9695acf2633009b7ce</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8cafd7ef9326eacd9cd81e9695acf2633009b7ce</guid></item><item><title>Molecular Simulations to Elucidate Transport Phenomena in Polymeric Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/07edc26520b6b7bc23f593021bf6ad54b4244cc7</link><description>Despite decades of dominance in separation technology, progress in the design and development of high-performance polymer-based membranes has been incremental. Recent advances in materials science and chemical synthesis provide opportunities for molecular-level design of next-generation membrane materials. Such designs necessitate a fundamental understanding of transport and separation mechanisms at the molecular scale. Molecular simulations are important tools that could lead to the development of fundamental structure-property-performance relationships for advancing membrane design. In this Perspective, we assess the application and capability of molecular simulations to understand the mechanisms of ion and water transport across polymeric membranes. Additionally, we discuss the reliability of molecular models in mimicking the structure and chemistry of nanochannels and transport pathways in polymeric membranes. We conclude by providing research directions for resolving key knowledge gaps related to transport phenomena in polymeric membranes and for the construction of structure-property-performance relationships for the design of next-generation membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/07edc26520b6b7bc23f593021bf6ad54b4244cc7</guid></item><item><title>Distinct impacts of natural organic matter and colloidal particles on gypsum crystallization.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/595336a05c377d1acf5afcbbc86b514bb74b8e4e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/595336a05c377d1acf5afcbbc86b514bb74b8e4e</guid></item><item><title>Inorganic Scaling in Membrane Desalination: Models, Mechanisms, and Characterization Methods.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/54f20e78704de680eccf3b5f4a4a6b34ae3c1130</link><description>Inorganic scaling caused by precipitation of sparingly soluble salts at supersaturation is a common but critical issue, limiting the efficiency of membrane-based desalination and brine management technologies as well as other engineered systems. A wide range of minerals including calcium carbonate, calcium sulfate, and silica precipitate during membrane-based desalination, limiting water recovery and reducing process efficiency. The economic impact of scaling on desalination processes requires understanding of its sources, causes, effects, and control methods. In this Critical Review, we first describe nucleation mechanisms and crystal growth theories, which are fundamental to understanding inorganic scale formation during membrane desalination. We, then, discuss the key mechanisms and factors that govern membrane scaling, including membrane properties, such as surface roughness, charge, and functionality, as well as feedwater characteristics, such as pH, temperature, and ionic strength. We follow with a critical review of current characterization techniques for both homogeneous and heterogeneous nucleation, focusing on the strengths and limitations of each technique to elucidate scale-inducing mechanisms, observe actual crystal growth, and analyze the outcome of scaling behaviors of desalination membranes. We conclude with an outlook on research needs and future research directions to provide guidelines for scale mitigation in water treatment and desalination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/54f20e78704de680eccf3b5f4a4a6b34ae3c1130</guid></item><item><title>(Invited) Electrified Membranes for Transformation of Nitrate in Wastewaters</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bb213e1d183bb4d1cf1ee29e6bc9fde57d9c2d97</link><description>The release of nitrate to the environment from wastewater effluent and agricultural runoff contributes to groundwater contamination, harmful algal blooms, and disruption of biogeochemical nitrogen flows. Typical treatment methods are based on nitrate separation, which produces waste streams that are often discharged to the environment. Alternatively, nitrate conversion via electrochemical reduction eliminates the production of concentrated waste streams while avoiding the addition of reductant or hole scavenger chemicals to accomplish the reaction. However, major challenges for nitrate removal from water via electrochemical conversion involve reducing the use of expensive precious metal electrocatalysts while also improving the reaction activity and selectivity, catalyst stability, and mass transport of nitrate to electrocatalyst active sites. The use of electrochemical membranes as multifunctional porous flow-through electrodes could potentially address these challenges based on improved mass transport and altered kinetics under flow conditions within membrane pores.
 Conductive membranes were fabricated using polymers combined with carbonaceous materials such as reduced graphene oxide (rGO) and carbon nanotubes. The rGO was functionalized with non-precious transition metal oxynitride electrocatalysts, where these catalysts showed higher nitrate conversion activity compared to the unsupported transition metal nitrides. The influence of catalyst materials, membrane fabrication process, and filtration conditions on nitrate reduction activity and selectivity were evaluated. In addition to the environmental impacts of closing the nitrogen loop by converting nitrate into innocuous N2, selective nitrate reduction to ammonia provides opportunities for recovery as fertilizer or carbon-free renewable energy storage. The prospects for reactive nitrogen recovery based on nitrate electrochemical conversion to ammonia were analyzed for various potential source waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bb213e1d183bb4d1cf1ee29e6bc9fde57d9c2d97</guid></item><item><title>Synergistic Nanowire-Enhanced Electroporation and Electrochlorination for Highly Efficient Water Disinfection.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8bb992d82f0964bb99ae53e924322b615916b4dc</link><description>Conventional water disinfection methods such as chlorination typically involve the generation of harmful disinfection byproducts and intensive chemical consumption. Emerging electroporation disinfection techniques using nanowire-enhanced local electric fields inactivate microbes by damaging their outer structures without byproduct formation or chemical dosing. However, this physical-based method suffers from a limited inactivation efficiency under high water flux due to an insufficient contact time. Herein, we integrate electrochlorination with nanowire-enhanced electroporation to achieve a synergistic flow-through process for efficient water disinfection targeting bacteria and viruses. Electroporation at the cathode induces sub-lethal damages on the microbial outer structures. Subsequently, electrogenerated active chlorine at the anode aggravates these electroporation-induced injuries to the level of lethal damage. This sequential flow-through disinfection system achieves complete disinfection (&gt;6.0-log) under a very high water flux of 2.4 × 104 L/(m2 h) with an applied voltage of 2.0 V. This disinfection efficiency is 8 times faster than that of electroporation alone. Further, the specific energy consumption for the disinfection by this novel process is extremely low (8 × 10-4 kW h/m3). Our results demonstrate a promising method for rapid and energy-efficient water disinfection by coupling electroporation with electrochlorination to meet vital needs for pathogen elimination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8bb992d82f0964bb99ae53e924322b615916b4dc</guid></item><item><title>Mining Nontraditional Water Sources for a Distributed Hydrogen Economy</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b764238a1537c78d50546faa886db5ab8ab8d825</link><description>Securing decarbonized economies for energy and commodities will require abundant and widely available green H2. Ubiquitous wastewaters and nontraditional water sources could potentially feed water electrolyzers to produce this green hydrogen without competing with drinking water sources. Herein, we show that the energy and costs of treating nontraditional water sources such as municipal wastewater, industrial and resource extraction wastewater, and seawater are negligible with respect to those for water electrolysis. We also illustrate that the potential hydrogen energy that could be mined from these sources is vast. Based on these findings, we evaluate the implications of small-scale, distributed water electrolysis using disperse nontraditional water sources. Techno-economic analysis and life cycle analysis reveal that the significant contribution of H2 transportation to costs and CO2 emissions results in an optimal levelized cost of hydrogen at small- to moderate-scale water electrolyzer size. The implications of utilizing nontraditional water sources and decentralized or stranded renewable energy for distributed water electrolysis are highlighted for several hydrogen energy storage and chemical feedstock applications. Finally, we discuss challenges and opportunities for mining H2 from nontraditional water sources to achieve resilient and sustainable economies for water and energy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b764238a1537c78d50546faa886db5ab8ab8d825</guid></item><item><title>Ultrahigh resistance of hexagonal boron nitride to mineral scale formation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/32981998c00e12339c76543e6ffc976baeec84b5</link><description>Formation of mineral scale on a material surface has profound impact on a wide range of natural processes as well as industrial applications. However, how specific material surface characteristics affect the mineral-surface interactions and subsequent mineral scale formation is not well understood. Here we report the superior resistance of hexagonal boron nitride (hBN) to mineral scale formation compared to not only common metal and polymer surfaces but also the highly scaling-resistant graphene, making hBN possibly the most scaling resistant material reported to date. Experimental and simulation results reveal that this ultrahigh scaling-resistance is attributed to the combination of hBN’s atomically-smooth surface, in-plane atomic energy corrugation due to the polar boron-nitrogen bond, and the close match between its interatomic spacing and the size of water molecules. The latter two properties lead to strong polar interactions with water and hence the formation of a dense hydration layer, which strongly hinders the approach of mineral ions and crystals, decreasing both surface heterogeneous nucleation and crystal attachment. Scale formation may have detrimental effects on the properties and functions of materials’ surfaces. Here the authors report the high scaling resistance of hexagonal boron nitride and relate it to the atomic level structure and interaction with water molecules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/32981998c00e12339c76543e6ffc976baeec84b5</guid></item><item><title>Denitrification mechanism in oxygen-rich aquatic environments through long-distance electron transfer</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b448ac5d2d64d8b698dc6c8584633799c19462b0</link><description>The lack of electron donors in oxygen-rich aquatic environments limits the ability of natural denitrification to remove excess nitrate, leading to eutrophication of aquatic ecosystems. Herein, we demonstrate that electron-rich substances in river or lake sediments could participate in long-distance electron rebalancing to reduce nitrate in the overlying water. A microstructure containing Dechloromonas and consisting of an inner layer of green rust and an outer layer of lepidocrocite forms in the sediment-water system through synergetic evolution and self-assembly. The microstructure enables long-distance electron transfer from the sediment to dilute nitrate in the overlying water. Specifically, the inner green rust adsorbs nitrate and reduces the kinetic barrier for denitrification via an Fe(II)/Fe(III) redox mediator. Our study reveals the mechanism of spontaneous electron transfer between distant and dilute electron donors and acceptors to achieve denitrification in electron-deficient aquatic systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b448ac5d2d64d8b698dc6c8584633799c19462b0</guid></item><item><title>Efficient electrocatalytic valorization of chlorinated organic water pollutant to ethylene</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/45e74c5a500572151ee4c681938303cf4b2668f7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/45e74c5a500572151ee4c681938303cf4b2668f7</guid></item><item><title>Microalgae Commercialization Using Renewable Lignocellulose Is Economically and Environmentally Viable.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d1d4947c22ef469ca441d46d8ac3c07d6ff728b8</link><description>Conventional phototrophic cultivation for microalgae production suffers from low and unstable biomass productivity due to limited and unreliable light transmission outdoors. Alternatively, the use of a renewable lignocellulose-derived carbon source, cellulosic hydrolysate, offers a cost-effective and sustainable pathway to cultivate microalgae heterotrophically with high algal growth rate and terminal density. In this study, we evaluate the feasibility of cellulosic hydrolysate-mediated heterotrophic cultivation (Cel-HC) for microalgae production by performing economic and environmental comparisons with phototrophic cultivation through techno-economic analysis and life cycle assessment. We estimate a minimum selling price (MSP) of 4722 USD/t for producing high-purity microalgae through Cel-HC considering annual biomass productivity of 300 t (dry weight), which is competitive with the conventional phototrophic raceway pond system. Revenues from the lignocellulose-derived co-products, xylose and fulvic acid fertilizer, could further reduce the MSP to 2976 USD/t, highlighting the advantages of simultaneously producing high-value products and biofuels in an integrated biorefinery scheme. Further, Cel-HC exhibits lower environmental impacts, such as cumulative energy demand and greenhouse gas emissions, than phototrophic systems, revealing its potential to reduce the carbon intensity of algae-derived commodities. Our results demonstrate the economic and environmental competitiveness of heterotrophic microalgae production based on renewable bio-feedstock of lignocellulose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d1d4947c22ef469ca441d46d8ac3c07d6ff728b8</guid></item><item><title>Prospects of metal recovery from wastewater and brine</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e999f29bc52acfb3b86e06f5852acbd230a30a0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e999f29bc52acfb3b86e06f5852acbd230a30a0</guid></item><item><title>Significance of Co-ion Partitioning in Salt Transport through Polyamide Reverse Osmosis Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9791e385ccc7f87dccf7a8234e87b4895bfc5454</link><description>Salt permeability of polyamide reverse osmosis (RO) membranes has been shown to increase with increasing feed salt concentration. The dependence of salt permeability on salt concentration has been attributed to the variation of salt partitioning with feed salt concentration. However, studies using various analytical techniques revealed that the salt (total ion) partitioning coefficient decreases with increasing salt concentration, in marked contrast to the observed increase in salt permeability. Herein, we thoroughly investigate the dependence of total ion and co-ion partitioning coefficients on salt concentration and solution pH. The salt partitioning is measured using a quartz crystal microbalance (QCM), while the co-ion partitioning is calculated from the measured salt partitioning using a modified Donnan theory. Our results demonstrate that the co-ion and total ion partitioning behave entirely differently with increasing salt concentrations. Specifically, the co-ion partitioning increased fourfold, while total ion partitioning decreased by 60% as the salt (NaCl) concentration increased from 100 to 800 mM. The increase in co-ion partitioning with increasing salt concentration is in accordance with the increasing trend of salt permeability in RO experiments. We further show that the dependence of salt and co-ion partitioning on salt concentration is much more pronounced at a higher solution pH. The good co-ion exclusion (GCE) model─derived from the solution-friction model─is used to calculate the salt permeability based on the co-ion partitioning coefficients. Our results show that the GCE model predicts the salt permeabilities in RO experiments relatively well, indicating that co-ion partitioning, not salt partitioning, governs salt transport through RO membranes. Our study provides an in-depth understanding of ion partitioning in polyamide RO membranes and its relationship with salt transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9791e385ccc7f87dccf7a8234e87b4895bfc5454</guid></item><item><title>Performance metrics for nanofiltration-based selective separation for resource extraction and recovery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/857ceecc1a6cfebe0b53ce2e6fde18a0a87bb602</link><description>Membrane filtration has been widely adopted in various water treatment applications, but its use in selective solute separation for resource extraction and recovery is an emerging research area. When a membrane process is applied for solute–solute separation to extract solutes as the product, the performance metrics and process optimization strategies should differ from a membrane process for water production because the separation goals are fundamentally different. Here we used lithium (Li) magnesium (Mg) separation as a representative solute–solute separation to illustrate the deficiency of existing performance evaluation framework developed for water–solute separation using nanofiltration (NF). We performed coupon- and module-scale analyses of mass transfer to elucidate how membrane properties and operating conditions affect the performance of Li/Mg separation in NF. Notably, we identified an important operational trade-off between Li/Mg selectivity and Li recovery, which is critical for process optimization. We also established a new framework for evaluating membrane performance based on the success criteria of Li purity and recovery and further extended this framework to separation with the target ions in the brine. This analysis lays the theoretical foundation for performance evaluation and process optimization for NF-based selective solute separation. Membranes can be used not only for water filtration but also for solute–solute separation. Using the separation between lithium and magnesium, this analysis provides a platform for evaluating the performance of nanofiltration-based selective solute separation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/857ceecc1a6cfebe0b53ce2e6fde18a0a87bb602</guid></item><item><title>Free-standing membrane incorporating single-atom catalysts for ultrafast electroreduction of low-concentration nitrate</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0d646b5b68cc3bfba1dda3033467f71c20c90bc4</link><description>Significance The release of nitrate-containing wastewaters leads to eutrophication of aquatic ecosystems and contamination of drinking water sources. Electrochemical methods for NO3− destruction are limited by expensive materials, by-product ammonia generation, and weak mass transport. Here, we employ an electrified membrane incorporating single-atom catalysts to modify the kinetics and pathways of NO3− reduction. We provide a method for trapping electrocatalysts with specific structure into a carbon nanotube interwoven framework for free-standing membrane fabrication. In addition to intensifying mass transport, electrofiltration enhances adsorption of the intermediate reduction species to the catalysts and improves their interactions with hydrogen species to promote N2 formation. These mechanisms enable orders-of-magnitude enhancement of NO3− reduction rate with superior N2 selectivity without requiring precious metals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0d646b5b68cc3bfba1dda3033467f71c20c90bc4</guid></item><item><title>Electrosorption Integrated with Bipolar Membrane Water Dissociation: A Coupled Approach to Chemical-free Boron Removal.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1402a8988b9c31039e40c40b3fcf7baba756930c</link><description>Boron removal from aqueous solutions has long persisted as a technological challenge, accounting for a disproportionately large fraction of the chemical and energy usage in seawater desalination and other industrial processes like lithium recovery. Here, we introduce a novel electrosorption-based boron removal technology with the capability to overcome the limitations of current state-of-the-art methods. Specifically, we incorporate a bipolar membrane (BPM) between a pair of porous carbon electrodes, demonstrating a synergized BPM-electrosorption process for the first time. The ion transport and charge transfer mechanisms of the BPM-electrosorption system are thoroughly investigated, confirming that water dissociation in the BPM is highly coupled with electrosorption of anions at the anode. We then demonstrate effective boron removal by the BPM-electrosorption system and verify that the mechanism for boron removal is electrosorption, as opposed to adsorption on the carbon electrodes or in the BPM. The effect of applied voltage on the boron removal performance is then evaluated, revealing that applied potentials above ∼1.0 V result in a decline in process efficiency due to the increased prevalence of detrimental Faradaic reactions at the anode. The BPM-electrosorption system is then directly compared with flow-through electrosorption, highlighting key advantages of the process with regard to boron sorption capacity and energy consumption. Overall, the BPM-electrosorption shows promising boron removal capability, with a sorption capacity &gt;4.5 μmol g-C-1 and a corresponding specific energy consumption of &lt;2.5 kWh g-B-1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1402a8988b9c31039e40c40b3fcf7baba756930c</guid></item><item><title>Fluids and Electrolytes under Confinement in Single-Digit Nanopores</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2be93336f45a8acaa4f61aaa06ebae1886c74ef</link><description>Confined fluids and electrolyte solutions in nanopores exhibit rich and surprising physics and chemistry that impact the mass transport and energy efficiency in many important natural systems and industrial applications. Existing theories often fail to predict the exotic effects observed in the narrowest of such pores, called single-digit nanopores (SDNs), which have diameters or conduit widths of less than 10 nm, and have only recently become accessible for experimental measurements. What SDNs reveal has been surprising, including a rapidly increasing number of examples such as extraordinarily fast water transport, distorted fluid-phase boundaries, strong ion-correlation and quantum effects, and dielectric anomalies that are not observed in larger pores. Exploiting these effects presents myriad opportunities in both basic and applied research that stand to impact a host of new technologies at the water–energy nexus, from new membranes for precise separations and water purification to new gas permeable materials for water electrolyzers and energy-storage devices. SDNs also present unique opportunities to achieve ultrasensitive and selective chemical sensing at the single-ion and single-molecule limit. In this review article, we summarize the progress on nanofluidics of SDNs, with a focus on the confinement effects that arise in these extremely narrow nanopores. The recent development of precision model systems, transformative experimental tools, and multiscale theories that have played enabling roles in advancing this frontier are reviewed. We also identify new knowledge gaps in our understanding of nanofluidic transport and provide an outlook for the future challenges and opportunities at this rapidly advancing frontier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2be93336f45a8acaa4f61aaa06ebae1886c74ef</guid></item><item><title>Influence of Graphite Geography on the Yield of Mechanically Exfoliated Few-Layer Graphene</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e1336535363314bb2ba2939317f58bf75d4bc136</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e1336535363314bb2ba2939317f58bf75d4bc136</guid></item><item><title>Water transport in reverse osmosis membranes is governed by pore flow, not a solution-diffusion mechanism</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9e221e77f9872af5811f49ca1ec61ec3b580ccea</link><description>We performed nonequilibrium molecular dynamics (NEMD) simulations and solvent permeation experiments to unravel the mechanism of water transport in reverse osmosis (RO) membranes. The NEMD simulations reveal that water transport is driven by a pressure gradient within the membranes, not by a water concentration gradient, in marked contrast to the classic solution-diffusion model. We further show that water molecules travel as clusters through a network of pores that are transiently connected. Permeation experiments with water and organic solvents using polyamide and cellulose triacetate RO membranes showed that solvent permeance depends on the membrane pore size, kinetic diameter of solvent molecules, and solvent viscosity. This observation is not consistent with the solution-diffusion model, where permeance depends on the solvent solubility. Motivated by these observations, we demonstrate that the solution-friction model, in which transport is driven by a pressure gradient, can describe water and solvent transport in RO membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9e221e77f9872af5811f49ca1ec61ec3b580ccea</guid></item><item><title>A mechanistic model for salt and water transport in leaky membranes: Implications for low-salt-rejection reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6db2d793f110540e67fc6a51b4b66e0345b6c55d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6db2d793f110540e67fc6a51b4b66e0345b6c55d</guid></item><item><title>Precise Cation Separations with Composite Cation-Exchange Membranes: Role of Base Layer Properties.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9d24e894f7254286f5d0aa49e33378b43dfc0407</link><description>Separation of specific ions from water could enable recovery and reuse of essential metals and nutrients, but established membrane technologies lack the high-precision selectivity needed to facilitate a circular resource economy. In this work, we investigate whether the cation/cation selectivity of a composite cation-exchange membrane (CEM), or a thin polymer selective layer on top of a CEM, may be limited by the mass transfer resistance of the underlying CEM. In our analysis, we utilize a layer-by-layer technique to modify CEMs with a thin polymer selective layer (∼50 nm) that has previously shown high selectivity toward copper over similarly sized metals. While these composite membranes have a CuCl2/MgCl2 selectivity up to 33 times larger than unmodified CEMs in diffusion dialysis, our estimates suggest that eliminating resistance from the underlying CEM could further increase selectivity twofold. In contrast, the CEM base layer has a smaller effect on the selectivity of these composite membranes in electrodialysis, although these effects could become more pronounced for ultrathin or highly conductive selective layers. Our results highlight that base layer resistance prevents selectivity factors from being comparable across diffusion dialysis and electrodialysis, and CEMs with low resistance are necessary for providing highly precise separations with composite CEMs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9d24e894f7254286f5d0aa49e33378b43dfc0407</guid></item><item><title>Subtle tuning of nanodefects actuates highly efficient electrocatalytic oxidation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/64c5fdda9a93f19dbc0cbffc6f341ae2b560d573</link><description>Achieving controllable fine-tuning of defects in catalysts at the atomic level has become a zealous pursuit in catalysis-related fields. However, the generation of defects is quite random, and their flexible manipulation lacks theoretical basis. Herein, we present a facile and highly controllable thermal tuning strategy that enables fine control of nanodefects via subtle manipulation of atomic/lattice arrangements in electrocatalysts. Such thermal tuning endows common carbon materials with record high efficiency in electrocatalytic degradation of pollutants. Systematic characterization and calculations demonstrate that an optimal thermal tuning can bring about enhanced electrocatalytic efficiency by manipulating the N-centered annulation–volatilization reactions and C-based sp ^3/ sp ^2 configuration alteration. Benefiting from this tuning strategy, the optimized electrocatalytic anodic membrane successfully achieves &gt;99% pollutant (propranolol) degradation during a flow-through (~2.5 s for contact time), high-flux (424.5 L m^−2 h^−1), and long-term (&gt;720 min) electrocatalytic filtration test at a very low energy consumption (0.029 ± 0.010 kWh m^−3 order^−1). Our findings highlight a controllable preparation approach of catalysts while also elucidating the molecular level mechanisms involved. Achieving controllable fine-tuning of defects is desired for electrocatalysts. Here, the authors present a facile and controllable thermal tuning strategy that enables fine control of nanodefects, thereby endowing common carbon materials with high electrocatalytic oxidation efficiency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/64c5fdda9a93f19dbc0cbffc6f341ae2b560d573</guid></item><item><title>Regulation of molecular transport in polymer membranes with voltage-controlled pore size at the angstrom scale</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/65345bf037556a77daf62beb841109c053d067a6</link><description>Polymer membranes have been used extensively for Angstrom-scale separation of solutes and molecules. However, the pore size of most polymer membranes has been considered an intrinsic membrane property that cannot be adjusted in operation by applied stimuli. In this work, we show that the pore size of an electrically conductive polyamide membrane can be modulated by an applied voltage in the presence of electrolyte via a mechanism called electrically induced osmotic swelling. Under applied voltage, the highly charged polyamide layer concentrates counter ions in the polymer network via Donnan equilibrium and creates a sizeable osmotic pressure to enlarge the free volume and the effective pore size. The relation between membrane potential and pore size can be quantitatively described using the extended Flory-Rehner theory with Donnan equilibrium. The ability to regulate pore size via applied voltage enables operando modulation of precise molecular separation in-situ. This study demonstrates the amazing capability of electro-regulation of membrane pore size at the Angstrom scale and unveils an important but previously overlooked mechanism of membrane-water-solute interactions. The ability to regulate membrane pore size as needed has been a topic of active research for developing next-generation stimuli-responsive smart membranes. Herein, the authors report the observation of operando regulation of the pore size of A membrane based on electro-osmotic swelling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/65345bf037556a77daf62beb841109c053d067a6</guid></item><item><title>Microstructure optimization of bioderived polyester nanofilms for antibiotic desalination via nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/36bb9cc66ecebbef1bdbb4322554b44e186e1833</link><description>The successful implementation of thin-film composite membranes (TFCM) for challenging solute-solute separations in the pharmaceutical industry requires a fine control over the microstructure (size, distribution, and connectivity of the free-volume elements) and thickness of the selective layer. For example, desalinating antibiotic streams requires highly interconnected free-volume elements of the right size to block antibiotics but allow the passage of salt ions and water. Here, we introduce stevioside, a plant-derived contorted glycoside, as a promising aqueous phase monomer for optimizing the microstructure of TFCM made via interfacial polymerization. The low diffusion rate and moderate reactivity of stevioside, together with its nonplanar and distorted conformation, produced thin selective layers with an ideal microporosity for antibiotic desalination. For example, an optimized 18-nm membrane exhibited an unprecedented combination of high water permeance (81.2 liter m−2 hour−1 bar−1), antibiotic desalination efficiency (NaCl/tetracycline separation factor of 11.4), antifouling performance, and chlorine resistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/36bb9cc66ecebbef1bdbb4322554b44e186e1833</guid></item><item><title>Distinguishing homogeneous advanced oxidation processes in bulk water from heterogeneous surface reactions in organic oxidation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/339e54eca327bdeb54b0abfb1e198ba56b239aa7</link><description>Significance Heterogeneous catalytic oxidation technologies for water purification, such as Fenton and Fenton-like catalytic oxidation, involve intricate interfacial reactions at the solid catalyst surface and in bulk solution. To date, the difference in the reaction pathways on the catalyst surface and in bulk water solution has not been recognized. In this work, we reveal a widespread surface-dependent reaction pathway that is fundamentally different from the previously accepted pathway. We further elucidate the changes in reaction pathways as oxidizing species (e.g., Mn(III), •OH) detach from the catalyst surface to the aqueous solution. Our study provides new insights on heterogeneous chemical oxidation and catalytic oxidation reactions, potentially leading to the design of more efficient nanocatalysts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/339e54eca327bdeb54b0abfb1e198ba56b239aa7</guid></item><item><title>Electrified water treatment: fundamentals and roles of electrode materials</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1be7d63aac021ee2e98df86abfbaf8cd5f962f9f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1be7d63aac021ee2e98df86abfbaf8cd5f962f9f</guid></item><item><title>Origin of Limiting and Overlimiting Currents in Bipolar Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b1842b4c8ce9f8d849a3c01aa666c7621f2f4577</link><description>Bipolar membranes (BPMs), a special class of ion exchange membranes with the unique ability to electrochemically induce either water dissociation or recombination, are of growing interest for environmental applications including eliminating chemical dosage for pH adjustment, resource recovery, valorization of brines, and carbon capture. However, ion transport within BPMs, and particularly at its junction, has remained poorly understood. This work aims to theoretically and experimentally investigate ion transport in BPMs under both reverse and forward bias operation modes, taking into account the production or recombination of H+ and OH–, as well as the transport of salt ions (e.g., Na+, Cl–) inside the membrane. We adopt a model based on the Nernst–Planck theory, that requires only three input parameters—membrane thickness, its charge density, and pK of proton adsorption—to predict the concentration profiles of four ions (H+, OH–, Na+, and Cl–) inside the membrane and the resulting current–voltage curve. The model can predict most of the experimental results measured with a commercial BPM, including the observation of limiting and overlimiting currents, which emerge due to particular concentration profiles that develop inside the BPM. This work provides new insights into the physical phenomena in BPMs and helps identify optimal operating conditions for future environmental applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b1842b4c8ce9f8d849a3c01aa666c7621f2f4577</guid></item><item><title>Theory for Salt Transport in Charged Reverse Osmosis Membranes: Novel Analytical Equations for Desalination Performance and Experimental Validation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/48909f73f0f67134e112f9fbe698d23bfde69715</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/48909f73f0f67134e112f9fbe698d23bfde69715</guid></item><item><title>Nanofiltration for circularity: Fit-for-purpose design and evaluation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1745416da5ec74a879e9067a740386aaf942695d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1745416da5ec74a879e9067a740386aaf942695d</guid></item><item><title>Theory of expansion and compression of polymeric materials</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cbfb34aaa2be9ec18f27afbebd3041f9a1516c8c</link><description>We extend classical Flory-Rehner theory for the expansion and compression of porous materials such as cross-linked polymer networks. The theory includes volume exclusion, affinity with the solvent, and finite stretching of the polymer chains. We also modify this equilibrium theory -- that applies to equal expansion of a material in all directions -- to the situation that a material can only expand in a single direction, as is the case when a thin layer is tightly bound to a support structure. We extend this equilibrium model to the case that a pressure is applied across such a thin layer of the polymer material, for instance a membrane, and liquid flows across this layer. The theory describes how in the direction of liquid flow the membrane is increasingly compacted (becomes less porous), and the more so at higher applied pressures. We provide results of example calculations for a thick membrane with significant changes in compaction across its thickness, and a thin membrane for which compaction due to flow is minor. In the last section we model the dynamics of the change of size of a porous material in time after a step change in the solvent-polymer attraction parameter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cbfb34aaa2be9ec18f27afbebd3041f9a1516c8c</guid></item><item><title>Electrochemical chromium removal using nanodiamond enhanced flow-through electrosorption</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/517a125c5dfd0a4468e17f0c41106d72480c4635</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/517a125c5dfd0a4468e17f0c41106d72480c4635</guid></item><item><title>General validity of the exponential law for the effect of concentration polarization in reverse osmosis in a stirred-cell geometry, including an activity correction for 1:1 salt solutions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ef6b7d736fbcfd6012e55dd54fa722f17d419d5f</link><description>Reverse osmosis (RO) is a method to desalinate water with membranes and an applied pressure. Very important in the theory of mass transport in RO is the concentration polarization (CP) layer, which develops on the upstream side of the membrane because of a combination of salt convection and diffusion. Because of the CP-effect, the salt concentration at the membrane surface is higher than in the channel, and this increases the osmotic pressure there, and thus transmembrane water flux is reduced (the osmotic pressure acts against water flux), while salt leakage through the membrane increases. So it is very important to understand and describe the CP-layer accurately. We analyze a one-dimensional geometry, which is of relevance for a typical lab-scale RO setup using small membrane coupons where the solution on the feed side of the membrane is stirred. For this geometry, the standard film layer approach is often used that assumes a stagnant film layer of a defined thickness, which however does not exist in reality. We set up a model without that assumption but including refreshment of solution because of the flow of water along the membrane due to stirring. We show that the `exponential law' for the CP-layer that is predicted by the the film model, also applies for this more accurate model. We further improve the model by including the activity coefficient of salt ions, as described by the Bjerrum theory that is based on ion-ion Coulombic interactions. We evaluate the original linearized Bjerrum theory as well as an extended Bjerrum equation that is valid up to 1.5 M salt concentration. We show how including this activity correction leads to a reduction of the diffusional driving force at high concentration, and thus the salt concentration at the membrane further increases. However, the effect can be easily included by reducing the CP-layer mass transfer coefficient by a fixed percentage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ef6b7d736fbcfd6012e55dd54fa722f17d419d5f</guid></item><item><title>Author Correction: Performance metrics for nanofiltration-based selective separation for resource extraction and recovery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0bb89c24a3ead621cb03d552f0aad593630a5b43</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0bb89c24a3ead621cb03d552f0aad593630a5b43</guid></item><item><title>Mechanisms and models for water transport in reverse osmosis membranes: history, critical assessment, and recent developments.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e8c584b2ca83029f0912ccec19f008f23bf909f8</link><description>Water scarcity is one of the greatest societal challenges facing humanity. Reverse osmosis (RO) desalination, a widely used membrane-based technology, has proven to be effective to augment water supply in water-stressed regions of our planet. However, progress in the design and development of RO membranes has been limited. To significantly enhance the performance of RO membranes, it is essential to acquire a deep understanding of the membrane separation and transport mechanisms. In this tutorial review, we cover the pivotal historical developments in RO technology, examine the chemical and physical properties of RO membrane materials, and critically review the models and mechanisms proposed for water transport in RO membranes. Based on recent experimental and computational findings, we conduct a thorough analysis of the key transport models-the solution-diffusion and pore-flow models-to assess their validity for accurately describing water transport in RO membranes. Our analysis involves examining the experimental evidence in favor of the solution-diffusion mechanism. Specifically, we explain whether the water content gradient within the membrane, cited as evidence for the key assumption in the solution-diffusion model, can drive a diffusive transport through RO membranes. Additionally, we review the recent molecular dynamics simulations which support the pore-flow mechanism for describing water transport in RO membranes. We conclude by providing future research directions aimed at addressing key knowledge gaps in water transport phenomena in RO membranes, with the goal of advancing the development of next-generation RO membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e8c584b2ca83029f0912ccec19f008f23bf909f8</guid></item><item><title>Orientation matters: Measuring the correct surface of polyamide membranes with quartz crystal microbalance</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0618f9ced1dde32bbbe91455293eb4508ba2780c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0618f9ced1dde32bbbe91455293eb4508ba2780c</guid></item><item><title>Ceramic thin-film composite membranes with tunable subnanometer pores for molecular sieving</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/31536ea9be73c25a28fdae784adca01afb9eccb4</link><description>Ceramic membranes are a promising alternative to polymeric membranes for selective separations, given their ability to operate under harsh chemical conditions. However, current fabrication technologies fail to construct ceramic membranes suitable for selective molecular separations. Herein, we demonstrate a molecular-level design of ceramic thin-film composite membranes with tunable subnanometer pores for precise molecular sieving. Through burning off the distributed carbonaceous species of varied dimensions within hybrid aluminum oxide films, we created membranes with tunable molecular sieving. Specifically, the membranes created with methanol showed exceptional selectivity toward monovalent and divalent salts. We attribute this observed selectivity to the dehydration of the large divalent ions within the subnanometer pores. As a comparison, smaller monovalent ions can rapidly permeate with an intact hydration shell. Lastly, the flux of neutral solutes through each fabricated aluminum oxide membrane was measured for the demonstration of tunable separation capability. Overall, our work provides the scientific basis for the design of ceramic membranes with subnanometer pores for molecular sieving using atomic layer deposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/31536ea9be73c25a28fdae784adca01afb9eccb4</guid></item><item><title>The potential of electrodialysis as a cost-effective alternative to reverse osmosis for brackish water desalination.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8db22ad5082f449194246813da39f6bde5d859f4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8db22ad5082f449194246813da39f6bde5d859f4</guid></item><item><title>The Future of Municipal Wastewater Reuse Concentrate Management: Drivers, Challenges, and Opportunities</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6a62d2eddbb62e0e7ad754c56d919ed854db49a9</link><description>Water reuse is rapidly becoming an integral feature of resilient water systems, where municipal wastewater undergoes advanced treatment, typically involving a sequence of ultrafiltration (UF), reverse osmosis (RO), and an advanced oxidation process (AOP). When RO is used, a concentrated waste stream is produced that is elevated in not only total dissolved solids but also metals, nutrients, and micropollutants that have passed through conventional wastewater treatment. Management of this RO concentrate—dubbed municipal wastewater reuse concentrate (MWRC)—will be critical to address, especially as water reuse practices become more widespread. Building on existing brine management practices, this review explores MWRC management options by identifying infrastructural needs and opportunities for multi-beneficial disposal. To safeguard environmental systems from the potential hazards of MWRC, disposal, monitoring, and regulatory techniques are discussed to promote the safety and affordability of implementing MWRC management. Furthermore, opportunities for resource recovery and valorization are differentiated, while economic techniques to revamp cost-benefit analysis for MWRC management are examined. The goal of this critical review is to create a common foundation for researchers, practitioners, and regulators by providing an interdisciplinary set of tools and frameworks to address the impending challenges and emerging opportunities of MWRC management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6a62d2eddbb62e0e7ad754c56d919ed854db49a9</guid></item><item><title>Molecular Design of Functional Polymers for Silica Scale Inhibition.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/77fc1ae5f425bc68b379525677fb6fb7fc8ef2e9</link><description>Silica polymerization, which involves the condensation reaction of silicic acid, is a fundamental process with wide-ranging implications in biological systems, material synthesis, and scale formation. The formation of a silica-based scale poses significant technological challenges to energy-efficient operations in various industrial processes, including heat exchangers and water treatment membranes. Despite the common strategy of applying functional polymers for inhibiting silica polymerization, the underlying mechanisms of inhibition remain elusive. In this study, we synthesized a series of nitrogen-containing polymers as silica inhibitors and elucidated the role of their molecular structures in stabilizing silicic acids. Polymers with both charged amine and uncharged amide groups in their backbones exhibit superior inhibition performance, retaining up to 430 ppm of reactive silica intact for 8 h under neutral pH conditions. In contrast, monomers of these amine/amide-containing polymers as well as polymers containing only amine or amide functionalities present insignificant inhibition. Molecular dynamics simulations reveal strong binding between the deprotonated silicic acid and a polymer when the amine groups in the polymer are protonated. Notably, an extended chain conformation of the polymer is crucial to prevent proximity between the interacting monomeric silica species, thereby facilitating effective silica inhibition. Furthermore, the hydrophobic nature of alkyl segments in polymer chains disrupts the hydration shell around the polymer, resulting in enhanced binding with ionized silicic acid precursors compared to monomers. Our findings provide novel mechanistic insights into the stabilization of silicic acids with functional polymers, highlighting the molecular design principles of effective inhibitors for silica polymerization.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/77fc1ae5f425bc68b379525677fb6fb7fc8ef2e9</guid></item><item><title>Rapid, Selective, and Chemical-Free Removal of Dissolved Silica from Water via Electrosorption: Feasibility and Mechanisms.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/53ed41a2a6aa76e787110ba9a5c6fa9c0ef009ba</link><description>The unavoidable and detrimental formation of silica scale in engineered processes necessitates the urgent development of effective, economic, and sustainable strategies for dissolved silica removal from water. Herein, we demonstrate a rapid, chemical-free, and selective silica removal method using electrosorption. Specifically, we confirm the feasibility of exploiting local pH dynamics at the electrodes in flow-through electrosorption, achieved through a counterintuitive cell configuration design, to induce ionization and concomitant electrosorption of dissolved silica. In addition, to improve the feasibility of silica electrosorption under high-salinity solutions, we developed a silica-selective anode by functionalizing porous activated carbon cloths with aluminum hydroxide nanoparticles (Al(OH)3-p-ACC). The modification markedly enhances silica sorption capacity (2.8 vs 1.1 mgsilica ganode-1) and reduces the specific energy consumption (13.3 vs 19.8 kWh kgsilica-1). Notably, the modified electrode retains remarkable silica sorption capacity even in the presence of high concentrations of co-occurring ions (up to 100 mM NaCl). The mechanisms underlying the superior silica removal stability and selectivity with the Al(OH)3-p-ACC electrode are also elucidated, revealing a synergistic interaction involving outer-sphere and inner-sphere complexation between dissolved silica and Al(OH)3 nanoparticles on the electrodes. Moreover, we find that effective regeneration of the electrodes may be achieved by applying a reverse potential during discharge, although complete regeneration of the modified electrodes may necessitate alternative materials or process optimization. We recommend the adoption of feedwater-specific designs for the development of future silica-selective electrodes in electrosorption capable of meeting silica removal demands across a wide range of engineered systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/53ed41a2a6aa76e787110ba9a5c6fa9c0ef009ba</guid></item><item><title>Transforming membrane distillation to a membraneless fabric distillation for desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8ef23231cad302ea04e7297c44d0fbcb460ffb3e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8ef23231cad302ea04e7297c44d0fbcb460ffb3e</guid></item><item><title>Salinity gradient energy is not a competitive source of renewable energy</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/038aa28488b266ec2c1a958af00d701a4fa198af</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/038aa28488b266ec2c1a958af00d701a4fa198af</guid></item><item><title>Correction to “Mining Nontraditional Water Sources for a Distributed Hydrogen Economy”</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0d6ad890b33fc39f6896b17d955bfba38b4aa776</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0d6ad890b33fc39f6896b17d955bfba38b4aa776</guid></item><item><title>Integrating Divalent-Selective Electrodialysis in Brackish Water Desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f93b0563a1e4ca8855deb8fb62624543eab5e1bc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f93b0563a1e4ca8855deb8fb62624543eab5e1bc</guid></item><item><title>Tailoring Interfaces for Enhanced Methanol Production from Photoelectrochemical CO2 Reduction.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73b634ca3189e077aeeb39e71d18a6c65a756e4d</link><description>Efficient and stable photoelectrochemical reduction of CO2 into highly reduced liquid fuels remains a formidable challenge, which requires an innovative semiconductor/catalyst interface to tackle. In this study, we introduce a strategy involving the fabrication of a silicon micropillar array structure coated with a superhydrophobic fluorinated carbon layer for the photoelectrochemical conversion of CO2 into methanol. The pillars increase the electrode surface area, improve catalyst loading and adhesion without compromising light absorption, and help confine gaseous intermediates near the catalyst surface. The superhydrophobic coating passivates parasitic side reactions and further enhances local accumulation of reaction intermediates. Upon one-electron reduction of the molecular catalyst, the semiconductor-catalyst interface changes from adaptive to buried junctions, providing a sufficient thermodynamic driving force for CO2 reduction. These structures together create a unique microenvironment for effective reduction of CO2 to methanol, leading to a remarkable Faradaic efficiency reaching 20% together with a partial current density of 3.4 mA cm-2, surpassing the previous record based on planar silicon photoelectrodes by a notable factor of 17. This work demonstrates a new pathway for enhancing photoelectrocatalytic CO2 reduction through meticulous interface and microenvironment tailoring and sets a benchmark for both Faradaic efficiency and current density in solar liquid fuel production.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73b634ca3189e077aeeb39e71d18a6c65a756e4d</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of concentration polarization in reverse osmosis and nanofiltration: zero-, one-, and two-dimensional models</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/485f6db63d2c09a71708bfffa49fed37dae8fc1f</link><description>Reverse osmosis and nanofiltration are membrane-based methods that remove solutes from solvent, for instance they remove salts from water (desalination). In these methods, an applied pressure is the driving force for solvent to pass the membrane, while most of the solutes are blocked. Very important in the theory of mass transport is the concentration polarization layer (CP layer), which develops on the upstream side of the membrane. Because of the CP layer, the solvent flux through the membrane is reduced while leakage of solutes through the membrane increases, and both these effects must be minimized. So it is very important to understand and describe the nature of the CP layer accurately, especially to find a good estimate of the CP layer mass transfer coefficient, $k$. This is also important for the accurate characterization of membranes in a test cell geometry. We theoretically analyze the structure of the CP layer using three levels of mathematical models. First, we present a modification of an equation for $k$ by Sherwood et al. (1965) and show that it works very well in a zero dimensional model. Second, we evaluate a one-dimensional model that is more accurate, which can incorporate any equation for the flow of solvent and solutes through the membrane, and which also makes use of the new modified Sherwood equation. Finally, we fully resolve the complete channel in a two-dimensional geometry, to validate the lower-order models and to illustrate the structure of the CP layer. The overall conclusion is that for typical test cell conditions, the modified Sherwood equation can be used to characterize the CP layer, also when solvent flux through the membrane changes between inlet and outlet of the test cell. Furthermore, the one-dimensional model accurately describes solute removal (for instance water desalination) not just in a short test cell but also in a longer module.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/485f6db63d2c09a71708bfffa49fed37dae8fc1f</guid></item><item><title>Roll-to-roll fabrication of large-area metal–organic framework-based membranes for high-performance aqueous separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6b15bfa960db65d5ccc25796e6d70e6e987c7739</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6b15bfa960db65d5ccc25796e6d70e6e987c7739</guid></item><item><title>Pressure-driven membrane desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b473b4a7ac4fcd80cec4adaa85ff927f1cfa5141</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b473b4a7ac4fcd80cec4adaa85ff927f1cfa5141</guid></item><item><title>Revolutionizing Airborne Virus Defense: Electromagnetic MXene-Coated Air Filtration for Superior Aerosol Viral Removal.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8f37f6a444ecb94a666ba76c3faec23b4edb7fc2</link><description>The COVID-19 pandemic sparked public health concerns about the transmission of airborne viruses. Current methods mainly capture pathogens without inactivation, leading to potential secondary pollution. Herein, we evaluated the inactivation performance of a model viral species (MS2) in simulated bioaerosol by an electromagnetically enhanced air filtration system under a 300 kHz electromagnetic induction field. A nonwoven fabric filter was coated with a 2D catalyst, MXene (Ti3C2Tx), at a coating density of 4.56 mg·cm-2 to absorb electromagnetic irradiation and produce local heating and electromagnetic field for microbial inactivation. The results showed that the MXene-coated air filter significantly enhanced the viral removal efficiency by achieving a log removal of 3.4 ± 0.15 under an electromagnetic power density of 369 W·cm-2. By contrast, the pristine filter without catalyst coating only garnered a log removal of 0.3 ± 0.04. Though the primary antimicrobial mechanism is the local heating as indicated by the elevated surface temperature of 72.2 ± 4 °C under the electromagnetic field, additional nonthermal effects (e.g., dielectrophoresis) on enhanced viral capture during electromagnetically enhanced filtration were investigated by COMSOL simulation to delineate the potential transmission trajectories of bioaerosol. The results provide unique insights into the mechanisms of pathogen control and thus promote alternative solutions for preventing the transmission of airborne pathogens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8f37f6a444ecb94a666ba76c3faec23b4edb7fc2</guid></item><item><title>Heat diffusion during thin-film composite membrane formation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ce579ee8593a1370ed22eb3f5cb3afce907cbe71</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ce579ee8593a1370ed22eb3f5cb3afce907cbe71</guid></item><item><title>Towards a molecular-scale theory for the removal of natural organic matter by coagulation with trivalent metals</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c1263d95ed68182e9a6e64369b45f65b33fd49f3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c1263d95ed68182e9a6e64369b45f65b33fd49f3</guid></item><item><title>Theory of expansion and compression of polymeric materials: Implications for membrane solvent flow under compaction</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b462aa9ac775856d6a9fa9815ffa8944377848fb</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b462aa9ac775856d6a9fa9815ffa8944377848fb</guid></item><item><title>The solution-diffusion model for water transport in reverse osmosis: What went wrong?</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/915ae862380df5aae91a180686cf333094e9b455</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/915ae862380df5aae91a180686cf333094e9b455</guid></item><item><title>Ultrastable ceramic-based metal–organic framework membranes with missing linkers for robust desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7ca9d40ea9de365eb179ee629a5546d0678c79a9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7ca9d40ea9de365eb179ee629a5546d0678c79a9</guid></item><item><title>Intensifying electrified flow-through water treatment technologies via local environment modification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e05eee60baf52e323900309ea16a3d527d632420</link><description>Removing high-risk and persistent contaminants from water is challenging, because they typically exist at low concentrations in complex water matrices. Electrified flow-through technologies are viable to overcome the limitations induced by mass transport for efficient contaminant removal. Modifying the local environment of the flow-through electrodes offers opportunities to further improve the reaction kinetics and selectivity for achieving near-complete removal of these contaminants from water. Here, we present state-of-the-art local environment modification approaches that can be incorporated into electrified flow-through technologies to intensify water treatment. We first show methods of nanospace incorporation, local geometry adjustment, and microporous structure optimization that can induce spatial confinement, enhanced local electric field, and microperiodic vortex, respectively, for local environment modification. We then discuss why local environment modification can complement the flow-through electrodes for improving the reaction rate and selectivity. Finally, we outline appropriate scenarios of intensifying electrified flow-through technologies through local environment modification for fit-for-purpose water treatment applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e05eee60baf52e323900309ea16a3d527d632420</guid></item><item><title>More resilient polyester membranes for high-performance reverse osmosis desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a0926674de0d735d8e4d4cfc148b840a7ce773f9</link><description>Thin-film composite reverse osmosis membranes have remained the gold standard technology for desalination and water purification for nearly half a century. Polyamide films offer excellent water permeability and salt rejection but also suffer from poor chlorine resistance, high fouling propensity, and low boron rejection. We addressed these issues by molecularly designing a polyester thin-film composite reverse osmosis membrane using co-solvent–assisted interfacial polymerization to react 3,5-dihydroxy-4-methylbenzoic acid with trimesoyl chloride. This polyester membrane exhibits substantial water permeability, high rejection for sodium chloride and boron, and complete resistance toward chlorine. The ultrasmooth, low-energy surface of the membrane also prevents fouling and mineral scaling compared with polyamide membranes. These membranes could increasingly challenge polyamide membranes by further optimizing water-salt selectivity, offering a path to considerably reducing pretreatment steps in desalination. Editor’s summary Reverse osmosis membranes have been dominated by polyamide chemistry, which has sufficient performance in terms of water permeability and salt rejection but is vulnerable to degradation in the presence of chlorine or other strong oxidants. Polyesters are not typically used for water filtration membranes because they suffer from hydrolytic degradation when immersed in aqueous solution. Yao et al. show that the polymerization of 3,5-dihydroxy-4-methylbenzoic acid with trimesoyl chloride yields a polymer membrane with impressive resistance to hydrolytic degradation in acidic or basic conditions (up to pH 9) and a complete resistance to chlorine. —Marc S. Lavine</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a0926674de0d735d8e4d4cfc148b840a7ce773f9</guid></item><item><title>Polyamide Reverse Osmosis Membrane Compaction and Relaxation: Mechanisms and Implications for Desalination Performance</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ceea3e8bb0c84099aafc5c9ac009f5c0cb0a8751</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ceea3e8bb0c84099aafc5c9ac009f5c0cb0a8751</guid></item><item><title>Inhibition of silica scaling with functional polymers: Role of ionic strength, divalent ions, and temperature.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b44fe6a3244afc4aeb9c96cf8406fb8f3c164541</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b44fe6a3244afc4aeb9c96cf8406fb8f3c164541</guid></item><item><title>The physical basis for solvent flow in organic solvent nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b22a6c28111843850edb1ef9ded77f143e8547e</link><description>Organic solvent nanofiltration (OSN) is an emerging membrane technology that could revolutionize chemical separations in numerous vital industries. Despite its significance, there remains a lack of fundamental understanding of solvent transport mechanisms in OSN membranes. Here, we use an extended Flory-Rehner theory, nonequilibrium molecular dynamic simulations, and organic solvent transport experiments to demonstrate that solvent flow in OSN membranes is driven by a pressure gradient. We show that solvent molecules migrate as clusters through interconnected pathways within the membrane pore structure, challenging the widely accepted diffusion-based view of solvent transport in OSN. We further reveal that solvent permeance is dependent on solvent affinity to the OSN membrane, which, in turn, controls the membrane pore structure. Our fundamental insights lay the scientific groundwork for the development of next-generation OSN membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8b22a6c28111843850edb1ef9ded77f143e8547e</guid></item><item><title>Scalable weaving of resilient membranes with on-demand superwettability for high-performance nanoemulsion separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/17888538989d9005e88b7d10abb59794f3188883</link><description>This study leverages the ancient craft of weaving to prepare membranes that can effectively treat oil/water mixtures, specifically challenging nanoemulsions. Drawing inspiration from the core-shell architecture of spider silk, we have engineered fibers, the fundamental building blocks for weaving membranes, that feature a mechanically robust core for tight weaving, coupled with a CO2-responsive shell that allows for on-demand wettability adjustments. Tightly weaving these fibers produces membranes with ideal pores, achieving over 99.6% separation efficiency for nanoemulsions with droplets as small as 20 nm. They offer high flux rates, on-demand self-cleaning, and can switch between sieving oil and water nanodroplets through simple CO2/N2 stimulation. Moreover, weaving can produce sufficiently large membranes (4800 cm2) to assemble a module that exhibits long-term stability and performance, surpassing state-of-the-art technologies for nanoemulsion separations, thus making industrial application a practical reality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/17888538989d9005e88b7d10abb59794f3188883</guid></item><item><title>Hyping direct seawater electrolysis hinders electrolyzer development</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/14b933c528168e4c6932f710f569003c503dec84</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/14b933c528168e4c6932f710f569003c503dec84</guid></item><item><title>Trends, risks and opportunities in environmental nanotechnology</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/799fe26b7cae34be7e0f4c00094d814d69f15926</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/799fe26b7cae34be7e0f4c00094d814d69f15926</guid></item><item><title>Depolymerization mechanisms and closed-loop assessment in polyester waste recycling</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/363ef0699b261711eb338df91aee7b0a7f737c1a</link><description>Alcoholysis of poly(ethylene terephthalate) (PET) waste to produce monomers, including methanolysis to yield dimethyl terephthalate (DMT) and glycolysis to generate bis-2-hydroxyethyl terephthalate (BHET), is a promising strategy in PET waste management. Here, we introduce an efficient PET-alcoholysis approach utilizing an oxygen-vacancy (Vo)-rich catalyst under air, achieving space time yield (STY) of 505.2 gDMT·gcat−1·h−1 and 957.1 gBHET·gcat−1·h−1, these results represent 51-fold and 28-fold performance enhancements compared to reactions conducted under N2. In situ spectroscopy, in combination with density functional theory calculations, elucidates the reaction pathways of PET depolymerization. The process involves O2-assisted activation of CH3OH to form CH3OH* and OOH* species at Vo-Zn2+–O–Fe3+ sites, highlighting the critical role of Vo-Zn2+–O–Fe3+ sites in ester bond activation and C–O bond cleavage. Moreover, a life cycle assessment demonstrates the viability of our approach in closed-loop recycling, achieving 56.0% energy savings and 44.5% reduction in greenhouse-gas emissions. Notably, utilizing PET textile scrap further leads to 58.4% reduction in initial total operating costs. This research offers a sustainable solution to the challenge of PET waste accumulation. Polyester waste is increasingly accumulating in the environment, and alcoholysis recycling offers a sustainable management solution. This study demonstrates the use of an oxygen vacancy-rich catalyst to transform waste blended polyester/textiles into high-value monomers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/363ef0699b261711eb338df91aee7b0a7f737c1a</guid></item><item><title>Spatial patterns and environmental functions of dissolved organic matter in grassland soils of China</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/85425e4720fbce7062591fa1b8bf08056878203d</link><description>Soil dissolved organic matter (DOM) is crucial to atmospheric, terrestrial and aquatic environments as well as human life. Here, by characterizing DOM from 89 grassland soils throughout China, we reveal the spatial association between DOM geochemistry in the dry season vs annual ecosystem exchange and cancer cases. The humic-like and high molecular weight (3.4–25 kDa) fractions with lower biodegradability, decline from the northern to the southern regions of China, and are correlated with lower soil respiration and net ecosystem productivity at the continental scale. The &lt;1.2 kDa and proteinaceous fractions could serve as a geographical indicator of nasopharyngeal cancer incidence and mortality, while the 3.4–25 kDa and humified fractions are potentially associated with pancreatic cancer cases (P &lt; 0.05). Our findings highlight that exploiting the environmental functions of soil DOM and mitigating the negative impacts are necessary, and require actions tailored to local soil DOM conditions. Soil dissolved organic matter (DOM) is critical to ecosystem processes and humans. Here the authors reveal the spatial variations in grassland soil DOM in China, with different fractions playing varied roles in local carbon exchange and human health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/85425e4720fbce7062591fa1b8bf08056878203d</guid></item><item><title>Designing membranes with specific binding sites for selective ion separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/224443b7ada1babe40978b2ae34b026102bd6442</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/224443b7ada1babe40978b2ae34b026102bd6442</guid></item><item><title>Pilot Scale Demonstration of Low-Salt-Rejection Reverse Osmosis (LSRRO) Desalination of High Salinity Brines</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2e14b40a4e85517c7d8438b43c0c71be06edf22</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2e14b40a4e85517c7d8438b43c0c71be06edf22</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of energy, water, land and cost implications of zero and minimal liquid discharge desalination technologies</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/df186759ee29a8f2304666dba19afffe6a4633ab</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/df186759ee29a8f2304666dba19afffe6a4633ab</guid></item><item><title>Ceramic Thin-Film Composite Membranes with Tunable Subnanometer Poresfor Molecular Sieving By Atomic Layer Deposition</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a14ec7708198105a5464a2b28af518de6faca0a9</link><description>Membranes with tunable, sub-nanometer pores are needed for molecular separations in applications including water treatment, critical mineral extraction, and recycling. Ceramic membranes are a promising alternative to the polymeric membranes typically used in such applications due to their robust operation under harsh chemical conditions. However, current fabrication technologies fail to construct ceramic membranes suitable for selective molecular separations. In this presentation, we describe a ceramic thin film composite (TFC) membrane fabrication method that achieves sub-nm pore size control using atomic layer deposition (ALD) by incorporating a molecular-scale porogen. By co-dosing alkyl alcohols along with the H2O coreactant during Al2O3 ALD, we incorporate alkoxide species in the film which create a continuous network of pores upon calcination. Varying the alkyl alcohol (methanol, ethanol, isopropanol) tunes the pore size. We use Fourier transform infrared absorption spectroscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and scanning electron microscopy to elucidate the surface chemistry and growth during the alcohol-modulated ALD as well as the subsequent pore formation. We evaluate the transport and separations properties of the ALD TFC membranes using a two-chamber diffusion cell with aqueous salt solutions. We measured a remarkable enhancement in the transport of Cl- compared to SO4
 2- (8.6 times faster) matching the selectivity of state-of-the-art polymer membranes. We attribute this selectivity to the dehydration of the large divalent ions within the subnanometer pores. In addition, permeation studies using neutral adsorbates revealed average pore sizes of ~7Å, 13Å, and 19Å for ALD TFC membranes prepared using methanol, ethanol, and isopropanol, respectively. This work provides the scientific basis for the design of ceramic membranes with subnanometer pores for molecular sieving using ALD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a14ec7708198105a5464a2b28af518de6faca0a9</guid></item><item><title>Tuning Metal-Organic Framework Linker Chemistry for Transition Metal Ion Separations.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2f568e5e4399d8466492f6bfa8a0a01294803afe</link><description>The pressing demand for critical metals necessitates the development of advanced ion separation technologies for circular resource economies. To separate transition metal ions, which exhibit near-identical chemical properties, adsorbents and membranes must be designed with ultraselective chemistries. We leverage the customizability of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) to systematically study the role of material chemistry in sorption and selectivity of Co2+, Ni2+, and Cu2+. To isolate the effect of MOF linker chemistry, a series of functionalized UiO-66 derivatives was synthesized from the same parent MOF through solvent-assisted linker exchange, which produced &gt;70% linker conversion for nine linker functional groups. This work presents the first instance of post-synthetic incorporation of carboxylic acid groups in UiO-66, which was achieved with &gt;90% conversion. A technique was developed for in situ MOF deposition in a quartz crystal microbalance to precisely monitor real-time sorption of Co2+, Ni2+, and Cu2+ in UiO-66-X [where X = H, (OH)2, COOH, or (COOH)2] and validated by comparing to batch sorption experiments (5 mM, pH 5). Carboxylic acid-functionalized derivatives exhibited the highest uptake and a trend of Cu2+ &gt; Co2+ &gt; Ni2+, with the highest sorption of 5.5% (g Cu2+/g MOF), equivalent to 37% mol Cu2+/mol linker, occurring in UiO-66-(COOH)2. Binary salt and single salt batch sorption experiments demonstrated preferential copper binding in all studied MOFs and selectivity enhancement in binary salt conditions. UiO-66-(COOH)2 exhibited the highest selectivity of 14 for equimolar Cu2+/Ni2+ and 13 for Cu2+/Co2+. Density functional theory calculations of ion binding energy at UiO-66-X pore windows indicate higher copper affinity for all functional groups and a trend in binding energy of UiO-66-(COOH)2 &gt; UiO-66-COOH &gt; UiO-66-(OH)2 &gt; UiO-66-H for each transition metal ion, in good agreement with experimental results. This work highlights the effectiveness of post-synthetic modification for tuning nanostructured materials to achieve similar ion separations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2f568e5e4399d8466492f6bfa8a0a01294803afe</guid></item><item><title>Dialysis opens a new pathway for high-salinity organic wastewater treatment</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bd58b7c2386b92c14fbcba4e22d15199a39f2e1b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bd58b7c2386b92c14fbcba4e22d15199a39f2e1b</guid></item><item><title>A highly selective and energy efficient approach to boron removal overcomes the Achilles heel of seawater desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1d054dbfc06a17dffa432ce0da94a02bcbca233f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1d054dbfc06a17dffa432ce0da94a02bcbca233f</guid></item><item><title>Gypsum heterogenous nucleation pathways regulated by surface functional groups and hydrophobicity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8398a99bd97e6f472239d7ed2c91029aee0ba9db</link><description>Gypsum (CaSO4·2H2O) plays a critical role in numerous natural and industrial processes. Nevertheless, the underlying mechanisms governing the formation of gypsum crystals on surfaces with diverse chemical properties remain poorly understood due to a lack of sufficient temporal-spatial resolution. Herein, we use in situ microscopy to investigate the real-time gypsum nucleation on self-assembled monolayers (SAMs) terminated with −CH3, −hybrid (a combination of NH2 and COOH), −COOH, −SO3, −NH3, and −OH functional groups. We report that the rate of gypsum formation is regulated by the surface functional groups and hydrophobicity, in the order of −CH3 &gt; −hybrid &gt; −COOH &gt; −SO3 ≈ − NH3 &gt; − OH. Results based on classical nucleation theory and molecular dynamics simulations reveal that nucleation pathways for hydrophilic surfaces involve surface-induced nucleation, with ion adsorption sites (i.e., functional groups) serving as anchors to facilitate the growth of vertically oriented clusters. Conversely, hydrophobic surfaces involve bulk nucleation with ions near the surface that coalesce into larger horizontal clusters. These findings provide new insights into the spatial and temporal characteristics of gypsum formation on various surfaces and highlight the significance of surface functional groups and hydrophobicity in governing gypsum formation mechanisms, while also acknowledging the possibility of alternative nucleation pathways due to the limitations of experimental techniques. This work demonstrates different gypsum nucleation pathways on hydrophilic and hydrophobic surfaces through in situ microscopy and molecular dynamics simulations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8398a99bd97e6f472239d7ed2c91029aee0ba9db</guid></item><item><title>Copper Single-Atom Catalyst on Nanoconfined Ceramic Membranes for Fenton-Like Removal of Organic Contaminants</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4fbed2080f5d6961028676e6db43d4ffe956eb26</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4fbed2080f5d6961028676e6db43d4ffe956eb26</guid></item><item><title>Approaching infinite selectivity in membrane-based aqueous lithium extraction via solid-state ion transport</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3f4662f462ba3716a3b3cf0377405b93cfa8d604</link><description>As the gap between lithium supply and demand continues to widen, the need to develop ion-selective technologies, which can efficiently extract lithium from unconventional water sources, grows increasingly crucial. In this study, we investigated the fundamentals of applying a solid-state electrolyte (SSE), typically used in battery technologies, as a membrane material for aqueous lithium extraction. We find that the anhydrous hopping of lithium ions through the ordered and confined SSE lattice is highly distinct from ion migration through the hydrated free volumes of conventional nanoporous membranes, thus culminating in unique membrane transport properties. Notably, we reveal that the SSE provides unparalleled performance with respect to ion-ion selectivity, consistently demonstrating lithium ion selectivity values that are immeasurable by even the part-per-billion detection limit of mass spectrometry. Such exceptional selectivity is shown to be the result of the characteristic size and charge exclusion mechanisms of solid-state ion transport, which may be leveraged in the design of next-generation membranes for resource recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3f4662f462ba3716a3b3cf0377405b93cfa8d604</guid></item><item><title>Dual-substrate synergistic catalysis for highly efficient water purification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/159484a3440d694f6293135b6f2aa24fab00bcd0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/159484a3440d694f6293135b6f2aa24fab00bcd0</guid></item><item><title>Relating Solute-Membrane Electrostatic Interactions to Solute Permeability in Reverse Osmosis Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ccd3bafac9438cca8d07a10647418df190cbffd6</link><description>Despite the widespread use of reverse osmosis (RO) membranes in water desalination, the role of solute-membrane interactions in solute transport remains complex and relatively not well understood. This study elucidates the relationship between solute-membrane electrostatic interactions and solute permeability in RO membranes. The transport of salt and neutral molecules through charged polyamide (PA) and uncharged cellulose triacetate (CTA) RO membranes was examined. Results show that salt rejection and salt permeability in the PA membrane are highly dependent on the solution pH due to the variations of membrane charge density and the Donnan potential at the membrane-solution interface. Specifically, a higher salt rejection (and hence lower salt permeability) of the PA membrane is observed under alkaline conditions compared to acidic conditions. This observation is attributed to the enhanced Donnan potential at higher solution pH, which hinders co-ion partitioning into the membrane. In contrast, for salt transport through the CTA membrane and neutral solute transport through both membranes, solute permeability is independent of the solution pH and solute concentration due to the negligible Donnan effect. Overall, our results demonstrate the important role of solute-membrane electrostatic interactions, combined with steric exclusion, in regulating solute permeability in RO membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ccd3bafac9438cca8d07a10647418df190cbffd6</guid></item><item><title>Ceramic-carbon Janus membrane for robust solar-thermal desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/232d97e80984cee11c6982047a0c01b53d9a27f6</link><description>The desalination performance of conventional distillation membranes is limited by insufficient stability and energy efficiency, impeding their application in sustainable water production. Herein, we report a ceramic-carbon Janus membrane with solar-thermal functionality for enhanced desalination performance, energy efficiency, and stability for hypersaline water treatment. The feed and permeate sides of this Janus membrane are designed with different properties such as wettability, conductivity, and solar-thermal conversion to enhance performance. We demonstrate that this membrane exhibits higher solar-thermal efficiency (66.8–68.8%) and water flux (3.3–5.1 L m–2 h–1) than most existing polymeric solar-thermal distillation membranes. Simulation results ascribe enhanced performance to an increased membrane surface temperature, which mitigates temperature polarization and attenuation, thus enhancing the desalination driving force. The nano-carbon membrane surface accelerates water evaporation by inducing a transition from free water to intermediate water with decreased hydrogen bonding and a lower evaporation energy barrier. Water vapor molecules transport through the membrane pores by a combined mechanism of Knudsen diffusion and viscous flow. Even for seawater and hypersaline water, the membrane exhibits stable water flux and salt rejection due to its scaling-resistant surface and stable interfacial temperature. This work provides a strategy for rationally designing next-generation Janus membranes for sustainable water purification. Conventional desalination membranes suffer from insufficient performance, stability and energy efficiency, impeding their application. Here, authors design a ceramic-carbon Janus membrane with enhanced desalination performance, energy efficiency, and operation stability for hypersaline desalination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/232d97e80984cee11c6982047a0c01b53d9a27f6</guid></item><item><title>Role of Transmembrane Pressure and Water Flux in Reverse Osmosis Composite Membrane Compaction and Performance.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3d009c8f97c6157681e58ee33000259b10f41823</link><description>This study explores the compaction behavior of thin-film composite reverse osmosis (TFC RO) membranes for different combinations of transmembrane pressure (TMP) and transmembrane water flux. Operating a crossflow system at constant feed pressure (60 bar) but different feed solution osmotic pressures enabled adjusting the TMP─the difference between hydraulic and osmotic pressure─and water flux. The extent of membrane compaction increases as TMP (and flux) increases. Both commercial and hand-cast TFC RO membranes showed substantial compaction at high TMP (up to 30% compaction at 50 bar TMP) compared to less than 10% at 10 bar TMP. Scanning electron microscope (SEM) images reveal a direct relationship between TMP and polysulfone (PSU) support layer compaction, while molecular dynamics (MD) simulations confirmed decreased porosity and reduced thickness in the polyamide (PA) active layer as TMP increases. Combined findings from wet-testing and MD simulations confirm a hydraulic pressure drop occurs across both the PA active layer and the meso-to-macro-porous support layer; higher TMP exacerbates compaction in both layers resulting in lower water permeability but higher water flux, observed salt rejection, and salt permeability. Transitioning from high TMP to low TMP or vice versa did not notably alter the extent of membrane compaction. This observation is attributed to the highly cross-linked PA active layer's ability to recover after pressure is released, whereas the compaction in the PSU support layer is largely irreversible. While TMP dictates the overall pressure gradient, our findings suggest that flux-induced frictional forces play a crucial role in compaction dynamics. Specifically, higher flux generates additional drag forces on the polymer matrix of both the PSU support layer and the PA selective layer, intensifying structural deformation. Overall, our findings offer critical insights into the mechanisms of membrane compaction, providing a foundation for optimizing RO membrane performance and advancing next-generation membrane technologies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3d009c8f97c6157681e58ee33000259b10f41823</guid></item><item><title>Nodular networks in hydrated polyamide desalination membranes enhance water transport</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/893cb795d9f5eac78d8d333a86b7e79b408fb6ad</link><description>For nearly half a century, thin-film composite reverse osmosis membranes have served as key separation materials for desalination. However, the precise structure of their polyamide selective layer under hydrated conditions and its relationship to membrane transport remain poorly understood. Using cryo–electron tomography, we successfully reconstructed the three-dimensional structure of six commercial polyamide membranes under hydrated conditions, revealing a fully swollen nodular network. The highly heterogeneous nodules, measuring 17.2 ± 2.8 nanometer in thickness, were directly connected to the pores of the underlying polysulfone substrate. The nodules occupied most of the surface area compared to the 75.9 ± 26.8-nanometer-thick dense layer of the polyamide film. Key structural parameters of the nodules, including surface area index and wall thickness, were correlated with the water permeance of an additional 16 polyamide membranes, validating the major role of these nodules in water transport. This study enhances our understanding of the heterogeneous structure of desalination membranes and its role in membrane transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/893cb795d9f5eac78d8d333a86b7e79b408fb6ad</guid></item><item><title>Ionophore-Based Molecular Layer-by-Layer Polyamide Membranes for Facilitated Single-Ion Transport.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/07de132343482d054a72b3805394d7ec8ef99dcb</link><description>Single-ion-selective membranes are indispensable for efficient ion separations in environmental, energy, and biomedical technologies. Inspired by biological ion channels, this work harnessed the selective and reversible ion binding features of ionophores to fabricate an ultrathin, ionophore-based K+-selective polyamide membrane through molecular layer-by-layer (m-LbL) polymerization with 18-crown-6-functionalized monomers. Compared with Cs+, Li+, and Mg2+, K+ exhibited the highest binding energy to 18-crown-6, facilitating its transport over the competing cations across the sub-10 nm polyamide film in a binary salt mixture. The need for competitive binding for selective K+ transport was further demonstrated through investigations of ion selectivity at varying concentration ratios between K+ and competing cations. Additionally, we extended the Nernst-Planck equation to describe individual ion flux in a binary system, identifying factors that govern ion transport. Our findings demonstrate the potential of selective single-ion transport enabled by preferential ion binding, showing promise for the development of biomimetic ion-selective polymeric membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/07de132343482d054a72b3805394d7ec8ef99dcb</guid></item><item><title>Nanonet trapping for effective removal of nanoplastics by iron coagulation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/86fd2fb71afe1800054265179c432731d6e2e8d8</link><description>Nanoplastics (NPs) are emerging aqueous pollutants, posing risks to drinking water safety and human health. However, conventional coagulants, widely employed in water treatment plants globally, are ineffective at removing NPs. Here, we present an in-situ Fe(III) method based on the simultaneous use of Fe(II) coagulant and an oxidant to enhance conventional coagulation by altering the nanostructure of Fe-based precipitates in flocs for efficient NP removal. Unlike the nanospheres formed by conventional Fe(III) coagulation, which are weakly attached to the NP surface, nanosheets formed by our approach can fully encapsulate NPs, achieving efficient nanonet trapping with a flexible mesh structure. In-situ formed nanosheets exhibit faster agglomeration, higher removal rate, and stronger anti-interference ability. The practical viability of our approach was proven in different natural water samples, where the inhibition for NP removal by various constituents of natural organic matter was effectively reduced. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that crystal structure differences between such nanosheets and nanospheres change short-range forces, thereby enhancing NP removal. Overall, this concept of modifying the nanoscale crystal structure of flocs offers valuable insights into enhanced coagulation processes, with broad applications in water treatment and environmental systems, and provides a promising solution to the critical challenge of NP removal. Nanoplastics (NPs) threaten water safety as conventional coagulants fail to remove them. Here, authors develop an in-situ Fe(III) method that forms encapsulating nanosheets, enabling efficient NP removal with stronger anti-interference in natural waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/86fd2fb71afe1800054265179c432731d6e2e8d8</guid></item><item><title>Compaction of Pressure-Driven Polymer Membranes: Measurements, Theory, and Mechanisms.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73c8dd9405f1475c25ed07d4242539e0e51aea71</link><description>Membrane compaction is inherent in pressure-driven membrane processes, resulting in a decrease in porosity and pore size of polymeric membranes as solvent flow compresses the porous structure of the polymer. The compaction of pores reduces solvent permeability and significantly impacts separation performance. Despite the importance of membrane compaction, its fundamental mechanisms have not been well studied. In this study, we combine well-controlled experiments and theory to analyze the relationship between pressure and porosity profiles within membranes. Specifically, we stack six porous films in a customized dead-end cell and measure the solvent content of each film immediately after pressure-driven solvent permeation tests. We show that, when a viscous solvent permeates through the stacked membranes, membrane porosity continuously decreases from the feed side to the permeate side. Compaction results in ∼25% reduction in solvent content (or porosity) at the membrane permeate side under 10 bar applied pressure and up to ∼50% reduction under 40 bar. We further analyze the stress-strain behavior of solvent-swollen films under mechanical compression and compare it to the compacted porosity in the solvent permeation tests. Our analysis reveals that the compression pressure in the permeation tests corresponds to the reduction in hydrostatic pressure within the membrane. In addition, we investigate the compaction behavior when membranes with varying pore sizes are stacked. Our results show that solvent permeating from tight-to-loose films induces significantly greater compaction than flow in the loose-to-tight direction. The compaction in tight-to-loose membrane stacking causes a 27% greater loss in membrane solvent content compared to the reverse arrangement. Notably, this study demonstrates that porosity gradients resulting from compaction cannot be interpreted as concentration gradients that drive diffusive solvent transport. Overall, our findings can inform the design of membranes with improved resistance to compaction by guiding material selection, processing techniques, and structural optimization.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73c8dd9405f1475c25ed07d4242539e0e51aea71</guid></item><item><title>Nondestructive In Operando Imaging of Thin Film Composite Membrane Compaction Enhanced by AI-Based Segmentation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5657e25a73dd96cc98d1cb29621c562a56f512f9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5657e25a73dd96cc98d1cb29621c562a56f512f9</guid></item><item><title>A covalent organic framework membrane with highly selective and permeable artificial sodium channels via ion recognition</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e6671e9c6c90592449ad65e5e8896dc126104324</link><description>Biological sodium channels efficiently discriminate between same–charge ions with similar hydration shells. However, achieving precise ion selectivity and high throughput in artificial ion channel fabrication remains challenging. Here, we investigate angstrom–scale channels in 15-crown-5 (15C5) functionalized COF membranes for fast, selective ion transport. Due to crown ether recognition of sodium ions, channels in DHTA-Hz-15C5 membranes selectively facilitate Na+ transport, further enhanced by the hydroxyl-enriched COF skeleton. A Na+/K+ selectivity of 58.31 is achieved with 9.33 mmol m−2 h–1 permeance, significantly exceeding current membranes and resembling biological channels. Theoretical simulations indicate one–dimensional COF channels facilitate transport, while crown ether recognition makes the Na+ energy barrier significantly lower than K⁺, enabling ultrahigh selectivity with high Na⁺ permeability. This promotes COFs for efficient single-ion transport and advances crown ether ion selectivity in nano-restricted environments. Discriminating between ions with the same charge and similar hydration shells with artificial ion channels is challenging. Here, the authors produced crown ether functionalized covalent organic framework membranes for fast and selective sodium transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e6671e9c6c90592449ad65e5e8896dc126104324</guid></item><item><title>Toward Continuous, Oriented Covalent Organic Framework Membranes for Precise Molecular Separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fb55e48db371d6984aa7f2a15031ae71ff50a541</link><description>The goal of achieving energy-efficient, precise molecular separations has motivated interest in developing and employing porous crystalline frameworks as membrane materials. Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) are ordered crystalline matrices composed of covalently bonded organic monomers and are synthesized via reversible reticular chemistry. COFs possess high porosity, structural tunability, and chemical and thermal stability, making them ideally suited for emerging, high-value membrane separation processes, such as ion separations, organic solvent nanofiltration, and gas separations. Although a range of COF membranes have been fabricated and tested in the past decade, these membranes are primarily polycrystalline, weakly crystalline, and/or discontinuous, resulting in suboptimal performance. In this review, we identify the properties that make COFs well-suited as membrane materials, while critically outlining the shortcomings of existing disordered COF membranes. We then highlight the recent emergence of highly crystalline, continuous, oriented two-dimensional COF membranes as a promising path forward for highly selective molecular separations. These continuous, oriented COF membranes exhibit tunable one-dimensional nanochannels, allowing for ultrafast molecular transport and precise species selectivity, thereby expanding the set of separations that can be practically achieved with membrane systems. We discuss synthesis and modification techniques that result in continuous, oriented COF membranes and evaluate the performance of such membranes for a variety of molecular separations. We conclude by identifying ongoing challenges in the development of COF membranes and outlining the future of their applications in molecular separations, which will necessarily rely on advancements in the synthesis of continuous, oriented membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fb55e48db371d6984aa7f2a15031ae71ff50a541</guid></item><item><title>Solvent Transport in Disordered and Dynamic Membrane Pores: Implications for Reverse Osmosis and Nanofiltration Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5a374340db6e45f0e42bdd409929d1af54996443</link><description>Pressure-driven separations with nanoporous membranes, such as reverse osmosis and nanofiltration, play a vital role in addressing water scarcity and enabling resource recovery. Understanding water or solvent transport in membrane pores is essential for advancing membrane separation technologies. A key question in transport modeling is to establish a relationship between solvent permeability and membrane porous structure properties, such as porosity or pore size. The nano- and subnanometer pores in polymeric membranes such as reverse osmosis and nanofiltration membranes are highly tortuous and dynamically connected, which challenges the conventional methods of transport modeling. This study addresses this challenge by developing a theoretical framework to describe solvent transport through membranes with dynamic and disordered porous structure. Specifically, we propose a lattice model to describe the pore network, while preserving the viscous nature of solvent permeation. We further establish a relationship between solvent permeability and membrane porosity or pore size, which is validated by molecular dynamics simulations and experimental data. By integrating this relationship into the solution-friction model, we define pore connectivity and local friction coefficient to quantify the impact of pore structure on solvent permeability. Our analysis highlights the dominant influence of pore connectivity on the permeability of reverse osmosis and nanofiltration membranes, particularly when the pore size approaches the dimensions of solvent molecules. Overall, this study provides critical insights into water and solvent transport mechanisms in nanoporous membranes, opening the door for strategies to substantially enhance membrane performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5a374340db6e45f0e42bdd409929d1af54996443</guid></item><item><title>The US–Israel Blavatnik Scientific Forum on alleviating global water scarcity by desalination and water reuse</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0805f790107b356b83404e43946e071cdf7c6417</link><description>Global</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0805f790107b356b83404e43946e071cdf7c6417</guid></item><item><title>Scalable catalytic nanofiltration membranes for advanced water treatment</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c4eb02723b9dc46c5037ae46285ebd115ee4c2bf</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c4eb02723b9dc46c5037ae46285ebd115ee4c2bf</guid></item><item><title>Ultrahigh pressure compaction-resistant thin film crosslinked composite reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/836617e45a73d33aaa56b52908519f23ff484032</link><description>In this study, we present a class of thin-film crosslinked (TFX) composite reverse osmosis (RO) membranes that resist physical compaction at ultrahigh pressures (up to 200 bar). Since RO membranes experience compaction at virtually all pressure ranges, the ability to resist compaction has widespread implications for RO membrane technology. The process described herein involves crosslinking a phase inverted porous polyimide (PI) support membrane followed by interfacial polymerization of a polyamide layer, thereby forming a fully thermoset composite membrane structure. We explore a range of phase inversion membrane formation parameters such as PI concentration, solvent-cosolvent ratios, coagulation bath composition, and crosslinking methods in addition to interfacial polymerization reaction chemistry and conditions. Overall, TFX membranes exhibit significantly less compaction compared to hand-cast and commercial high-pressure RO membranes, experiencing less than 10% decline in water permeance and maintaining salt rejection over 99% for NaCl solutions up to 180,000 mg/L with 200 bar applied pressure. The ability to resist compaction has widespread implications for reverse osmosis (RO) membrane technology. Here the authors present a class of thin-film crosslinked composite reverse osmosis membranes that resist physical compaction at ultrahigh pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/836617e45a73d33aaa56b52908519f23ff484032</guid></item><item><title>Plasmonic nanoheating for versatile water purification membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fe49e6fbe8d493e70e3e2b9df0c725ef16380a5d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fe49e6fbe8d493e70e3e2b9df0c725ef16380a5d</guid></item><item><title>Affinity-induced upcycling of palladium nanoclusters in COF membranes for catalytic water treatment</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cf399f8a0ae15b88b5ff61079ef2a20def7bf1ae</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cf399f8a0ae15b88b5ff61079ef2a20def7bf1ae</guid></item><item><title>Partition–diffusion–reaction bounds for thin-film membrane formation kinetics</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f5849158b69bd62e6b702f995e5f8140b1ec5e12</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f5849158b69bd62e6b702f995e5f8140b1ec5e12</guid></item><item><title>Embossing-Free Permeate Carrier for Ultrahigh Pressure Reverse Osmosis.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/03e663c85264073261e6ad7b95c252b591ca530b</link><description>Membrane brine concentration (MBC) offers the ability to concentrate brines at lower energy and cost compared to thermal brine concentration (TBC), thus expanding the global opportunities for minimum and zero liquid discharge (M/ZLD). Ultrahigh-pressure reverse osmosis (UHPRO) and osmosis-assisted RO (OARO) MBC processes operate between 80 and 120 bar, depending on the specific process configuration. Herein, we show that operating commercial RO membranes on top of commercial permeate carriers (PCs) at such high pressures leads to both RO membrane compaction and embossing, which initially cause reduced water permeability and elevated permeate backpressure, respectively. Eventually, the polyamide (and polysulfone) layer can rupture, resulting in the irreversible loss of salt rejection at applied pressures of 80 to 120 bar. Optical and SEM images confirmed through-thickness mechanical imprinting that aligned with the structural features of the PCs, establishing a clear causal relationship between embossing and performance decline. Finally, we designed an embossing-free permeate carrier (EFPC) composed of two soft tricot mesh layers sandwiching a rigid stainless-steel mesh. This EFPC eliminated embossing-enhanced permeate backpressure and membrane damage, enabling commercial RO membranes to sustain stable water flux and salt rejection up to 120 bar. Overall, this study demonstrates that advancements in UHPRO/OARO technology must incorporate both compaction-resistant membranes and EFPCs to fully realize the potential of MBC technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/03e663c85264073261e6ad7b95c252b591ca530b</guid></item><item><title>Solar-thermal membrane distillation: Opportunities and challenges</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/21fb22e4e1a0f630b3e7ef13b006b9d425df8b4c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/21fb22e4e1a0f630b3e7ef13b006b9d425df8b4c</guid></item></channel></rss>