<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ryan Kingsbury</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/40390912</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Ryan Kingsbury</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:34:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A database of molecular properties integrated in the Materials Project</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a7f7efae6d379a9b4dbde85f944f50e7c9ccce6b</link><description>Advanced chemical research is increasingly reliant on large computed datasets of molecules and reactions to discover new functional molecules, understand chemical trends, train machine learning models, and more. To be...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a7f7efae6d379a9b4dbde85f944f50e7c9ccce6b</guid></item><item><title>Evaluation of Magnetic Ion Exchange (MIEX) Pre-treatment on Ozonation Performance and Disinfection By-Product Formation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/47343a05a21aebbd375ed7aa5396809ed452c78c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/47343a05a21aebbd375ed7aa5396809ed452c78c</guid></item><item><title>Effect of magnetic ion exchange and ozonation on disinfection by-product formation.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/35c5080ec722e059f2337ec7ee19044fa4992149</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/35c5080ec722e059f2337ec7ee19044fa4992149</guid></item><item><title>Energy storage by reversible electrodialysis: The concentration battery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/431c031fb1b08898d2f8ae0ced5914867920f189</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/431c031fb1b08898d2f8ae0ced5914867920f189</guid></item><item><title>Osmotic Ballasts Enhance Faradaic Efficiency in Closed-Loop, Membrane-Based Energy Systems.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99dee010710331227a2f4108673b285d07b5540e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99dee010710331227a2f4108673b285d07b5540e</guid></item><item><title>Partitioning of Alkali Metal Salts and Boric Acid from Aqueous Phase into the Polyamide Active Layers of Reverse Osmosis Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ddd1bf342bf2eb5b40daac4ee353d0552a9d1a4a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ddd1bf342bf2eb5b40daac4ee353d0552a9d1a4a</guid></item><item><title>Impact of natural organic matter and inorganic solutes on energy recovery from five real salinity gradients using reverse electrodialysis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0a011ce6c06efb012ad284d5c7eca6bd8bf7b091</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0a011ce6c06efb012ad284d5c7eca6bd8bf7b091</guid></item><item><title>Junction Potentials Bias Measurements of Ion Exchange Membrane Permselectivity.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ee18ab6832064eeab81b863037331aa4b94281d4</link><description>Ion exchange membranes (IEMs) are versatile materials relevant to a variety of water and waste treatment, energy production, and industrial separation processes. The defining characteristic of IEMs is their ability to selectively allow positive or negative ions to permeate, which is referred to as permselectivity. Measured values of permselectivity that equal unity (corresponding to a perfectly selective membrane) or exceed unity (theoretically impossible) have been reported for cation exchange membranes (CEMs). Such nonphysical results call into question our ability to correctly measure this crucial membrane property. Because weighing errors, temperature, and measurement uncertainty have been shown to not explain these anomalous permselectivity results, we hypothesized that a possible explanation are junction potentials that occur at the tips of reference electrodes. In this work, we tested this hypothesis by comparing permselectivity values obtained from bare Ag/AgCl wire electrodes (which have no junction) to values obtained from single-junction reference electrodes containing two different electrolytes. We show that permselectivity values obtained using reference electrodes with junctions were greater than unity for CEMs. In contrast, electrodes without junctions always produced permselectivities lower than unity. Electrodes with junctions also resulted in artificially low permselectivity values for AEMs compared to electrodes without junctions. Thus, we conclude that junctions in reference electrodes introduce two biases into results in the IEM literature: (i) permselectivity values larger than unity for CEMs and (ii) lower permselectivity values for AEMs compared to those for CEMs. These biases can be avoided by using electrodes without a junction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ee18ab6832064eeab81b863037331aa4b94281d4</guid></item><item><title>Impact of solution composition on the resistance of ion exchange membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4af18f5c7ca9d6f0a03c3f0ffa0dfe2d16c21a55</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4af18f5c7ca9d6f0a03c3f0ffa0dfe2d16c21a55</guid></item><item><title>Microstructure Determines Water and Salt Permeation in Commercial Ion-Exchange Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/170942bd17bc6a8e1fb21a515b25f2611d539c7b</link><description>Ion-exchange membrane (IEM) performance in electrochemical processes such as fuel cells, redox flow batteries, or reverse electrodialysis (RED) is typically quantified through membrane selectivity and conductivity, which together determine the energy efficiency. However, water and co-ion transport (i.e., osmosis and salt diffusion/fuel crossover) also impact energy efficiency by allowing uncontrolled mixing of the electrolyte solutions to occur. For example, in RED with hypersaline water sources, uncontrolled mixing consumes 20-50% of the available mixing energy. Thus, in addition to high selectivity and high conductivity, it is desirable for IEMs to have low permeability to water and salt to minimize energy losses. Unfortunately, there is very little quantitative water and salt permeability information available for commercial IEMs, making it difficult to select the best membrane for a particular application. Accordingly, we measured the water and salt transport properties of 20 commercial IEMs and analyzed the relationships between permeability, diffusion, and partitioning according to the solution-diffusion model. We found that water and salt permeance vary over several orders of magnitude among commercial IEMs, making some membranes better suited than others to electrochemical processes that involve high salt concentrations and/or concentration gradients. Water and salt diffusion coefficients were found to be the principal factors contributing to the differences in permeance among commercial IEMs. We also observed that water and salt permeability were highly correlated to one another for all IEMs studied, regardless of polymer type or reinforcement. This finding suggests that transport of mobile salt in IEMs is governed by the microstructure of the membrane and provides clear evidence that mobile salt does not interact strongly with polymer chains in highly swollen IEMs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/170942bd17bc6a8e1fb21a515b25f2611d539c7b</guid></item><item><title>Correction to "Microstructure Determines Water and Salt Permeation in Commercial Ion-Exchange Membranes".</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6d9c70aa9728294e309e1e127480cdeeab67f47b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6d9c70aa9728294e309e1e127480cdeeab67f47b</guid></item><item><title>Influence of Water Uptake, Charge, Manning Parameter, and Contact Angle on Water and Salt Transport in Commercial Ion Exchange Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c915df7ac3463c13f172764652efe45b74594758</link><description>In electrochemical processes such as electrodialysis or redox flow batteries, where ion exchange membranes (IEMs) play a critical role in process performance, energy losses can be reduced by minimi...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c915df7ac3463c13f172764652efe45b74594758</guid></item><item><title>materialsproject/pymatgen: v2020.4.2</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/11392ca4de4ba4e14e9502235fc41c2bda70a46b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/11392ca4de4ba4e14e9502235fc41c2bda70a46b</guid></item><item><title>Comparison of water and salt transport properties of ion exchange, reverse osmosis, and nanofiltration membranes for desalination and energy applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f960de21b21b23bb83d7b2e8474cee0fe898fa3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f960de21b21b23bb83d7b2e8474cee0fe898fa3</guid></item><item><title>Modeling and validation of concentration dependence of ion exchange membrane permselectivity: Significance of convection and Manning's counter-ion condensation theory</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7fb785157a7717c10cb13a32ac6d1297b23b6021</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7fb785157a7717c10cb13a32ac6d1297b23b6021</guid></item><item><title>Temporal variation of power production via reverse electrodialysis using coastal North Carolina waters and its correlation to temperature and conductivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a03be56240509006170c11552eba68dd4d8d6111</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a03be56240509006170c11552eba68dd4d8d6111</guid></item><item><title>A framework for quantifying uncertainty in DFT energy corrections</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f85a3e68c6cd309c940c647bdbd00fc8cfb14c23</link><description>In this work, we demonstrate a method to quantify uncertainty in corrections to density functional theory (DFT) energies based on empirical results. Such corrections are commonly used to improve the accuracy of computational enthalpies of formation, phase stability predictions, and other energy-derived properties, for example. We incorporate this method into a new DFT energy correction scheme comprising a mixture of oxidation-state and composition-dependent corrections and show that many chemical systems contain unstable polymorphs that may actually be predicted stable when uncertainty is taken into account. We then illustrate how these uncertainties can be used to estimate the probability that a compound is stable on a compositional phase diagram, thus enabling better-informed assessments of compound stability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f85a3e68c6cd309c940c647bdbd00fc8cfb14c23</guid></item><item><title>Performance comparison of r2SCAN and SCAN metaGGA density functionals for solid materials via an automated, high-throughput computational workflow</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7bd8fc23ed98c708fdc16e5aea1674c9d7d37a31</link><description>Computational materials discovery efforts utilize hundreds or thousands of density functional theory (DFT) calculations to predict material properties. Historically, such efforts have performed calculations at the generalized gradient approximation (GGA) level of theory due to its efficient compromise between accuracy and computational reliability. However, high-throughput calculations at the higher metaGGA level of theory are becoming feasible. The Strongly Constrainted and Appropriately Normed (SCAN) metaGGA functional offers superior accuracy to GGA across much of chemical space, making it appealing as a general-purpose metaGGA functional, but it suffers from numerical instabilities that impede it's use in high-throughput workflows. The recently-developed r2SCAN metaGGA functional promises accuracy similar to SCAN in addition to more robust numerical performance. However, its performance compared to SCAN has yet to be evaluated over a large group of solid materials. In this work, we compared r2SCAN and SCAN predictions for key properties of approximately 6,000 solid materials using a newly-developed high-throughput computational workflow. We find that r2SCAN predicts formation energies more accurately than SCAN and PBEsol for both strongly- and weakly-bound materials and that r2SCAN predicts systematically larger lattice constants than SCAN. We also find that r2SCAN requires modestly fewer computational resources than SCAN and offers significantly more reliable convergence. Thus, our large-scale benchmark confirms that r2SCAN has delivered on its promises of numerical efficiency and accuracy, making it a preferred choice for high-throughput metaGGA calculations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7bd8fc23ed98c708fdc16e5aea1674c9d7d37a31</guid></item><item><title>Aqueous Stability of Zirconium Clusters, Including the Zr(IV) Hexanuclear Hydrolysis Complex [Zr6O4(OH)4(H2O)24]12+, from Density Functional Theory.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/16cc74dad0a061af47033b5df7e74067547d3039</link><description>Framework materials constitute a broad family of solids that range from zeolites and metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) to coordination polymers. The synthesis of such network structures typically rely on precursor molecular building blocks. As an example, the UiO-66 MOF series is constructed of hexanuclear [Zr6O4(OH)4(CO2)12] cluster nodes and linear carboxylate linkers. Unfortunately, these Zr MOF cluster nodes cannot currently be manufactured in a sustainable way, motivating a search for "green" alternative synthesis methods. Stabilizing the hexanuclear Zr(IV) cluster (i.e., the hexamer, {Zr612+}) without the use of organic ligation would enable the use of environmentally friendly solvents such as water. The Zr(IV) tetranuclear cluster (i.e., the tetramer, {Zr48+}) can be stabilized in solution with or without organic ligands, yet the hexamer has yet to be synthesized without supporting ligands. The reasons why certain zirconium clusters are favored in aqueous solution over others are not well understood. This study reports the relative thermodynamic instability of the hypothetical hexamer {Zr612+} compared to the ubiquitous {Zr48+} tetramer. Density functional theory calculations were performed to obtain the hydrolysis Gibbs free energy of these species and used to construct Zr Pourbaix diagrams that illustrate the effects of electrochemical potential, pH, and Zr(IV) concentration. It was found that the aqueous {Zr612+} hexamer is ∼17.8 kcal/mol less stable than the aqueous {Zr48+} tetramer at pH = 0, V = 0, and [Zr(IV)] = 1 M, which is an energy difference on the order of counterion interactions. Electronic structure analyses were used to explore trends in the highest occupied molecular orbital-lowest unoccupied molecular orbital gap, frontier molecular orbitals, and electrostatic potential distribution of these clusters. The evidence suggests that the aqueous {Zr612+} hexamer may be promoted with more strategic syntheses incorporating minimal ligands and counterions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/16cc74dad0a061af47033b5df7e74067547d3039</guid></item><item><title>Tunable Anion Exchange Membrane Conductivity and Permselectivity via Non-Covalent, Hydrogen Bond Cross-Linking.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/38c67d2804cdf42503a9df3d53106c8882a3339d</link><description>Ion exchange membranes (IEMs) are a key component of electrochemical processes that purify water, generate clean energy, and treat waste. Most conventional polymer IEMs are covalently cross-linked, which results in a challenging tradeoff relationship between two desirable properties─high permselectivity and high conductivity─in which one property cannot be changed without negatively affecting the other. In an attempt to overcome this limitation, in this work we synthesized a series of anion exchange membranes containing non-covalent cross-links formed by a hydrogen bond donor (methacrylic acid) and a hydrogen bond acceptor (dimethylacrylamide). We show that these monomers act synergistically to improve both membrane permselectivity and conductivity relative to a control membrane without non-covalent cross-links. Furthermore, we show that the hydrogen bond donor and acceptor loading can be used to tune permselectivity and conductivity relatively independently of one another, escaping the tradeoff observed in conventional membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/38c67d2804cdf42503a9df3d53106c8882a3339d</guid></item><item><title>Effect of osmotic ballast properties on the performance of a concentration gradient battery.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bec25febf0e6fcb10badb0138d633d5c0891977b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bec25febf0e6fcb10badb0138d633d5c0891977b</guid></item><item><title>Tuning the Solvation Structure in Aqueous Zinc Batteries to Maximize Zn-Ion Intercalation and Optimize Dendrite-Free Zinc Plating</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0892de9b53098d5295d82765ba6a5dbe1ecb81ae</link><description>Aqueous zinc batteries are recognized to suffer from H/ Zn coinsertion in the cathode, but few approaches have been reported to suppress deleterious H intercalation. Herein, we realize this goal by tuning the solvation structure, using LiV2(PO4)3 (LVP) as a model cathode. Phase conversion of LVP induced by H intercalation is observed in 4 m Zn(OTf)2, whereas dominant Zn 2+ insertion is confirmed in a ZnCl2 water-in-salt electrolyte (WiSE). This disparity is ascribed to the complete absence of free water and a strong Zn−H2O interaction in the latter that interrupts the H2O hydrogen bonding network, thus suppressing H intercalation. On the basis of this strategy, a novel PEG-based hybrid electrolyte is designed to replace the corrosive ZnCl2 WiSE. This system exhibits an optimized Zn 2+ solvation sheath with a similar low free water content, showing not only much better suppression of H intercalation but also highly reversible Zn plating/stripping with a CE of ∼99.7% over 150 cycles. Owing to the high electrodeposition potential of Zn 2+ (∼−0.76 V vs SHE), the high theoretical volumetric capacity of the Zn anode (5850 mAh mL−1) and the advantages of low-cost, high-safety, and eco-friendly operation, aqueous zinc metal batteries (AZMBs) are becoming one of the most attractive technologies for large-scale stationary energy storage. Much work has focused on developing cathode materials for AZMBs, including MnO2, 4 Zn0.25V2O5· nH2O, 5 and many others. However, recent studies have found that the high electrochemical capacity of these metal oxides is not solely due to Zn insertion/extraction but also relies on H (de)intercalation. Proton intercalation results in the formation of layered double-hydroxide salts (LDH, for example, Zn4SO4(OH)6·5H2O) on the surface of metal oxides, which aids the reversible and stable operation of metal oxides due to its unique buffering mechanism. On the other hand, the LDH forms an insulating layer on the oxide surface that detaches from the electrode over time, leading to loss of active material. Proton intercalation has now been generally accepted as a common phenomenon for metal oxides in AZMBs. Studies involving polyanion compounds similarly showed that either H (or Na) insertion occurs along with Zn intercalation. For example, by analyzing the differential capacity curves (dQ/dV) of layered VOPO4·xH2O cathode in different electrolytes, Sun et al. found that H intercalation played a dominant role in an electrolyte comprised of 5 m ZnCl2/0.8 m H3PO4. 13 Not surprisingly, on increasing the concentration of ZnCl2 to 10−13 m, Zn was suggested to dominate the intercalation process based on the higher peak intensity of the Zn contribution in the dQ/dV curve. The factors responsible for Zn versus H intercalation (aside from concentration) were not investigated in this study. Monoclinic LiV2(PO4)3 was reported to be a superior host for AZMBs and can be cycled at an exceptionally high rate of 60 C. As the high charge density of Zn would likely result in limits to solid-state diffusion at this current density and significant structural distortion in monoclinic V2(PO4)3, 16 a fundamenReceived: November 18, 2021 Accepted: December 28, 2021 Leter http://pubs.acs.org/journal/aelccp © XXXX American Chemical Society 533 https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.1c02514 ACS Energy Lett. 2022, 7, 533−540 D ow nl oa de d vi a L A W R E N C E B E R K E L E Y N A T L L A B O R A T O R Y o n Ja nu ar y 4, 2 02 2 at 1 6: 24 :4 8 (U T C ). Se e ht tp s: //p ub s. ac s. or g/ sh ar in gg ui de lin es f or o pt io ns o n ho w to le gi tim at el y sh ar e pu bl is he d ar tic le s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0892de9b53098d5295d82765ba6a5dbe1ecb81ae</guid></item><item><title>Zinc Titanium Nitride Semiconductor toward Durable Photoelectrochemical Applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1facbf49dd97de7866acb3a5da2cceb2b0a2b456</link><description>Photoelectrochemical fuel generation is a promising route to sustainable liquid fuels produced from water and captured carbon dioxide with sunlight as the energy input. Development of these technologies requires photoelectrode materials that are both photocatalytically active and operationally stable in harsh oxidative and/or reductive electrochemical environments. Such photocatalysts can be discovered based on co-design principles, wherein design for stability is based on the propensity for the photocatalyst to self-passivate under operating conditions and design for photoactivity is based on the ability to integrate the photocatalyst with established semiconductor substrates. Here, we report on the synthesis and characterization of zinc titanium nitride (ZnTiN2) that follows these design rules by having a wurtzite-derived crystal structure and showing self-passivating surface oxides created by electrochemical polarization. The sputtered ZnTiN2 thin films have optical absorption onsets below 2 eV and n-type electrical conduction of 3 S/cm. The band gap of this material is reduced from the 3.36 eV theoretical value by cation-site disorder, and the impact of cation antisites on the band structure of ZnTiN2 is explored using density functional theory. Under electrochemical polarization, the ZnTiN2 surfaces have TiO2- or ZnO-like character, consistent with Materials Project Pourbaix calculations predicting the formation of stable solid phases under near-neutral pH. These results show that ZnTiN2 is a promising candidate for photoelectrochemical liquid fuel generation and demonstrate a new materials design approach to other photoelectrodes with self-passivating native operational surface chemistry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1facbf49dd97de7866acb3a5da2cceb2b0a2b456</guid></item><item><title>Screening of bimetallic electrocatalysts for water purification with machine learning.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/18cccfb7cef470e794f0c48fa07eb8511495ca55</link><description>Electrocatalysis provides a potential solution to NO3 - pollution in wastewater by converting it to innocuous N2 gas. However, materials with excellent catalytic activity are typically limited to expensive precious metals, hindering their commercial viability. In response to this challenge, we have conducted the most extensive computational search to date for electrocatalysts that can facilitate NO3 - reduction reaction, starting with 59 390 candidate bimetallic alloys from the Materials Project and Automatic-Flow databases. Using a joint machine learning- and computation-based screening strategy, we evaluated our candidates based on corrosion resistance, catalytic activity, N2 selectivity, cost, and the ability to synthesize. We found that only 20 materials will satisfy all criteria in our screening strategy, all of which contain varying amounts of Cu. Our proposed list of candidates is consistent with previous materials investigated in the literature, with the exception of Cu-Co and Cu-Ag based compounds that merit further investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/18cccfb7cef470e794f0c48fa07eb8511495ca55</guid></item><item><title>A flexible and scalable scheme for mixing computed formation energies from different levels of theory</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5a8deb511ee64bddaf060d744a6666d54c7e41ad</link><description>Computational materials discovery efforts are enabled by large databases of properties derived from high-throughput density functional theory (DFT), which now contain millions of calculations at the generalized gradient approximation (GGA) level of theory. It is now feasible to carry out high-throughput calculations using more accurate methods, such as meta-GGA DFT; however recomputing an entire database with a higher-fidelity method would not effectively leverage the enormous investment of computational resources embodied in existing (GGA) calculations. Instead, we propose here a general procedure by which higher-fidelity, low-coverage calculations (e.g., meta-GGA calculations for selected chemical systems) can be combined with lower-fidelity, high-coverage calculations (e.g., an existing database of GGA calculations) in a robust and scalable manner. We then use legacy PBE(+ U ) GGA calculations and new r 2 SCAN meta-GGA calculations from the Materials Project database to demonstrate that our scheme improves solid and aqueous phase stability predictions, and discuss practical considerations for its implementation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5a8deb511ee64bddaf060d744a6666d54c7e41ad</guid></item><item><title>A reverse-selective ion exchange membrane for the selective transport of phosphates via an outer-sphere complexation–diffusion pathway</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1413a0be68122b5649386afae4769c11d2c33edf</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1413a0be68122b5649386afae4769c11d2c33edf</guid></item><item><title>SolvationAnalysis: A Python toolkit for understanding liquid solvation structure in classical molecular dynamics simulations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a4896df3c85f0286a306d587cb2864b841f3ef73</link><description>1 Materials Science Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, United States of America 2 Australian National University, Australia 3 Institute of Materials Research, Shenzhen International Graduate School, Tsinghua University, China 4 Energy Storage &amp; Distributed Resources Division, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, United States of America 5 Department of Materials Science, University of California, United States of America 6 Molecular Foundry, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, United States of America DOI: 10.21105/joss.05183</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a4896df3c85f0286a306d587cb2864b841f3ef73</guid></item><item><title>Enabling selective zinc-ion intercalation by a eutectic electrolyte for practical anodeless zinc batteries</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ba4501380ae9d34a17a35e7379d143fbe319f54c</link><description>Two major challenges hinder the advance of aqueous zinc metal batteries for sustainable stationary storage: (1) achieving predominant Zn-ion (de)intercalation at the oxide cathode by suppressing adventitious proton co-intercalation and dissolution, and (2) simultaneously overcoming Zn dendrite growth at the anode that triggers parasitic electrolyte reactions. Here, we reveal the competition between Zn2+ vs proton intercalation chemistry of a typical oxide cathode using ex-situ/operando techniques, and alleviate side reactions by developing a cost-effective and non-flammable hybrid eutectic electrolyte. A fully hydrated Zn2+ solvation structure facilitates fast charge transfer at the solid/electrolyte interface, enabling dendrite-free Zn plating/stripping with a remarkably high average coulombic efficiency of 99.8% at commercially relevant areal capacities of 4 mAh cm−2 and function up to 1600 h at 8 mAh cm−2. By concurrently stabilizing Zn redox at both electrodes, we achieve a new benchmark in Zn-ion battery performance of 4 mAh cm−2 anode-free cells that retain 85% capacity over 100 cycles at 25 °C. Using this eutectic-design electrolyte, Zn | |Iodine full cells are further realized with 86% capacity retention over 2500 cycles. The approach represents a new avenue for long-duration energy storage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ba4501380ae9d34a17a35e7379d143fbe319f54c</guid></item><item><title>Unifying the Conversation: Membrane Separation Performance in Energy, Water, and Industrial Applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/631095fdb8fadfd8feec2042b183572116107d71</link><description>Dense polymer membranes enable a diverse range of separations and clean energy technologies, including gas separation, water treatment, and renewable fuel production or conversion. The transport of small molecular and ionic solutes in the majority of these membranes is described by the same solution-diffusion mechanism, yet a comparison of membrane separation performance across applications is rare. A better understanding of how structure–property relationships and driving forces compare among applications would drive innovation in membrane development by identifying opportunities for cross-disciplinary knowledge transfer. Here, we aim to inspire such cross-pollination by evaluating the selectivity and electrochemical driving forces for 29 separations across nine different applications using a common framework grounded in the physicochemical characteristics of the permeating and rejected solutes. Our analysis shows that highly selective membranes usually exhibit high solute rejection, rather than fast solute permeation, and often exploit contrasts in the size and charge of solutes rather than a nonelectrostatic chemical property, polarizability. We also highlight the power of selective driving forces (e.g., the fact that applied electric potential acts on charged solutes but not on neutral ones) to enable effective separation processes, even when the membrane itself has poor selectivity. We conclude by proposing several research opportunities that are likely to impact multiple areas of membrane science. The high-level perspective of membrane separation across fields presented herein aims to promote cross-pollination and innovation by enabling comparisons of solute transport and driving forces among membrane separation applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/631095fdb8fadfd8feec2042b183572116107d71</guid></item><item><title>pyEQL: A Python interface for water chemistry</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/39c6a1aaf6e79d6a6b0f381dc3486be8f49c90e6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/39c6a1aaf6e79d6a6b0f381dc3486be8f49c90e6</guid></item><item><title>Kinetic barrier networks reveal rate limitations in ion-selective membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7afbda1cb36b4659d8ab114d549bcb233430a3cd</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7afbda1cb36b4659d8ab114d549bcb233430a3cd</guid></item><item><title>Unveiling the role of membrane properties in water and salt transport and performance of a concentration gradient battery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/779cacc309f0e0779775e9749c409ba8be3cddb8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/779cacc309f0e0779775e9749c409ba8be3cddb8</guid></item><item><title>Microporous Polymer Sorbents for Direct Lithium Extraction</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e9ca708d9e91d11e5614a645fae63717b1e0cbfe</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e9ca708d9e91d11e5614a645fae63717b1e0cbfe</guid></item><item><title>HEPOM: Using Graph Neural Networks for the Accelerated Predictions of Hydrolysis Free Energies in Different pH Conditions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/acd844aee84820aa3d08ad7d321d098addcb497e</link><description>Hydrolysis is a fundamental family of chemical reactions where water facilitates the cleavage of bonds. The process is ubiquitous in biological and chemical systems, owing to water’s remarkable versatility as a solvent. However, accurately predicting the feasibility of hydrolysis through computational techniques is a difficult task, as subtle changes in reactant structure like heteroatom substitutions or neighboring functional groups can influence the reaction outcome. Furthermore, hydrolysis is sensitive to the pH of the aqueous medium, and the same reaction can have different reaction properties at different pH conditions. In this work, we have combined reaction templates and high-throughput ab initio calculations to construct a diverse data set of hydrolysis free energies. The developed framework automatically identifies reaction centers, generates hydrolysis products, and utilizes a trained graph neural network (GNN) model to predict ΔG values for all potential hydrolysis reactions in a given molecule. The long-term goal of the work is to develop a data-driven, computational tool for high-throughput screening of pH-specific hydrolytic stability and the rapid prediction of reaction products, which can then be applied in a wide array of applications including chemical recycling of polymers and ion-conducting membranes for clean energy generation and storage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/acd844aee84820aa3d08ad7d321d098addcb497e</guid></item><item><title>Atomate2: modular workflows for materials science</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99c331a47048c67ebb87758b7f760ca40c9bd70f</link><description>High-throughput density functional theory (DFT) calculations have become a vital element of computational materials science, enabling materials screening, property database generation, and training of “universal” machine learning models. While several software frameworks have emerged to support these computational efforts, new developments such as machine learned force fields have increased demands for more flexible and programmable workflow solutions. This manuscript introduces atomate2, a comprehensive evolution of our original atomate framework, designed to address existing limitations in computational materials research infrastructure. Key features include the support for multiple electronic structure packages and interoperability between them, along with generalizable workflows that can be written in an abstract form irrespective of the DFT package or machine learning force field used within them. Our hope is that atomate2's improved usability and extensibility can reduce technical barriers for high-throughput research workflows and facilitate the rapid adoption of emerging methods in computational material science.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/99c331a47048c67ebb87758b7f760ca40c9bd70f</guid></item><item><title>Accelerated data-driven materials science with the Materials Project</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cbb06d047cda87b3807b963c74958c5173b302a6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cbb06d047cda87b3807b963c74958c5173b302a6</guid></item><item><title>A guide to ion separations for the global energy transition</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/675ca0470680b801af281fe103b60c02bd727171</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/675ca0470680b801af281fe103b60c02bd727171</guid></item><item><title>Electrolytic hydrogen production from acidified wastewater effluent.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/62245bdf5dac256f121f8f11836b24115a0174e7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/62245bdf5dac256f121f8f11836b24115a0174e7</guid></item></channel></rss>