<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ryan Lively</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/2832408</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Ryan Lively</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:31:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PIM hybrids and derivatives: how to make a good thing better</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/70c57d82f5dcb72b76d9f8e333c3b48e605acbc4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/70c57d82f5dcb72b76d9f8e333c3b48e605acbc4</guid></item><item><title>Interpreting the Ultramicroporous Structure of Carbon Molecular Sieves</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/624a9c3fbe7b0842f09a8c04f3364670a3c962e7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/624a9c3fbe7b0842f09a8c04f3364670a3c962e7</guid></item><item><title>Achieving Order of Magnitude Increases in CO2 Reduction Reaction Efficiency by Product Separations and Recycling</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/396fd7e64ab5f5e229833493ace82acb8fc6b701</link><description>CO2 reduction reaction (CO2RR) systems are the heart of many proposed e-refinery schemes. There have been few studies on the separation systems that will be needed to complement CO2RR reactors....</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/396fd7e64ab5f5e229833493ace82acb8fc6b701</guid></item><item><title>Evaluating Degradation of CO2 Adsorbents in Flue Gas from Bioenergy with Carbon Capture and Storage</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d7f1f9ad9265c8499290869e4f402fe18a093394</link><description>The potential degradation of CO2 adsorbents in Bioenergy with Carbon Capture and Storage (BECCS) was investigated through direct exposure to biomass combustion flue gas. Pre- and post-exposure characterization after 6-12...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d7f1f9ad9265c8499290869e4f402fe18a093394</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Study of Direct CO2 Capture from Indoor Air using Poly(ethylenimine)-Impregnated Fiber Sorbents</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/80c402cb8daeafad24d244847bd76e952ef12b2d</link><description>Supported amine adsorbents are promising materials for direct air capture (DAC) of CO2 due to their high CO2 capacity and relatively low energy requirement for regeneration. For a DAC process,...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/80c402cb8daeafad24d244847bd76e952ef12b2d</guid></item><item><title>Tuning sorbent properties to reduce the cost of direct air capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e3da799751467dcdd64f6aba20a08fa04519d377</link><description>The question has shifted from whether solid sorbents can work in direct air capture (DAC) technologies to which solid sorbents are more economically advantaged. Determining this is challenging due to...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e3da799751467dcdd64f6aba20a08fa04519d377</guid></item><item><title>Amine-dependent CO2 sorption on amine-impregnated Mg2(dobpdc) MOF under humid conditions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7be295629f195bdcc298984f5eafb970ceb23674</link><description>Water improves CO2 uptake in oligomeric amine impregnated-Mg2(dobpdc) by increasing CO2 diffusion into the amine films, whereas water decreases CO2 uptake in the polymeric amine analogue by particle/pore collapse of Mg2(dobpdc).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7be295629f195bdcc298984f5eafb970ceb23674</guid></item><item><title>Defining Targets for Adsorbent Material Performance to Enable Viable BECCS Processes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/33f0fe016ab215c999b565e553fff3719d968092</link><description>Target properties of CO2 capture adsorbents that would ensure economic viability of bioenergy with carbon capture and storage (BECCS) are defined. The key role of sorbent lifetime in the process cost is demonstrated, and an optimal heat of adsorption for BECCS is postulated through a balance of adsorbent–adsorbate affinity and regeneration energy demand. Using an exponential decay model of sorbent capacity increases the process cost and results in an optimum sorbent lifetime. To ensure a levelized cost of carbon below $100/tonne-CO2, adsorbents should be designed to have working capacities above 0.75 mol/kg, lifetimes over 2 years, heats of adsorption of approximately −40 kJ/mol, and exponential degradation decay constants below 5 × 10–6 cycle–1 (equivalent to a half-life of 1.3 years). Our model predicts a BECCS process cost of $65/t-CO2 can be achieved with a degradation-resistant adsorbent, $40/kg sorbent cost, 2.0 mol/kg working capacity, −40 kJ/mol heat of adsorption, and at least a 2 year lifetime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/33f0fe016ab215c999b565e553fff3719d968092</guid></item><item><title>Framework for predicting the fractionation of complex liquid feeds via polymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2a3bdd685962606f7b818d038486a5bf88771aeb</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2a3bdd685962606f7b818d038486a5bf88771aeb</guid></item><item><title>CO2 Capture Using PIM-1 Hollow Fiber Sorbents with Enhanced Performance by PEI Infusion</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2925cc3d1003725ff2c65728048433e3076d4787</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2925cc3d1003725ff2c65728048433e3076d4787</guid></item><item><title>Zeolite-like performance for xylene isomer purification using polymer-derived carbon membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0c08a8c99f971663fb6723b6443ca4ab31dec1f7</link><description>Significance Xylenes are essential feedstocks for manufacturing packaging materials, versatile chemicals, industrial solvents, etc. The purification of xylene isomers is one of the most important yet energy-intensive organic mixture separations in the chemical industry. We achieved the separation of xylene isomers using carbon molecular sieve (CMS) membranes derived from a spirobifluorene-based polymer of intrinsic microporosity (PIM-SBF), which could potentially reduce the energy consumption, carbon emissions, and equipment footprint. CMS membranes are solvent- and temperature-resistant materials that can withstand high transmembrane pressures when fabricated into the form of hollow fibers. The new CMS membrane produced here shows competitive performance with state-of-the-art zeolites under high xylene loadings, and its development has provided fundamental insight and guidance into the manipulation of CMS pore structure. Polymers of intrinsic microporosity (PIMs) have been used as precursors for the fabrication of porous carbon molecular sieve (CMS) membranes. PIM-1, a prototypical PIM material, uses a fused-ring structure to increase chain rigidity between spirobisindane repeat units. These two factors inhibit effective chain packing, thus resulting in high free volume within the membrane. However, a decrease of pore size and porosity was observed after pyrolytic conversion of PIM-1 to CMS membranes, attributed to the destruction of the spirocenter, which results in the “flattening” of the polymer backbone and graphite-like stacking of carbonaceous strands. Here, a spirobifluorene-based polymer of intrinsic microporosity (PIM-SBF) was synthesized and used to fabricate CMS membranes that showed significant increases in p-xylene permeability (approximately four times), with little loss in p-xylene/o-xylene selectivity (13.4 versus 14.7) for equimolar xylene vapor separations when compared to PIM-1–derived CMS membranes. This work suggests that it is feasible to fabricate such highly microporous CMS membranes with performances that exceed current state-of-the-art zeolites at high xylene loadings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0c08a8c99f971663fb6723b6443ca4ab31dec1f7</guid></item><item><title>Assessing the physical potential capacity of direct air capture with integrated supply of low‐carbon energy sources</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/20b2ad12484439d091ca5c41c10395ac4684c297</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/20b2ad12484439d091ca5c41c10395ac4684c297</guid></item><item><title>Research needs targeting direct air capture of carbon dioxide: Material &amp; process performance characteristics under realistic environmental conditions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/de8b788bd5ec322d3cd4ff4a6c499aac171a9c47</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/de8b788bd5ec322d3cd4ff4a6c499aac171a9c47</guid></item><item><title>A model for the separation of complex liquid mixtures with glassy polymer membranes: A thermodynamic perspective</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9032f55e1dd5bd8fa0727f1bdcbca593d02459a6</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9032f55e1dd5bd8fa0727f1bdcbca593d02459a6</guid></item><item><title>Exemplar Mixtures for Studying Complex Mixture Effects in Practical Chemical Separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1787e7a747672f42093ba9ecc7b7eb5c8d060575</link><description>Materials and processes for chemical separations must be used in complex environments to have an impact in many practical settings. Despite these complexities, much research on chemical separations has focused on idealized chemical mixtures. In this paper, we suggest that research communities for specific chemical separations should develop well-defined exemplar mixtures to bridge the gap between fundamental studies and practical applications and we provide a hierarchical framework of chemical mixtures for this purpose. We illustrate this hierarchy with examples, including CO2 capture, capture of uranium from seawater, and separations of mixtures from electrocatalytic CO2 reactions, among others. We conclude with four recommendations for the research community to accelerate the development of innovative separations strategies for pressing real-world challenges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1787e7a747672f42093ba9ecc7b7eb5c8d060575</guid></item><item><title>Sub-Ambient Temperature Direct Air Capture of CO2 using Amine-Impregnated MIL-101(Cr) Enables Ambient Temperature CO2 Recovery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7dd29cb34daa665e351baf07aa1b25efb67a6f76</link><description>Due to the dramatically increased atmospheric CO2 concentration and consequential climate change, significant effort has been made to develop sorbents to directly capture CO2 from ambient air (direct air capture, DAC) to achieve negative CO2 emissions in the immediate future. However, most developed sorbents have been studied under a limited array of temperature (&gt;20 °C) and humidity conditions. In particular, the dearth of experimental data on DAC at sub-ambient conditions (e.g., −30 to 20 °C) and under humid conditions will severely hinder the large-scale implementation of DAC because the world has annual average temperatures ranging from −30 to 30 °C depending on the location and essentially no place has a zero absolute humidity. To this end, we suggest that understanding CO2 adsorption from ambient air at sub-ambient temperatures, below 20 °C, is crucial because colder temperatures represent important practical operating conditions and because such temperatures may provide conditions where new sorbent materials or enhanced process performance might be achieved. Here we demonstrate that MIL-101(Cr) materials impregnated with amines (TEPA, tetraethylenepentamine, or PEI, poly(ethylenimine)) offer promising adsorption and desorption behavior under DAC conditions in both the presence and absence of humidity under a wide range of temperatures (−20 to 25 °C). Depending on the amine loading and adsorption temperature, the sorbents show different CO2 capture behavior. With 30 and 50 wt % amine loadings, the sorbents show weak and strong chemisorption-dominant CO2 capture behavior, respectively. Interestingly, at −20 °C, the CO2 adsorption capacity of 30 wt % TEPA-impregnated MIL-101(Cr) significantly increased up to 1.12 mmol/g from 0.39 mmol/g at ambient conditions (25 °C) due to the enhanced weak chemisorption. More importantly, the sorbents also show promising working capacities (0.72 mmol/g) over 15 small temperature swing cycles with an ultralow regeneration temperature (−20 °C sorption to 25 °C desorption). The sub-ambient DAC performance of the sorbents is further enhanced under humid conditions, showing promising and stable CO2 working capacities over multiple humid small temperature swing cycles. These results demonstrate that appropriately designed DAC sorbents can operate in a weak chemisorption modality at low temperatures even in the presence of humidity. Significant energy savings may be realized via the utilization of small temperature swings enabled by this weak chemisorption behavior. This work suggests that significant work on DAC materials that operate at low, sub-ambient temperatures is warranted for possible deployment in temperate and polar climates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7dd29cb34daa665e351baf07aa1b25efb67a6f76</guid></item><item><title>A Co-Axial Microtubular Flow Battery Cell with Ultra-high Volumetric Power Density</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f9f4512d7d56f4ebf1a207aa7488bf12c69e4ee</link><description>Volumetric power density is a key factor determining flow batteries' footprint, capital cost and ability to handle uneven energy resource distributions. While significant progress has been made on flow battery materials and electrochemistry to improve energy density, conventional flow battery assemblies based on planar cell configuration exhibit low packing efficiencies and membrane surface area per volume of the cell, thus resulting in low volumetric power density. Here, we introduce a co-axial microtubular (CAMT) flow battery cell that significantly improves the volumetric power density. This cell design overcomes the intrinsic power limit of planar cell configuration and is suitable for all mainstream flow battery chemistries. Using zinc-iodide chemistry as a demonstration, our CAMT cell shows peak charge and discharge power densities of 1322 W/Lcell and 306.1 W/Lcell compared to average charge and discharge power densities of &lt; 60 W/Lcell and 45 W/Lcell of conventional planar flow battery cells. In addition, the battery can cycle for more than 220 hours, corresponding to &gt; 2,500 cycles at off-peak conditions. Furthermore, we have also demonstrated that the CAMT cell is compatible with zinc-bromide, quinone-bromide, and all-vanadium chemistries. The CAMT flow cell represents a device-level innovation to enhance the volumetric power of flow batteries, and potentially reduce the size and cost of the cells and the entire flow battery. The CAMT design can potentially be applied to other electrochemical systems and lead to a paradigm shift in flow battery fundamental study and commercialization.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f9f4512d7d56f4ebf1a207aa7488bf12c69e4ee</guid></item><item><title>Accelerating Solvent Selection for Type II Porous Liquids.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fe22ba66f3bef3e6ab01a7d972c4b730dc1b117d</link><description>Type II porous liquids, comprising intrinsically porous molecules dissolved in a liquid solvent, potentially combine the adsorption properties of porous adsorbents with the handling advantages of liquids. Previously, discovery of appropriate solvents to make porous liquids had been limited to direct experimental tests. We demonstrate an efficient screening approach for this task that uses COSMO-RS calculations, predictions of solvent pKa values from a machine-learning model, and several other features and apply this approach to select solvents from a library of more than 11,000 compounds. This method is shown to give qualitative agreement with experimental observations for two molecular cages, CC13 and TG-TFB-CHEDA, identifying solvents with higher solubility for these molecules than had previously been known. Ultimately, the algorithm streamlines the downselection of suitable solvents for porous organic cages to enable more rapid discovery of Type II porous liquids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fe22ba66f3bef3e6ab01a7d972c4b730dc1b117d</guid></item><item><title>Matching Analysis of Mixed Matrix Membranes for Organic Solvent Reverse Osmosis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5eae274218cb71796fb84f9cf5cc19aa3626519a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5eae274218cb71796fb84f9cf5cc19aa3626519a</guid></item><item><title>Withdrawal notice: The role of skin layer defects in organic solvent reverse osmosis membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c6e657b325a4229023f80046e71517ef2a056883</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c6e657b325a4229023f80046e71517ef2a056883</guid></item><item><title>Co-Transport of Water and P-Xylene Through Carbon Molecular Sieve Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cf1d706165a1b6826e1dd36bf6f3b3e36be31b42</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cf1d706165a1b6826e1dd36bf6f3b3e36be31b42</guid></item><item><title>Tailoring the Structure of Carbon Molecular Sieves Derived from an Aromatic Polyamide</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9828b300efa78fb5b7c42897fa80b0131935578a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9828b300efa78fb5b7c42897fa80b0131935578a</guid></item><item><title>Self-diffusion of mixed xylene isomers in ZIF-71 crystals dispersed in a polymer to form a hybrid membrane</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2c155e135c718ce24a79a6d351ece03096f53b40</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2c155e135c718ce24a79a6d351ece03096f53b40</guid></item><item><title>Scalable Formation of Diamine-Appended Metal–Organic Framework Hollow Fiber Sorbents for Postcombustion CO2 Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bc909de274b88b6b7a8003d6f90095acc1d8031c</link><description>We describe a straightforward and scalable fabrication of diamine-appended metal–organic framework (MOF)/polymer composite hollow fiber sorbent modules for CO2 capture from dilute streams, such as flue gas from natural gas combined cycle (NGCC) power plants. A specific Mg-MOF, Mg2(dobpdc) (dobpdc4– = 4,4′-dioxidobiphenyl-3,3′-dicarboxylate), incorporated into poly(ether sulfone) (PES) is directly spun through a conventional “dry-jet, wet-quench” method. After phase separation, a cyclic diamine 2-(aminomethyl)piperidine (2-ampd) is infused into the MOF within the polymer matrix during postspinning solvent exchange. The MOF hollow fibers from direct spinning contain as high as 70% MOF in the total fibers with 98% of the pure MOF uptake. The resulting fibers exhibit a step isotherm and a “shock-wave-shock” breakthrough profile consistent with pure 2-ampd-Mg2(dobpdc). This work demonstrates a practical method for fabricating 2-ampd-Mg2(dobpdc) fiber sorbents that display the MOF’s high CO2 adsorption capacity while lowering the pressure drop during operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bc909de274b88b6b7a8003d6f90095acc1d8031c</guid></item><item><title>Dry Glass Reference Perturbation Theory Predictions of the Temperature and Pressure Dependent Separations of Complex Liquid Mixtures Using SBAD-1 Glassy Polymer Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c9b7162e6cbdac33a44a1b35d864f689421e1d74</link><description>In this work we apply dry glass reference perturbation theory (DGRPT) within the context of fully mutualized diffusion theory to predict the temperature and pressure dependent separations of complex liquid mixtures using SBAD-1 glassy polymer membranes. We demonstrate that the approach allows for the prediction of the membrane-based separation of complex liquid mixtures over a wide range of temperature and pressure, using only single-component vapor sorption isotherms measured at 25 °C to parameterize the model. The model was then applied to predict the membrane separation of a light shale crude using a structure oriented lumping (SOL) based compositional model of petroleum. It was shown that when DGRPT is applied based on SOL compositions, the combined model allows for the accurate prediction of separation performance based on the trend of both molecular weight and molecular class.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c9b7162e6cbdac33a44a1b35d864f689421e1d74</guid></item><item><title>Effects of trimethylaluminum vapor pressure and exposure time on inorganic loading in vapor phase infiltrated PIM-1 polymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b0d55433dbf91c6f1146c725df18f2bc5dfee824</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b0d55433dbf91c6f1146c725df18f2bc5dfee824</guid></item><item><title>How Reproducible are Surface Areas Calculated from the BET Equation? (Adv. Mater. 27/2022)</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e9283132a7ae59e7295c3eedb2f50864324cb81</link><description>J.R., D.M., and N.R. contributed equally to this work. J.W.M.O. and D.F-J. designed the study. J.W.M.O. and D.M. collected and curated the dataset of isotherms shared among co-authors. J.W.M.O., J.R., N.R., L.S. and B.C. developed BETSI code. All co-authors calculated the BET areas from the pre-measured isotherms. J.W.M.O., D.M., and D.F-J. co-wrote the paper. All authors discussed the results and contributed to the editing of the manuscript.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e9283132a7ae59e7295c3eedb2f50864324cb81</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of Gas Transport in Molecularly-Mixed Composite Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed58651e912180f26a6a385bfe6cde4d6c7803d4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed58651e912180f26a6a385bfe6cde4d6c7803d4</guid></item><item><title>Vapor-Phase Infiltration of Polymer of Intrinsic Microporosity 1 (PIM-1) with Trimethylaluminum (TMA) and Water: A Combined Computational and Experimental Study.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1543bb7a18e85a81b6e03efd2afafdc8cfd039e8</link><description>Vapor-phase infiltration, a postpolymerization modification process, has demonstrated the ability to create organic-inorganic hybrid membranes with excellent stability in organic solvents while maintaining critical membrane properties of high permeability and selectivity. However, the chemical reaction pathways that occur during VPI and their implications on the hybrid membrane stability are poorly understood. This paper combines in situ quartz crystal microbalance gravimetry (QCM) and ex situ chemical characterization with first-principles simulations at the atomic scale to study each processing step in the infiltration of polymer of intrinsic microporosity 1 (PIM-1) with trimethylaluminum (TMA) and its co-reaction with water vapor. Building upon results from in situ QCM experiments and SEM/EDX, which find TMA remains within PIM-1 even under long desorption times, density functional theory (DFT) simulations identify that an energetically stable coordination forms between the metal-organic precursor and PIM-1's nitrile functional group during the precursor exposure step of VPI. In the subsequent water vapor exposure step, the system undergoes a series of exothermic reactions to form the final hybrid membrane. DFT simulations indicate that these reaction pathways result in aluminum oxyhydroxide species consistent with ex situ XPS and FTIR characterization. Both NMR and DFT simulations suggest that the final aluminum structure is primarily 6-fold coordinated and that the aluminum is at least dimerized, if not further "polymerized". According to the simulations, coordination of the aluminum with at least one nitrile group from the PIM-1 appears to weaken significantly as the final inorganic structure emerges but remains present to enable the formation of the 6-fold coordination species. Water molecules are proposed to complete the coordination complex without further increasing the aluminum's oxidation state. This study provides new insights into the infiltration process and the chemical structure of the final hybrid membrane including support for the possible mechanism of solvent stability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1543bb7a18e85a81b6e03efd2afafdc8cfd039e8</guid></item><item><title>Design of Gas Separation Processes Using Type II Porous Liquids as Physical Solvents</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e8688ceef66e835fee1bd17cbc622a34453f21dd</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e8688ceef66e835fee1bd17cbc622a34453f21dd</guid></item><item><title>Cold-Temperature Capture of Carbon Dioxide with Water Coproduction from Air Using Commercial Zeolites</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/23a576524c951f4706b96774ff0ae2dd7e5d2a36</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/23a576524c951f4706b96774ff0ae2dd7e5d2a36</guid></item><item><title>MIL-101(Cr) Polymeric Fiber Adsorbents for Sub-Ambient Post-Combustion CO2 Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d20ad34788755d75def125963ba5a607c3178ab3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d20ad34788755d75def125963ba5a607c3178ab3</guid></item><item><title>Estimation of the Flory-Huggins interaction parameter of polymer-solvent mixtures using machine learning</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ae3e8568492e5d0b51b5b1b1526cd17af3b2c62</link><description>The Flory-Huggins interaction parameter $$\chi$$ χ for polymer-solvent mixtures captures the nature of interactions and provides insights on solubility. $$\chi$$ χ is usually estimated using experimental or (empirical) computational methods, which may be expensive, time-consuming or inaccurate. Here, we built a machine learning (ML) model to instantly predict temperature-dependent $$\chi$$ χ for a given polymer-solvent pair. The ML model was trained using 1586 experimental polymer-solvent datapoints, and a hierarchical polymer and solvent fingerprinting scheme. Extensive testing has been performed to verify the accuracy and generality of this model. This work demonstrates an ML model that can progressively be improved as new data emerges. Graphical Abstract</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ae3e8568492e5d0b51b5b1b1526cd17af3b2c62</guid></item><item><title>Unblocking a rigid purine MOF for kinetic separation of xylenes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34b78c46794e9f25b97a1ecb6b001496e161e5ed</link><description>The separation of xylene isomers still remains an industrially challenging task. Here, porous purine-based metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have been synthesized and studied for their potential in xylene separations. In particular, Zn(purine)I showed excellent para-xylene/ortho-xylene separation capability with a diffusion selectivity of 6 and high equilibrium adsorption selectivity as indicated by coadsorption experiments. This high selectivity is attributed to the shape and size of the channel aperture within the rigid framework of Zn(purine)I.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34b78c46794e9f25b97a1ecb6b001496e161e5ed</guid></item><item><title>Theoretical Pathway toward Improved Reverse Osmosis Membrane Selectivity for Neutral Solutes: Inspiration from Gas Separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/048f33e8dc815420cb28d770095d832e9bb50708</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/048f33e8dc815420cb28d770095d832e9bb50708</guid></item><item><title>A triple-functional carbon molecular sieve (CMS) that addresses the performance trilemma in practical lithium sulfur batteries</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c5e8582833577514df1ac0a3bb28c30ac577b12</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c5e8582833577514df1ac0a3bb28c30ac577b12</guid></item><item><title>Assessment of Acid Gas Adsorption Selectivities in MIL-125-NH2</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/417d3ea31895739d62a7ae1dbecacf416079f665</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/417d3ea31895739d62a7ae1dbecacf416079f665</guid></item><item><title>A submillimeter bundled microtubular flow battery cell with ultrahigh volumetric power density</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db66eb65cd94cb9a732ac3dced1f42e82a2ca34e</link><description>Significance Due to an uneven renewable energy resource distribution and time-dependent fluctuation in energy generation, the harvest, storage, and delivery of renewable energy are crucial to match a rapidly growing demand. Flow batteries are a promising technology for large-scale energy storage and exhibit unparalleled advantages in scalability and design flexibility because of the spatially decoupled energy storage and power conversion units. However, commercial flow batteries are still based on cell configurations developed decades ago. The planar configuration exhibits a large cell size with bulky components for high performance, which results in low volumetric power density, high footprint and capital cost. Step-change decreases in cell size will enable reductions in flow battery capital costs and increase their competitiveness ingrid-level applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db66eb65cd94cb9a732ac3dced1f42e82a2ca34e</guid></item><item><title>Development of Novel Materials for Direct Air Capture of CO2: MIL-101(Cr)-Amine Sorbents Evaluation Under Realistic Direct Air Capture Conditions (Final Report)</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d4514df5a6ba10b3cb498505d03cc5bcae2c2dfc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d4514df5a6ba10b3cb498505d03cc5bcae2c2dfc</guid></item><item><title>Effect of SO2 on the CO2 Capture Performance of Self-Supported Branched Poly(ethyleneimine) Scaffolds</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e01c03b899001e2d0a9a6d9c3601cb4a452de70e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e01c03b899001e2d0a9a6d9c3601cb4a452de70e</guid></item><item><title>Support Pore Structure and Composition Strongly Influence the Direct Air Capture of CO2 on Supported Amines</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2ae65350e42be30fe68ad4e2fb140fca43aefc4</link><description>A variety of amine-impregnated porous solid sorbents for direct air capture (DAC) of CO2 have been developed, yet the effect of amine-solid support interactions on the CO2 adsorption behavior is still poorly understood. When tetraethylenepentamine (TEPA) is impregnated on two different supports, commercial γ-Al2O3 and MIL-101(Cr), they show different trends in CO2 sorption when the temperature (−20 to 25 °C) and humidity (0–70% RH) of the simulated air stream are varied. In situ IR spectroscopy is used to probe the mechanism of CO2 sorption on the two supported amine materials, with weak chemisorption (formation of carbamic acid) being the dominant pathway over MIL-101(Cr)-supported TEPA and strong chemisorption (formation of carbamate) occurring over γ-Al2O3-supported TEPA. Formation of both carbamic acid and carbamate species is enhanced over the supported TEPA materials under humid conditions, with the most significant enhancement observed at −20 °C. However, while equilibrium H2O sorption is high at cold temperatures (e.g., −20 °C), the effect of humidity on a practical cyclic DAC process is expected to be minimal due to slow H2O uptake kinetics. This work suggests that the CO2 capture mechanisms of impregnated amines can be controlled by adjusting the degree of amine-solid support interaction and that H2O adsorption behavior is strongly affected by the properties of the support materials. Thus, proper selection of solid support materials for amine impregnation will be important for achieving optimized DAC performance under varied deployment conditions, such as cold (e.g., −20 °C) or ambient temperature (e.g., 25 °C) operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a2ae65350e42be30fe68ad4e2fb140fca43aefc4</guid></item><item><title>Selective Uptake of Ethane/Ethylene Mixtures by UTSA-280 is Driven by Reversibly Coordinated Water Defects</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/dcf03078ceb422358ca3cf6e8f2f1c661624b13e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/dcf03078ceb422358ca3cf6e8f2f1c661624b13e</guid></item><item><title>Direct evidence of the ultramicroporous structure of carbon molecular sieves</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8571e50c4171160bf6ca1d761fcd16f43004d83d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8571e50c4171160bf6ca1d761fcd16f43004d83d</guid></item><item><title>Structure–Function Relationships in Membrane-Based Hydrocarbon Separations Using N-Aryl-Linked Spirocyclic Polymers</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/313ea48bfabb45039e7ab5ae1f9404260d04a5af</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/313ea48bfabb45039e7ab5ae1f9404260d04a5af</guid></item><item><title>Influence of Polymer Modification on Intra-Mof Self-Diffusion in Mof-Based Mixed Matrix Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0d271df8a541c61658b93664c4a8b5258d86ce2</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f0d271df8a541c61658b93664c4a8b5258d86ce2</guid></item><item><title>Interpreting inorganic compositional depth profiles to understand the rate-limiting step in vapor phase infiltration processes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8a01a5a760d623a47e595454aefd4c725b8d5bca</link><description>Vapor phase infiltration (VPI) is a post-polymerization modification technique that infuses inorganics into polymers to create organic-inorganic hybrid materials with new properties. Much is yet to be understood about the chemical kinetics underlying the VPI process. The aim of this study is to create a greater understanding of the process kinetics that govern the infiltration of trimethyl aluminum (TMA) and TiCl4 into PMMA to form inorganic-PMMA hybrid materials. To gain insight, this paper initially examines the predicted results for the spatiotemporal concentrations of inorganics computed from a recently posited reaction-diffusion model for VPI. This model provides insight on how the Damköhler number (reaction versus diffusion rates) and non-Fickian diffusional processes (hindering) that result from the material transforming from a polymer to a hybrid can affect the evolution of inorganic concentration depth profiles with time. Subsequently, experimental XPS depth profiles are collected for TMA and TiCl4 infiltrated PMMA films at 90 °C and 135 °C. The functional behavior of these depth profiles at varying infiltration times are qualitatively compared to various computed predictions and conclusions are drawn about the mechanisms of each of these processes. TMA infiltration into PMMA appears to transition from a diffusion-limited process at low temperatures (90 °C) to a reaction-limited process at high temperatures (135 °C) for the film thicknesses investigated here (200 nm). While TMA appears to fully infiltrate these 200 nm PMMA films within a few hours, TiCl4 infiltration into PMMA is considerably slower, with full saturation not occurring even after 2 days of precursor exposure. Infiltration at 90 °C is so slow that no clear conclusions about mechanism can be drawn; however, at 135 °C, the TiCl4 infiltration into PMMA is clearly a reaction-limited process, with TiCl4 permeating the entire thickness (at low concentrations) within only a few minutes, but inorganic loading continuously increasing in a uniform manner over a course of 2 days. Near-surface deviations from the uniform-loading expected for a reaction-limited process also suggest that diffusional hindering is high for TiCl4 infiltration into PMMA. These results demonstrate a new, ex situ analysis approach for investigating the rate-limiting process mechanisms for vapor phase infiltration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8a01a5a760d623a47e595454aefd4c725b8d5bca</guid></item><item><title>Chemical Stability of MIL-101(Cr) upon Adsorption of SO2 and NO2 under Dry and Humid Conditions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c85311d2eada08fc42947afba125895b03b0f7ae</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c85311d2eada08fc42947afba125895b03b0f7ae</guid></item><item><title>Sorbent-Coated Carbon Fibers for Direct Air Capture Using Electrically-Driven Temperature Swing Adsorption</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f819fc5a03178ed14e62f7f9acc5bbb513af7a9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f819fc5a03178ed14e62f7f9acc5bbb513af7a9</guid></item><item><title>Selective permeation up a chemical potential gradient to enable an unusual solvent purification modality</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0051b18d95133eac3e68666120e378cf92a7f5aa</link><description>Significance There has been a growing need for separation systems capable of removing or concentrating organic molecules from aqueous streams. We highlight that carbon-based membranes can enable this important preconcentration or removal step. We observe that the transport of the organic through the membrane occurs despite the presence of an unfavorable chemical potential driving force. The experimental observation of steady-state uphill chemical potential permeation without fixed or mobile carriers is unique and challenges conventional membrane transport theories. This observation is reconciled by coupling continuity expressions to models derived for diffusive transport of guests in membrane materials. This new membrane separation modality provides a potentially low-energy method to preconcentrate organic species from an organic–aqueous mixture before further purification via existing technologies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0051b18d95133eac3e68666120e378cf92a7f5aa</guid></item><item><title>Kinetic model describing self-limiting CO2 diffusion in supported amine adsorbents</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/eb5ea5fc3dabd9b16507b7296c8eb5ecb260274d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/eb5ea5fc3dabd9b16507b7296c8eb5ecb260274d</guid></item><item><title>Evaluation of the Permeation of Syngas and Its Components through a Synthesized Matrimid Asymmetric Hollow-Fiber Membrane</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6d0f7aad487e8098d2361d8d83489ebfaac3b19a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6d0f7aad487e8098d2361d8d83489ebfaac3b19a</guid></item><item><title>Thermodynamic Evidence for Type II Porous Liquids</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/890843702fd860cb60524922ab8d12e3eb35d78a</link><description>Porous liquids are an emerging class of microporous materials where intrinsic, stable porosity is imbued in a liquid material. Many porous liquids are prepared by dispersing porous solids in bulky solvents; these can be contrasted by the method of dissolving microporous molecules. We highlight the latter “Type II” porous liquids—which are stable thermodynamic solutions with demonstrable colligative properties. This feature significantly impacts the ultimate utility of the liquid for various end-use applications. We also describe a facile method for determining if a Type II porous liquid candidate is “porous” based on assessing the partial molar volume of the porous host molecule dissolved in the solvent by measuring the densities of candidate solutions. Conventional CO2 isotherms confirm the porosity of the porous liquids and corroborate the facile density method.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/890843702fd860cb60524922ab8d12e3eb35d78a</guid></item><item><title>Solvent and thermally stable polymeric membranes for liquid molecular separations: Recent advances, challenges, and perspectives</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db9a394239ad670ec16fc3bda2a75477f4821e2f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db9a394239ad670ec16fc3bda2a75477f4821e2f</guid></item><item><title>Improved numerical methods for simulating complex mixture transport across asymmetric polymer membranes using a Maxwell-Stefan model</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/432545399109d2b9cfe656a36388c2eb9912cafc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/432545399109d2b9cfe656a36388c2eb9912cafc</guid></item><item><title>Data-driven predictions of complex organic mixture permeation in polymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac40987522631170d6aa1ff9f518dc7ad17c71f2</link><description>Membrane-based organic solvent separations are rapidly emerging as a promising class of technologies for enhancing the energy efficiency of existing separation and purification systems. Polymeric membranes have shown promise in the fractionation or splitting of complex mixtures of organic molecules such as crude oil. Determining the separation performance of a polymer membrane when challenged with a complex mixture has thus far occurred in an ad hoc manner, and methods to predict the performance based on mixture composition and polymer chemistry are unavailable. Here, we combine physics-informed machine learning algorithms (ML) and mass transport simulations to create an integrated predictive model for the separation of complex mixtures containing up to 400 components via any arbitrary linear polymer membrane. We experimentally demonstrate the effectiveness of the model by predicting the separation of two crude oils within 6-7% of the measurements. Integration of ML predictors of diffusion and sorption properties of molecules with transport simulators enables for the rapid screening of polymer membranes prior to physical experimentation for the separation of complex liquid mixtures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac40987522631170d6aa1ff9f518dc7ad17c71f2</guid></item><item><title>Engineering organic solvent reverse osmosis in hybrid AlOxHy / polymer of intrinsic microporosity 1 (PIM-1) membranes using vapor phase infiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/961f6519f5f115ac49c040dfa4db1ece07126560</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/961f6519f5f115ac49c040dfa4db1ece07126560</guid></item><item><title>Organic solvent reverse osmosis separations of hydrocarbon-alcohol mixtures using matrimid membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4fd39f57374d3b9632937a17f8f84906592c75a1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4fd39f57374d3b9632937a17f8f84906592c75a1</guid></item><item><title>Solution-processable polytriazoles from spirocyclic monomers for membrane-based hydrocarbon separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/da8a5c10b53a6c8a305b1c0d0ae53f7cf9529f1c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/da8a5c10b53a6c8a305b1c0d0ae53f7cf9529f1c</guid></item><item><title>Structure–Transport Relationships of Water–Organic Solvent Co-transport in Carbon Molecular Sieve (CMS) Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/04f53a8725383860db0f2f57355ea923a714a55c</link><description>We explore the effects of the carbon molecular sieve (CMS) microstructure on the separation performance and transport mechanism of water–organic mixtures. Specifically, we utilize PIM-1 dense films and integrally skinned asymmetric hollow fiber membranes as polymer precursors for the CMS materials. The PIM-1 membranes were pyrolyzed under several different pyrolysis atmospheres (argon, carbon dioxide, and diluted hydrogen gas) and at multiple pyrolysis temperatures. Detailed gas physisorption measurements reveal that membranes pyrolyzed under 4% H2 and CO2 had broadened ultramicropore distributions (pore diameter &lt;7 Å) compared to Ar pyrolysis, and pyrolysis under CO2 increased ultramicropore volume and broadened micropore distributions at increased pyrolysis temperatures. Gravimetric water and p-xylene sorption and diffusion measurements reveal that the PIM-1-derived CMS materials are more hydrophilic than other CMS materials that have been previously studied, which leads to sorption-diffusion estimations showing water-selective permeation. Water permeation in the vapor phase, pervaporation, and liquid-phase hydraulic permeation reveal that the isobaric permeation modes (vapor permeation and pervaporation) are reasonably well predicted by the sorption-diffusion model, whereas the hydraulic permeation mode is significantly underpredicted (&gt;250×). Conversely, the permeation of p-xylene is well predicted by the sorption-diffusion model in all cases. The collection of pore size analysis, vapor sorption and diffusion, and permeation in different modalities creates a picture of a combined transport mechanism in which water—under high transmembrane pressures—permeates via a Poiseuille-style mechanism, whereas p-xylene solutes in the mixture permeate via sorption-diffusion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/04f53a8725383860db0f2f57355ea923a714a55c</guid></item><item><title>Amine-functionalized MIL-101(Cr) fibers for direct air capture at cold temperatures using rapid temperature vacuum swing adsorption</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b7f1b67cbf4e8f485b1f6e14b321c1600985e92c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b7f1b67cbf4e8f485b1f6e14b321c1600985e92c</guid></item><item><title>Optimum relative humidity enhances CO2 uptake in Diamine-Appended M2(dobpdc)</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1329266850c619edd679efa3033ed2983484ed6f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1329266850c619edd679efa3033ed2983484ed6f</guid></item><item><title>Click-chemistry polymer membranes for hydrocarbon mixture fractionation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db985f3556f8a699b0894eb06d414c1f1a974121</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/db985f3556f8a699b0894eb06d414c1f1a974121</guid></item><item><title>Cold Temperature Direct Air CO2 Capture with Amine-Loaded Metal–Organic Framework Monoliths</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bcdd0cc02cb34706e53eaf9d7989ec8f18e6e1c1</link><description>Zeolites, silica-supported amines, and metal–organic frameworks (MOFs) have been demonstrated as promising adsorbents for direct air CO2 capture (DAC), but the shaping and structuring of these materials into sorbent modules for practical processes have been inadequately investigated compared to the extensive research on powder materials. Furthermore, there have been relatively few studies reporting the DAC performance of sorbent contactors under cold, subambient conditions (temperatures below 20 °C). In this work, we demonstrate the successful fabrication of adsorbent monoliths composed of cellulose acetate (CA) and adsorbent particles such as zeolite 13X and MOF MIL-101(Cr) by a 3D printing technique: solution-based additive manufacturing (SBAM). These monoliths feature interpenetrated macroporous polymeric frameworks in which microcrystals of zeolite 13X or MIL-101(Cr) are evenly distributed, highlighting the versatility of SBAM in fabricating monoliths containing sorbents with different particle sizes and density. Branched poly(ethylenimine) (PEI) is successfully loaded into the CA/MIL-101(Cr) monoliths to impart CO2 uptakes of 1.05 mmol gmonolith–1 at −20 °C and 400 ppm of CO2. Kinetic analysis shows that the CO2 sorption kinetics of PEI-loaded MIL-101(Cr) sorbents are not compromised in the monoliths compared to the powder sorbents. Importantly, these monoliths exhibit promising working capacities (0.95 mmol gmonolith–1) over 14 temperature swing cycles with a moderate regeneration temperature of 60 °C. Dynamic breakthrough experiments at 25 °C under dry conditions reveal a CO2 uptake capacity of 0.60 mmol gmonolith–1, which further increases to 1.05 and 1.43 mmol gmonolith–1 at −20 °C under dry and humid (70% relative humidity) conditions, respectively. Our work showcases the successful implementation of SBAM in making DAC sorbent monoliths with notable CO2 capture performance over a wide range of sorption temperatures, suggesting that SBAM can enable the preparation of efficient sorbent contactors in various form factors for other important chemical separations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bcdd0cc02cb34706e53eaf9d7989ec8f18e6e1c1</guid></item><item><title>Alumina Incorporation in Self-Supported Poly(ethylenimine) Sorbents for Direct Air Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/adfea5ecb585b66f51d41bd5a15de5f6d17e0cab</link><description>Self-supported branched poly(ethylenimine) scaffolds with ordered macropores are synthesized with and without Al2O3 powder additive by cross-linking poly(ethylenimine) (PEI) with poly(ethylene glycol) diglycidyl ether (PEGDGE) at −196 °C. The scaffolds’ CO2 uptake performance is compared with a conventional sorbent, i.e., PEI impregnated on an Al2O3 support. PEI scaffolds with Al2O3 additive show narrow pore size distribution and thinner pore walls than alumina-free materials, facilitating higher CO2 uptake at conditions relevant to direct air capture. The PEI scaffold containing 6.5 wt % Al2O3 had the highest CO2 uptake of 1.23 mmol/g of sorbent under 50% RH 400 ppm of CO2 conditions. In situ DRIFT spectroscopy and temperature-programmed desorption experiments show a significant CO2 uptake contribution via physisorption as well as carbamic acid formation, with lower CO2 binding energies in PEI scaffolds relative to conventional PEI sorbents, likely a result of a lower population of primary amines due to the amine cross-linking reactions during scaffold synthesis. The PEI scaffold containing 6.5 wt % Al2O3 is estimated to have the lowest desorption energy penalty under humid conditions, 4.6 GJ/tCO2, among the sorbents studied.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/adfea5ecb585b66f51d41bd5a15de5f6d17e0cab</guid></item><item><title>Solid-state crosslinking of thin film composite membranes for organic solvent reverse osmosis separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f7f382e936a56923381cb97f34ca3f5250f0c590</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f7f382e936a56923381cb97f34ca3f5250f0c590</guid></item><item><title>Water management and heat integration in direct air capture systems</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bdc4fce77c37f371d13946bbaf6ebda565881f76</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bdc4fce77c37f371d13946bbaf6ebda565881f76</guid></item><item><title>Membrane separation of cyclic siloxanes from silicone fluid</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6eb57d127566aa391c1f1a340f2166f71f714e65</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6eb57d127566aa391c1f1a340f2166f71f714e65</guid></item><item><title>Guanidine-Functionalized PIM-1 as a High-Capacity Polymeric Sorbent for CO2 Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/74f117ddae9d816b84c114b4283be95b2556e911</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/74f117ddae9d816b84c114b4283be95b2556e911</guid></item><item><title>Investigating the Effect of Trace Levels of Manganese Ions During Solvothermal Synthesis of Massey University Framework-16 on CO2 Uptake Capacity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f39f4530e902743de88d53d4b85077ee5574879</link><description>The effects of impurities on reaction precursors for metal–organic framework (MOF) synthesis have not been studied in extensive detail. The impact of these impurities can be an important factor while considering scale-up of these materials. In this work, we study the apparently positive impact of the presence of manganese ions for the synthesis of a Co-based MOF, Massey University Framework-16 (MUF-16). The presence of a trace amount of manganese in the reaction mixture led to consistently high CO2 uptake across multiple batches. Characterization including X-ray diffraction, scanning electron microscopy, Fourier transform infrared-attenuated total reflectance, ultraviolet–visible spectroscopy, thermogravimetric analysis, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and extended X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy led us to hypothesize that the differences in CO2 adsorption among materials with differing synthesis routes arise from variations in the local environment around the cobalt metal center. Aided by density functional theory calculations, we speculate that manganese ions get inserted into the structure during crystallization and act as catalysts for ligand substitution, improving the possibility for octahedral coordination of cobalt with the ligand, thus leading to Co-based pristine structures with higher CO2 uptakes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f39f4530e902743de88d53d4b85077ee5574879</guid></item><item><title>Electrocatalysis in Solid Oxide Fuel Cells and Electrolyzers.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/72c6412ca8f957674320561d3883a3e904b03228</link><description>Interest in energy-to-X and X-to-energy (where X represents green hydrogen, carbon-based fuels, or ammonia) technologies has expanded the field of electrochemical conversion and storage. Solid oxide electrochemical cells (SOCs) are among the most promising technologies for these processes. Their unmatched conversion efficiencies result from favorable thermodynamics and kinetics at elevated operating temperatures (400-900 °C). These solid-state electrochemical systems exhibit flexibility in reversible operation between fuel cell and electrolysis modes and can efficiently utilize a variety of fuels. However, electrocatalytic materials at SOC electrodes remain nonoptimal for facilitating reversible operation and fuel flexibility. In this Review, we explore the diverse range of electrocatalytic materials utilized in oxygen-ion-conducting SOCs (O-SOCs) and proton-conducting SOCs (H-SOCs). We examine their electrochemical activity as a function of composition and structure across different electrochemical reactions to highlight characteristics that lead to optimal catalytic performance. Catalyst deactivation mechanisms under different operating conditions are discussed to assess the bottlenecks in performance. We conclude by providing guidelines for evaluating the electrochemical performance of electrode catalysts in SOCs and for designing effective catalysts to achieve flexibility in fuel usage and mode of operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/72c6412ca8f957674320561d3883a3e904b03228</guid></item><item><title>CO2 Uptake and Stability Enhancement in Vinyltrimethoxysilane-Treated SBA-15 Solid Amine-Based Sorbents.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/806b22502c5dc8beaf937896bbf17c921027776b</link><description>Silica-supported amine absorbents, including materials produced by tethering aminosilanes or infusion of poly(ethyleneimine), represent a promising class of materials for CO2 capture applications, including direct air and point source capture. Various silica surface treatments and functionalization strategies are explored to enhance stability and CO2 uptake in amine-based solid sorbent systems. Here, the synthesis and characterization of novel vinyltrimethoxysilane-treated Santa Barbara Amorphous-15 (SBA-15) supports and the corresponding enhancement in CO2 uptake compared to various SBA-15-based control supports are presented. The relationship between CO2 diffusion and amine efficiency in these systems is explored using a previously reported kinetic model. The synthesized materials are characterized with CO2 and H2O isotherms, diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy, 1H T1-T2 relaxation correlation NMR, and rapid thermal cycling experiments. The novel support materials are shown to enable high amine efficiencies, approaching a fourfold improvement over standard SBA-15-supported amines, while simultaneously exhibiting excellent stability when cycled rapidly under humid conditions. As the poly(ethyleneimine) loadings are held constant across the various samples, enhancements in CO2 uptake are attributed to differences in the way the poly(ethyleneimine) interacts with the support surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/806b22502c5dc8beaf937896bbf17c921027776b</guid></item><item><title>A transition in diffusion behaviors of organic liquid mixtures in dense polymer membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cfdfec06dbd915c0164c590428da93a8cad527ca</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/cfdfec06dbd915c0164c590428da93a8cad527ca</guid></item><item><title>Open and FAIR data for nanofiltration in organic media: A unified approach</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c3324fab3378afd3cad4c2b47c2d3ab2e508f0c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9c3324fab3378afd3cad4c2b47c2d3ab2e508f0c</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation of Pore Structure for Increased CO2 Selectivity in Type 3 Porous Liquids.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e4f7f4dfdb4eaa6562bde9484014986475d6bcc6</link><description>CO2 capture requires materials with high adsorption selectivity and an industrial ease of implementation. To address these needs, a new class of porous materials was recently developed that combines the fluidity of solvents with the porosity of solids. Type 3 porous liquids (PLs) composed of solvents and metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) offer a promising alternative to current liquid carbon capture methods due to the inherent tunability of the nanoporous MOFs. However, the effects of MOF structural features and solvent properties on CO2-MOF interactions within PLs are not well understood. Herein experimental and computational data of CO2 gas adsorption isotherms were used to elucidate both solvent and pore structure influences on ZIF-based PLs. The roles of the pore structure including solvent size exclusion, structural environment, and MOF porosity on PL CO2 uptake were examined. A comparison of the pore structure and pore aperture was performed using ZIF-8, ZIF-L, and amorphous-ZIF-8. Adsorption experiments here have verified our previously proposed solvent size design principle for ZIF-based PLs (1.8× ZIF pore aperture). Furthermore, the CO2 adsorption isotherms of the ZIF-based PLs indicated that judicious selection of the pore environment allows for an increase in CO2 selectivity greater than expected from the individual PL components or their combination. This nonlinear increase in the CO2 selectivity is an emergent behavior resulting from the complex mixture of components specific to the ZIF-L + 2'-hydroxyacetophenone-based PL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e4f7f4dfdb4eaa6562bde9484014986475d6bcc6</guid></item><item><title>Humidity Effects on Sub-Ambient Direct Air Capture of CO2 with Amine Functionalized Mg-Al LDHs and MMOs</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fd79471100d48e5757f00688d8ace6f241ed87c8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fd79471100d48e5757f00688d8ace6f241ed87c8</guid></item><item><title>Techno-Economic Analysis of a Carbon Molecular Sieve-Based Xylene Isomer Purification Process</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/09e2c8fee5f61a9cfe47ef3ffd1c46c58b70344e</link><description>The separation and purification of xylene isomers is critical to the production of polyethylene terephthalate (PET). These separations are complex to operate and demand tremendous amounts of energy and thus are an opportunity for reducing industrial energy consumption. Membranes provide a low-energy footprint technology with simpler operation, and recently, membrane materials have been developed that are capable of separating xylene isomers. While these materials have demonstrated the ability to separate xylenes, they have yet to be commercially deployed. This work conducts a techno-economic analysis (TEA) to provide insight on the commercial attractiveness of a p-xylene selective carbon molecular sieve (CMS) membrane from both a cost and energy standpoint. This TEA was conducted through the pairing of a Maxwell–Stefan transport framework for rigid microporous materials with process modeling. Single-stage organic solvent reverse osmosis (OSRO) and pervaporation processes were used to evaluate the effects of recovery, selectivity, and diffusivity on the energy intensity and cost of the xylene separation. The final analysis used two systems, a single pervaporation stage followed by two OSRO stages, which was compared against a three-stage OSRO cascade. These were benchmarked against the commercial Parex process. We estimate that the membrane processes have the potential to enable impressive cost savings compared to the Parex process. While both systems outperformed the Parex process in terms of cost, the pervaporation/OSRO hybrid process was able to achieve the lowest cost of all due to its reduced membrane surface area compared to standalone OSRO. These findings demonstrate the potential of membrane systems in the field of difficult small molecule solvent separations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/09e2c8fee5f61a9cfe47ef3ffd1c46c58b70344e</guid></item><item><title>Fractionation of complex aromatic hydrocarbon mixtures using membrane cascades hybridized with distillation</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e794435bc0686c0b4b5fa062901a67542f8593a8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e794435bc0686c0b4b5fa062901a67542f8593a8</guid></item><item><title>Carbon and oxygen recycling strategies in CO2-to-sustainable synthetic fuel production: Recycling route, techno-economics and carbon intensity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/710db18894df01c3c9eb8e754c8b907d512637be</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/710db18894df01c3c9eb8e754c8b907d512637be</guid></item><item><title>Fiber Sorbents – A Versatile Platform for Sorption-Based Gas Separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6bde3eaabb9cd5da3d90e71fcbf3b1464cdc3376</link><description>Conspectus Increasing demand for high-purity fine chemicals and a drive for process intensification of large-scale separations have driven significant work on the development of highly engineered porous materials with promise for sorption-based separations. While sorptive separations in porous materials offer energy-efficient alternatives to longstanding thermal-based methods, the particulate nature of many of these sorbents has sometimes limited their large-scale deployment in high-throughput applications such as gas separations, for which the necessary high feed flow rates and gas velocities accrue prohibitive operational costs. These processability limitations have been historically addressed through powder shaping methods aimed at the fabrication of structured sorbent contactors based on pellets, beads or monoliths, commonly obtained as extrudates. These structures overcome limitations such as elevated pressure drops commonly recorded across powder adsorption beds but often accrue thermal limitations arising from elevated particle density and aggregation, which ultimately cap their maximum separation performance. Furthermore, the harsh mechanical strain to which powder particles are subjected during contactor fabrication, in the form of extrusion/compression forces, can result in partial pore occlusion and framework degradation, further limiting their performance. Here, we present the development of porous fiber sorbents as an alternative sorbent contactor design capable of addressing sorbent processability limitations while enabling an array of performance-maximizing heat integration capabilities. This new sorbent form factor leverages pre-existing know-how from hollow fiber spinning to produce fiber-shaped sorbent contactors through the phase inversion of known polymers in a process known as dry-jet/wet quenching. The process of phase inversion allows microporous sorbent particles to be latched onto a macroporous polymer matrix under mild processing conditions, thus making it compatible with soft porous materials prone to amorphization under traditional pelletization conditions. Sorbent fibers can be created with different geometries through control of the spinning apparatus and process, offering the possibility to produce monolithic and hollow fibers alike, the latter of which can be integrated with thermalization fluid flows. In this Account, we summarize our progress in the field of fiber sorbents from both design and application standpoints. We further guide the reader through the evolution of this field from the early inceptive work on zeolite hollow fibers to recent developments on MOF fibers. We highlight the versatile nature of fiber sorbents, both from the composition, fabrication and structure points of view, and further demonstrate how fiber sorbents offer alternative paths in tackling new and challenging chemical separation challenges like direct air capture (DAC), with a final perspective on the future of the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6bde3eaabb9cd5da3d90e71fcbf3b1464cdc3376</guid></item><item><title>Fluorine-rich poly(arylene amine) membranes for the separation of liquid aliphatic compounds.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e46833bc9672ad2198c6e0b2365a1e1dd0685ad2</link><description>We explored the potential for membrane materials to reduce energy and carbon requirements for the separation of aliphatic hydrocarbon feedstocks and products. We developed a series of fluorine-rich poly(arylene amine) polymer membranes that feature rigid polymer backbones with segregated perfluoroalkyl side chains. This combination imbues the polymers with resistance to dilation induced by hydrocarbon immersion without the loss of solution-based membrane fabrication techniques. These materials exhibit good separation of liquid-phase alkane isomers at ambient temperatures. The integration of these polymeric membranes into fuel and chemical feedstock separation processes was investigated in a series of experiments. Technoeconomic analyses based on these experiments indicate that the best-performing membrane materials can substantially reduce the energy costs and associated carbon emissions of hydrocarbon separations (two to 10 times, depending on product specifications).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e46833bc9672ad2198c6e0b2365a1e1dd0685ad2</guid></item><item><title>Polymer‐Sorbent Direct Air Capture Contactors with Complex Geometries 3D‐Printed via Templated Phase Inversion</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/744afe5f22b1c42944eb1b2ec2add34d331b4b35</link><description>Low‐cost direct air capture (DAC) systems require efficient gas–solid contactors. These contactors provide rapid rates of heat and mass transport with minimal pressure drops. Triply periodic minimal surfaces (TPMS) are a class of geometries that are shown to have heat transfer properties that exceed those of other geometries, and these benefits are expected to manifest in mass transfer as well due to the analogies between heat and mass transfer. However, creating TPMS contactors is difficult using conventional manufacturing techniques such as injection molding. Non‐solvent‐induced phase separation (NIPS) of a polymeric ink containing the adsorbent is one way to construct adsorption contactors with excellent mass transport rates, but contactors have to date only been fabricated in simple geometries (e.g., films, fibers). This study demonstrates that NIPS of polymeric inks occurs within a simultaneously‐dissolving, water‐soluble, 3D‐printed template. This templated phase inversion (TPI) technique can create seemingly unlimited macroscopic architectures, including TPMS contactors, using a variety of potential DAC adsorbents, including zeolite, silica, activated carbon, and metal–organic frameworks. SEM, micro‐computed tomography, and nitrogen adsorption experiments reveal the microscopic pore structures and macroscopic geometries of the resulting sorbent contactors. TPMS DAC contactors with poly(ethyleneimine)/silica adsorbents are shown to have CO2 capture performances that rival or exceed other contactor geometries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/744afe5f22b1c42944eb1b2ec2add34d331b4b35</guid></item><item><title>Self-Supported Branched Poly(ethylenimine) Monoliths from Inverse Template 3D Printing for Direct Air Capture</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2b91f521bcaaa60d0c9ae2f57ac6514a4d95cef0</link><description>3D-printed inverse templates are combined with ice templating to develop self-supported branched poly(ethylenimine) monoliths with regular channels of varying channel density and ordered macropores. A maximum uptake of 0.96 mmol of CO2/g of monolith from ambient air containing 45.5% RH is achieved from dynamic breakthrough experiments, which is a 31% increase compared to the CO2 uptake from adsorption under dry conditions for the same duration. The breakthrough experiments show characteristics of internal mass-transfer limitations. The cyclic dynamic breakthrough experiments indicate stable operation without significant loss in CO2 uptake across eight cycles. Moreover, the self-supported monolith shows minimal loss in adsorption capacity (7.7%) upon exposure to air containing 21% oxygen at 110 °C, in comparison to a conventional sorbent consisting of poly(ethylenimine) impregnated on Al2O3 (18.9%). The monoliths exhibit good mechanical stability, contributed by elastic deformation, corresponding to up to 74% strain and lower pressure drop compared to many existing monoliths in the literature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2b91f521bcaaa60d0c9ae2f57ac6514a4d95cef0</guid></item><item><title>Structurally Driven Selective Adsorption of Hydrocarbons by Metal Substitution in Isostructural Rare-Earth Metal–Organic Frameworks</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0974508e2c25d398ec8b989e48fdb4fa268b8417</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0974508e2c25d398ec8b989e48fdb4fa268b8417</guid></item><item><title>Nonadditive CO2 Uptake of Type II Porous Liquids Based on Imine Cages</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fa0df06d0518d1924fff32e143e2bf42a7111a25</link><description>Type II porous liquids can potentially exploit the fluidity of liquids and sorption properties of porous sorbents, yet CO2 uptake in porous liquids is still poorly understood. Molecular simulations and experiments are used to examine CO2 uptake by a prototypical porous liquid composed of porous organic cages (CC13) in 2′‐hydroxyacetophenone (2′‐HAP). The simulations are in reasonable agreement with experimental measurements of CO2 solubility and provide unambiguous information on the partitioning of CO2 within microenvironments in the liquid. Analysis of CO2 dynamics is performed using these simulations, including assessing the self‐diffusivity of CO2 in both the neat solvent and porous liquid. This offers insights into the kinetics of CO2 uptake and transport in type II porous liquids based on imine cages. Experiments with type II porous liquids formed by dissolving CC13 in three different size‐excluded solvents show nonadditive CO2 absorption relative to predictions based on ideal volume additivity. This nonadditive absorption behavior is also observed in simulations. Nonadditive CO2 uptake is also demonstrated in type II porous liquids based on another imine‐based porous cage, CC19.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fa0df06d0518d1924fff32e143e2bf42a7111a25</guid></item><item><title>Investigation of Moisture Swing Adsorbents for Direct Air Capture by Dynamic Breakthrough Studies</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/949d181a4b1533f31ff90a4335237fa2e80873f7</link><description>Adsorbent materials with humidity-modulated CO2 sorption capacities are essential for direct air capture (DAC) based on moisture swing adsorption (MSA) processes. These materials have seldom been studied in the context of dynamic breakthrough experiments despite their efficacy in providing valuable equilibrium and kinetics information on the adsorbents and their resemblance to practical processes at large scales. Herein, we performed a series of breakthrough experiments to systematically investigate the DAC properties of the MSA adsorbent IRA-900-C. Prepared from the commercially available anion exchange resin IRA-900 (chloride form), IRA-900-C exhibits a CO2 capacity of 1.92 mmol g–1 at 20% RH at 25 °C. The CO2 uptake capacity in IRA-900-C decreases as the environmental relative humidity (RH) increases at constant temperature. The competitive sorption behavior of CO2 and H2O is also revealed by humid CO2 breakthrough experiments. Breakthrough experiments with different gas velocities and particle sizes of IRA-900-C suggest that the CO2 adsorption kinetics in IRA-900-C is controlled by internal mass transfer resistances under DAC conditions. A theoretical maximum CO2 working capacity of 1.27 mmol g–1 can be achieved with IRA-900-C by swinging the RH from 20 to 50% RH at 25 °C along with constant purge of inert gas, and the feasibility of CO2 production in a vacuum is experimentally verified. This study highlights the significance of dynamic breakthrough experiments in evaluating the DAC performance of MSA sorbents and providing valuable information for the design and optimization of DAC systems enabled by moisture swing processes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/949d181a4b1533f31ff90a4335237fa2e80873f7</guid></item><item><title>Effect of Amines on MIL-101(Cr) for Simultaneous H2S/CO2 Removal from Biogas</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1fe9f3bd380db2a1733103490f384fd7831c03ee</link><description>Production of biomethane from raw biogas requires the removal of impurities, such as CO2 and H2S. To accommodate the variety of biogas sources, a modular separation design with a small footprint is desired. In this work, we report three diamine-impregnated metal–organic frameworks (MOFs), MIL-101(Cr) (diamines: diethylethylenediamine, ee-2; 2,2-dimethyl-1,3-propanediamine, dmpn; N-methylethylenediamine, m-2) for simultaneous removal of H2S and CO2 from simulated binary and ternary biogas mixtures. The H2S and CO2 separation performance and regeneration conditions were investigated by dynamic column breakthrough and temperature-programmed desorption experiments. While all three diamine-impregnated MIL-101(Cr) samples were H2S-selective over CO2 in the mixture compositions studied, MIL-101(Cr)-ee-2 displayed the highest H2S/CO2 adsorption selectivity of ∼7. Also, it showed distinct desorption temperatures for H2S and CO2 that allows for concentrated H2S collection during adsorbent regeneration, which can potentially simplify the biogas separation process to achieve concentrated biomethane and H2S collection using the same adsorption module.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1fe9f3bd380db2a1733103490f384fd7831c03ee</guid></item><item><title>Modifying Inorganic Structure through Hydration in Vapor Phase Infiltrated AlO x H y ‑PIM‑1 Hybrid Membranes: Implications for Solvent Stability, Permeance, and Selectivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d8ba0346fb615a6b3b5e3f9583a0909a4f6a8151</link><description>Vapor-phase infiltration (VPI) presents a promising approach to enhancing the stability of organic membranes in organic solvents while maintaining critical properties, such as membrane permeance and selectivity. However, the precise chemical structure of the infiltrated inorganics and their impact on solvent stability remain poorly understood, limiting efforts to improve VPI treated hybrid membrane technology for organic solvent reverse osmosis (OSRO). This study uses X-ray absorption spectroscopy alongside X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) to elucidate the inorganic cluster structure within PIM-1/AlO x H y . By analyzing the H2O ratio via XPS and assessing the first and second shell Al coordination numbers from Al K-edge extended X-ray absorption fine structure (EXAFS) spectroscopy, we propose that aluminum oxyhydroxide tends to form nonlinear networked structures. X-ray absorption near-edge spectroscopy (XANES) analysis confirms a predominantly six-coordinate structure in the first shell, while EXAFS analysis of the second shell reveals the presence of three aluminum atoms, suggesting clusters significantly larger than simple dimers or trimers, similar to larger aluminum hydroxide and oxyhydroxide crystal structures. Furthermore, we demonstrate that postprocessing techniques, such as dehydration and rehydration, can be utilized to control this network structure and membrane permeance and selectivity without compromising solvent stability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d8ba0346fb615a6b3b5e3f9583a0909a4f6a8151</guid></item><item><title>Correction for “Structure–Transport Relationships of Water–Organic Solvent Co-transport in Carbon Molecular Sieve (CMS) Membranes”</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2b57e139645fbbeca593c4d693c3708f98ef91b9</link><description>[This corrects the article DOI: 10.1021/acs.iecr.3c02519.].</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2b57e139645fbbeca593c4d693c3708f98ef91b9</guid></item><item><title>Performance Degradation of Amine-Infused Fiber Sorbents for Direct Air Capture: Mechanisms and Solutions</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e82dac5b26ebdfb157b15a2f7239e80121a7664a</link><description>Sorbent stability poses significant impacts on long-term performance of direct air capture (DAC) of CO2 and levelized cost of capture (LCOC). We report the DAC performance degradation of amine-infused fiber sorbents based on poly(ethylenimine) (PEI), mesoporous SiO2, and cellulose acetate (CA) over CO2 cyclic sorption cycles in a nonoxidative environment. Infrared and nuclear magnetic resonance spectra indicate that the aminolysis reactions between CA ester moieties and PEI amine sites lead to the formation of acetamides and hence lower CO2 affinities of the sorbents. This stability issue can be remedied by hydrolysis treatment of the CA fiber sorbents before PEI impregnation or replacing CA with poly(ether sulfone). This study underscores the importance of selecting proper support or additive materials of DAC contactors that are compatible with active species of CO2 capture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e82dac5b26ebdfb157b15a2f7239e80121a7664a</guid></item><item><title>Inorganic chemistry, cluster formation and solvent stability of PIM-1/ZnOxHy hybrid membranes synthesized via vapor phase infiltration.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c99636db1cc7178cc3be9cadba6010faddb1e1af</link><description>Vapor phase infiltration (VPI) is a vapor processing technique that converts polymers into organic-inorganic hybrid materials with modified properties. VPI of polymer membranes stabilizes against dissolution and swelling in organic liquids, opening up new opportunities for use in organic solvent reverse osmosis (OSRO) separations. However, the precise chemical structure of the infiltrated inorganic components remains poorly understood, limiting the potential to fully exploit process-structure-property relations for materials design and slowing the development of new hybrid membranes. This study explores the structural characteristics contributing to the chemical stability of PIM-1/ZnOxHy hybrid membranes through advanced spectroscopic techniques to clarify the chemistry and inorganic cluster formation in these materials that lead to enhanced stability in solvents that otherwise swell or dissolve the pure polymer. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) indicates a predominantly zinc hydroxide chemistry with higher proportions of oxide forming only at increasing cycle counts. Extended X-ray absorption fine structure (EXAFS) spectroscopy provides new understanding of the first and second coordination shells. These results indicate that the size of the clusters increases with prolonged VPI precursor exposure and additional VPI cycles, leading to improvements in membrane solvent stability. These findings offer a new understanding for how the physicochemical structure of these hybrid membranes can be characterized and then used to design for a desired performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c99636db1cc7178cc3be9cadba6010faddb1e1af</guid></item><item><title>Prediction-based trade-off analysis of polymer membranes for organic solvent reverse osmosis of hydrocarbons</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/80f95452d22c0d3a7ccc86adc7cdcb4df8796165</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/80f95452d22c0d3a7ccc86adc7cdcb4df8796165</guid></item><item><title>Independent Experimental Measurements of Diffusion, Sorption, and Permeability Support the Solution-Diffusion Model of Membrane Transport</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1078c82cb440c14f6ac244cd3d5931c51ccf0c77</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1078c82cb440c14f6ac244cd3d5931c51ccf0c77</guid></item><item><title>Diffusion-based evidence for hyperskin in CMS membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/eddee0d9b6d197e4d9def11e32535cd15c567650</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/eddee0d9b6d197e4d9def11e32535cd15c567650</guid></item><item><title>Prediction-driven selection of microporous polymer membranes for organic solvent reverse osmosis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/afb3d3a1970d3c5380e60636a0ede586e981ad82</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/afb3d3a1970d3c5380e60636a0ede586e981ad82</guid></item><item><title>Simulated Moving Bed Process for CO2 Capture from Humid Postcombustion Flue Gases Using MUF-16</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b9b904479d07babe1da1c4db461b5b6bf5fe0287</link><description>Simulated moving bed (SMB) designs are increasingly being adapted for the separation of multicomponent gaseous mixtures. In this work, we develop a modified SMB process for capturing CO2 from humid postcombustion flue gas using MUF-16 (MUF = Massey University Framework). MUF-16 shows excellent selectivity for CO2 over N2, moderate heats of adsorption for CO2 and H2O, and no competitive sorption of CO2 over water at relative humidities relevant to postcombustion capture. We utilize these characteristics to propose a continuous process that uses N2 from the feed as the desorbent for the water, eliminating the need for a separate desiccant bed and allowing for localized heating during desorption for H2O-saturated MOF beds. Single-component isotherms, single-column breakthrough experiments, and SO2 stability tests suggest the excellent suitability of MUF-16 to this separation via the proposed SMB design.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b9b904479d07babe1da1c4db461b5b6bf5fe0287</guid></item><item><title>Electrically Conductive Amine Functionalized Reduced Graphite Oxide Foam for CO2 Removal from the Air</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4b77f9dce4000899eb02cb323d06a75bf83676d5</link><description>Rapid regeneration of CO2 adsorbents is critical to improving the productivity of direct air capture (DAC) systems. In this study, we codesigned a material to have appropriate electrical conductivity and CO2 adsorption properties to enable efficient CO2 capture from air. Specifically, we present a poly(ethylenimine) (PEI)-impregnated thermally annealed graphite oxide (TAGO900) foam adsorbent tailored for vacuum-assisted electrically driven thermal swing adsorption (V-ETSA). This structured adsorbent leverages the high electrical conductivity of the reduced graphite oxide framework to enable fast and direct heating of the adsorbent material by electrical resistance heating (Joule heating). An optimal sample, 40 wt % PEI (molecular weight 25k) impregnated TAGO900, shows the best balance between adsorption capacity (1.54 mmol g–1) and adsorption rates (0.016 mmol g–1 min–1) using fixed bed breakthrough experiments at 25 °C and 70% RH using 50 sccm 400 ppm of CO2/N2 flow. Compared to conventional temperature vacuum swing adsorption (TVSA), the V-ETSA approach achieves substantially faster CO2 desorption, achieving average desorption rates (including cooling time) of 0.09 mmol g–1 min–1approximately 2.5 times faster than TVSA under similar operating conditions. The maximum desorption rate reaches 0.23 mmol/g/min during the desorption stage. These results underscore the importance of the direct heating strategy, such as Joule heating, for fast and highly productive vacuum swing adsorption in DAC systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4b77f9dce4000899eb02cb323d06a75bf83676d5</guid></item><item><title>The unusual transport of phenolic compounds through poly(triazole) membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ea7a5c1901d96e448ed13eba5df181f3a63ee5a3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ea7a5c1901d96e448ed13eba5df181f3a63ee5a3</guid></item><item><title>Lignin/Graphene Oxide Membrane for Sorpvection-Driven Butanol Recovery</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8c567e6d0b02c8b8b820d769d9cdbd3d4daf9f7c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8c567e6d0b02c8b8b820d769d9cdbd3d4daf9f7c</guid></item><item><title>Analysis of uphill diffusion of CO2 driven by the chemical potential difference of H2O</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/49616b7bb35bab2805759a366399e25d21e3cfa5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/49616b7bb35bab2805759a366399e25d21e3cfa5</guid></item><item><title>Sub-hour Rapid Cycling of Direct Air Capture Enabled by Engineered Hollow Fiber Sorbents</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/03bbb359a4a8e215b36cd13f4515e2e0d706ba03</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/03bbb359a4a8e215b36cd13f4515e2e0d706ba03</guid></item></channel></rss>