<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Viatcheslav Freger</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/author/7937200</link><description>Semantic Scholar publications for Viatcheslav Freger</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:28:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>REMOVED: Ion Association Effects in Partitioning and Transport of Salt in NF and RO</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e6ab89e37f2037aab73694f8044e734efffaf798</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e6ab89e37f2037aab73694f8044e734efffaf798</guid></item><item><title>Thermodynamics, Microstructure and Interfacial Effects in Hydrated Nafion</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ae4bb5ac8526c9da9452169468ac858f8548dc49</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ae4bb5ac8526c9da9452169468ac858f8548dc49</guid></item><item><title>REMOVED: A Microfluidic Cell for NF/RO Filtration: Design and Applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a9adcea97599293481ef4407d616ecd52a7bb7e5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a9adcea97599293481ef4407d616ecd52a7bb7e5</guid></item><item><title>REMOVED: Bolaamphiphile-Based Biomimetic Lipid Membranes for Water Purification</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/62afd197c667f4d533c5c575810edb5dad78a2b3</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/62afd197c667f4d533c5c575810edb5dad78a2b3</guid></item><item><title>Macroinitiator Mediated Photoreactive Coating of Membrane Surfaces with Antifouling Hydrogel Layers</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/57079dc38e9ce6e0b68df34f587ff2d30328c056</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/57079dc38e9ce6e0b68df34f587ff2d30328c056</guid></item><item><title>Development of Anti-Fouling, Anti-Microbial Membranes by Chemical Patterning</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c10574cab0e17a99f00b2e5751e40b9ba7f88026</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c10574cab0e17a99f00b2e5751e40b9ba7f88026</guid></item><item><title>Boron Removal Using Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8c2db9b2bf730ce237afb412aac497ba66b756b7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8c2db9b2bf730ce237afb412aac497ba66b756b7</guid></item><item><title>CARBON NANOTUBE MEMBRANE</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ab92d3d78838bf545eb2878b218e07d31ec43be</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ab92d3d78838bf545eb2878b218e07d31ec43be</guid></item><item><title>Three-dimensional CFD modeling for hollow fiber gas separation membrane modules based on a dual porous media model</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2ecbead14a5feb7dd6152e5c3f9d5c3a2bfe4d27</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2ecbead14a5feb7dd6152e5c3f9d5c3a2bfe4d27</guid></item><item><title>Surface-Induced Micelle Orientation in Nafion Films</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f1cbc1594e041fdcf75dfae718143fa10ad2675</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f1cbc1594e041fdcf75dfae718143fa10ad2675</guid></item><item><title>Chemical and physical factors in design of antibiofouling polymer coatings.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8e662c0ad4cb66e00afb69b30b7fd40de755d99e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8e662c0ad4cb66e00afb69b30b7fd40de755d99e</guid></item><item><title>Bacterial attachment to RO membranes surface-modified by concentration-polarization-enhanced graft polymerization.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2e46bef8e2606e0d31f4175abb1feda80b25830c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2e46bef8e2606e0d31f4175abb1feda80b25830c</guid></item><item><title>Co-solvent-mediated synthesis of thin polyamide membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0d5a2f74dfaf2ed42a9d73a5beafa8abe167b83a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0d5a2f74dfaf2ed42a9d73a5beafa8abe167b83a</guid></item><item><title>Enhanced partitioning and transport of phenolic micropollutants within polyamide composite membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d09d52c4b3e01bffb3fdb35bb40435463e2755d4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d09d52c4b3e01bffb3fdb35bb40435463e2755d4</guid></item><item><title>Microfluidic NF/RO separation: Cell design, performance and application</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a0a6868b129b2f2f04cb7363ad142f278bb36b7c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a0a6868b129b2f2f04cb7363ad142f278bb36b7c</guid></item><item><title>Pseudomonas aeruginosa attachment on QCM-D sensors: the role of cell and surface hydrophobicities.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c896876ccf19ed955940a05d9a2ae83417b66702</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c896876ccf19ed955940a05d9a2ae83417b66702</guid></item><item><title>Improving performance of spiral wound RO elements by in situ concentration polarization-enhanced radical graft polymerization</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e8432caac6c022aaf268afeadf0048b993c1cea1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e8432caac6c022aaf268afeadf0048b993c1cea1</guid></item><item><title>Antimicrobial and fouling-resistant membranes for treatment of agricultural and municipal wastewater</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34e0d6b8359ea7c15163f19568405c14006d1ac6</link><description>This research project introduced a novel membrane coating strategy to combat biofouling, which is a major problem for the membrane-based treatment of agricultural and municipal wastewaters. The novelty of the strategy is that the membrane coatings have the unique ability to switch reversibly between passive (antifouling) and active (antimicrobial) fouling control mechanisms. This dual-mode approach differs fundamentally from other coating strategies that rely solely on one mode of fouling control.   The research project had two complementary objectives: (1) preparation, characterization, and testing of dual-mode polymer nanolayers on planar surfaces and (2) evaluation of these nanolayers as membrane modifiers. The first objective was designed to provide a fundamental understanding of how polymer nanolayer chemistry and structure affect bacterial deposition and to demonstrate the reversibility of chemical switching. The second objective, which focused on membrane development, characterization, and testing, was designed to demonstrate methods for the production of water treatment membranes that couple passive and active biofouling control mechanisms.  Both objectives were attained through synergistic collaboration among the three research groups. Using planar silicon and glass surfaces, we demonstrated using infrared spectroscopy that this new polymer coating can switch reversibly between the anti-fouling, zwitterion mode and an anti-microbial, quaternary amine mode. We showed that switching could be done more than 50 times without loss of activity and that the kinetics for switching from a low fouling zwitterion surface to an antimicrobial quaternary amine surface is practical for use. While a low pH was required for switching in the original polymer, we illustrated that by slightly altering the chemistry, it is possible to adjust the pH at which the switching occurs. A method was developed for applying the new zwitterionic surface chemistry onto polyethersulfone (PES) ultrafiltration membranes. Bacteria deposition studies showed that the new chemistry performed better than other common anti-fouling chemistries. Biofilm studies showed that PESultrafiltration membranes coated with the new chemistry accumulated half the biomass volume as unmodified membranes. Biofilm studies also showed that PES membranes coated with the new chemistry in the anti-microbial mode attained higher biofilm mortality than PES membranes coated with a common, non-switchablezwitterionic polymer.  Results from our research are expected to improve membrane performance for the purification of wastewaters prior to use in irrigation. Since reduction in flux due to biofouling is one of the largest costs associated with membrane processes in water treatment, using dual-mode nanolayer coatings that switch between passive and active control of biofouling and enable detachment of attached biofoulants would have significant economic and societal impacts.  Specifically, this research program developed and tested advanced ultrafiltration membranes for the treatment of wastewaters. Such membranes could find use in membrane bioreactors treating municipal wastewater, a slightly upgraded version of what presently is used in Israel for irrigation. They also may find use for pretreatment of agricultural wastewaters, e.g., rendering facility wastewater, prior to reverse osmosis for desalination. The need to desalinate such impaired waters water for unlimited agricultural use is likely in the near future. </description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/34e0d6b8359ea7c15163f19568405c14006d1ac6</guid></item><item><title>Bacterial attachment and viscoelasticity: physicochemical and motility effects analyzed using quartz crystal microbalance with dissipation (QCM-D).</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/23bd79b21fa07c50c52dec42262583bbe279ab21</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/23bd79b21fa07c50c52dec42262583bbe279ab21</guid></item><item><title>Fusion of bolaamphiphile micelles: a method to prepare stable supported biomimetic membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6db832c2ef8cf0c1de1c70c8c0973fd04603a154</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6db832c2ef8cf0c1de1c70c8c0973fd04603a154</guid></item><item><title>Modeling and analysis of hydrodynamic and physico-chemical effects in bacterial deposition on surfaces</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/94d2bc351e3d25669d181b15729f21940b6a7aec</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/94d2bc351e3d25669d181b15729f21940b6a7aec</guid></item><item><title>Synthesis and Characterization of Poly(ethylene glycol) Methacrylate Based Hydrogel Networks for Anti‐Biofouling Applications</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2fa89a6ba872eff939f637a64a7e793feb1f357c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2fa89a6ba872eff939f637a64a7e793feb1f357c</guid></item><item><title>Permeability and selectivity of reverse osmosis membranes: correlation to swelling revisited.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a74e07c47d73dbd09559c04b0c867de535c25316</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a74e07c47d73dbd09559c04b0c867de535c25316</guid></item><item><title>‘Should I stay or should I go?’ Bacterial attachment vs biofilm formation on surface-modified membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/83c3a386a59d4cac0ae8240817ae5f69666d5eeb</link><description>A number of techniques are used for testing the anti-biofouling activity of surfaces, yet the correlation between different results is often questionable. In this report, the correlation between initial bacterial deposition (fast tests, reported previously) and biofilm growth (much slower tests) was analyzed on a pristine and a surface-modified reverse osmosis membrane ESPA-1. The membrane was modified with grafted hydrophilic polymers bearing negatively charged, positively charged and zwitter-ionic moieties. Using three different bacterial strains it was found that there was no general correlation between the initial bacterial deposition rates and biofilm growth on surfaces, the reasons being different for each modified surface. For the negatively charged surface the slowest deposition due to the charge repulsion was eventually succeeded by the largest biofilm growth, probably due to secretion of extracellular polymeric substances (EPS) that mediated a strong attachment. For the positively charged surface, short-term charge attraction by quaternary amine groups led to the fastest deposition, but could be eventually overridden by their antimicrobial activity, resulting in non-consistent results where in some cases a lower biofilm formation rate was observed. The results indicate that initial deposition rates have to be used and interpreted with great care, when used for assessing the anti-biofouling activity of surfaces. However, for a weakly interacting ‘low-fouling’ zwitter-ionic surface, the positive correlation between initial cell deposition and biofilm growth, especially under flow, suggests that for this type of coating initial deposition tests may be fairly indicative of anti-biofouling potential.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/83c3a386a59d4cac0ae8240817ae5f69666d5eeb</guid></item><item><title>A critical review of transport through osmotic membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/83f22a3419d197822e2256414fcb6f20079e3ece</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/83f22a3419d197822e2256414fcb6f20079e3ece</guid></item><item><title>Hydration, porosity and water dynamics in the polyamide layer of reverse osmosis membranes: A molecular dynamics study</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/21d5451bd07051b6bbdd8f0a407c6789ccfee1f7</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/21d5451bd07051b6bbdd8f0a407c6789ccfee1f7</guid></item><item><title>Towards supported bolaamphiphile membranes for water filtration: Roles of lipid and substrate</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/03445bfc2d294641ed5c60808b66844092e8879f</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/03445bfc2d294641ed5c60808b66844092e8879f</guid></item><item><title>Interactions of glycosphingolipids and lipopolysaccharides with silica and polyamide surfaces: adsorption and viscoelastic properties.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6d4a3d1b8769631b7e698116245ebfef8a65485a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6d4a3d1b8769631b7e698116245ebfef8a65485a</guid></item><item><title>Does hindered transport theory apply to desalination membranes?</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/26ec536c6b1484c413bf20472fcb1716090be022</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/26ec536c6b1484c413bf20472fcb1716090be022</guid></item><item><title>Outperforming nature's membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4bb32ce2ea62eb400dd9f8743acaa561fbd20802</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4bb32ce2ea62eb400dd9f8743acaa561fbd20802</guid></item><item><title>Predicting the Rejection of Major Seawater Ions by Spiral-Wound Nanofiltration Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f2b4927997c29db48d3bc038a68ac5a94ced2acc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f2b4927997c29db48d3bc038a68ac5a94ced2acc</guid></item><item><title>Solute hindrance in non-porous membranes: An ATR-FTIR study</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2418a92b058596c251c4186da00050d22743ebfe</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/2418a92b058596c251c4186da00050d22743ebfe</guid></item><item><title>Facile evaluation of coating thickness on membranes using ATR-FTIR</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c27f37ec874c77c3c74d171ef6fed010fc9a56e5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c27f37ec874c77c3c74d171ef6fed010fc9a56e5</guid></item><item><title>Molecular Dynamics Investigation of Ion Sorption and Permeation in Desalination Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/00fd0472c8d5d3349e35934f4d58d2a01c3295e9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/00fd0472c8d5d3349e35934f4d58d2a01c3295e9</guid></item><item><title>Modeling pH variation in reverse osmosis.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/67216c3ecb41f432899f6b5ee4bc2d9a59a1ed9e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/67216c3ecb41f432899f6b5ee4bc2d9a59a1ed9e</guid></item><item><title>A Novel Composite Nafion/Anodized Aluminium Oxide Proton Exchange Membrane</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/90c29f061ac652903e6e9e76c8139c288573f475</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/90c29f061ac652903e6e9e76c8139c288573f475</guid></item><item><title>Breaking the Symmetry: Mitigating Scaling in Tertiary Treatment of Waste Effluents Using a Positively Charged Nanofiltration Membrane</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/21a6a76e65e135ae63c6bdd4de311b349c86679d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/21a6a76e65e135ae63c6bdd4de311b349c86679d</guid></item><item><title>Assessing biofouling resistance of a polyamide reverse osmosis membrane surface-modified with a zwitterionic polymer</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f55c20dbfaf9443bdd46c39051300cf066d60852</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f55c20dbfaf9443bdd46c39051300cf066d60852</guid></item><item><title>A Nafion‐filled Polycarbonate Track‐Etched Composite Membrane with Enhanced Selectivity for Direct Methanol Fuel Cells</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f19d7183a20ae1934bbf367196d3f5cdebdc0521</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f19d7183a20ae1934bbf367196d3f5cdebdc0521</guid></item><item><title>Formation of pore-spanning lipid membrane and cross-membrane water and ion transport</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0cdb325bbe68bd614f75872b945e34b851d38cdd</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0cdb325bbe68bd614f75872b945e34b851d38cdd</guid></item><item><title>When Salt-Rejecting Polymers Meet Protons: An Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy Investigation.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d6777121b64f6b63fe631578d2dc275806a21f58</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d6777121b64f6b63fe631578d2dc275806a21f58</guid></item><item><title>Facile Modification of Reverse Osmosis Membranes by Surfactant-Assisted Acrylate Grafting for Enhanced Selectivity.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/418642317b4fccb12a13458a21ef34b1317d5fdf</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/418642317b4fccb12a13458a21ef34b1317d5fdf</guid></item><item><title>Understanding methods of preparation and characterization of pore-filling polymer composites for proton exchange membranes: a beginner’s guide</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a6d605eb75d4c2c36794f62dd29b9be6a6e8d7d0</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a6d605eb75d4c2c36794f62dd29b9be6a6e8d7d0</guid></item><item><title>In situ modification of membrane elements for improved boron rejection in RO desalination</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5703fef26bbc5b9bc7cc92676147cd17e5503a5a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5703fef26bbc5b9bc7cc92676147cd17e5503a5a</guid></item><item><title>What makes aromatic polyamide membranes superior: New insights into ion transport and membrane structure</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/25ddad6e9a5e58c2740da2e86a0d6f882547db48</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/25ddad6e9a5e58c2740da2e86a0d6f882547db48</guid></item><item><title>Modification of polyamide membranes by hydrophobic molecular plugs for improved boron rejection</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/94c01d75e19142f72201706c31e7c655fffc036c</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/94c01d75e19142f72201706c31e7c655fffc036c</guid></item><item><title>A switchable zwitterionic membrane surface chemistry for biofouling control</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7de4406952f065fbc84ab95ea9cd0a4e8aeca6a1</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7de4406952f065fbc84ab95ea9cd0a4e8aeca6a1</guid></item><item><title>Permeation mechanism and interplay between ions in nanofiltration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0235db83cbb280afa039c1ad1ebbf0d19f300bf9</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0235db83cbb280afa039c1ad1ebbf0d19f300bf9</guid></item><item><title>Electrotreated Carbon Nanotube Membranes for Facile Oil–Water Separations</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/404c3d76b3c876e4b81852394b519c59498a1337</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/404c3d76b3c876e4b81852394b519c59498a1337</guid></item><item><title>The modelling and enhancement of water hydrodynamics: general discussion.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f1451c32439704562f5f6fa3dbcb638c141d4bf5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/f1451c32439704562f5f6fa3dbcb638c141d4bf5</guid></item><item><title>Selectivity and polarization in water channel membranes: lessons learned from polymeric membranes and CNTs.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c92a54cbc3009762fd598f71eb481cb5c3dd450d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c92a54cbc3009762fd598f71eb481cb5c3dd450d</guid></item><item><title>Structure and function of natural proteins for water transport: general discussion.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b8beb813ea09d20409f2f0cad8e4b6ba97f2732b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b8beb813ea09d20409f2f0cad8e4b6ba97f2732b</guid></item><item><title>Applications to water transport systems: general discussion.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a76cc864e0fee3df1953229843e98533d60a508a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a76cc864e0fee3df1953229843e98533d60a508a</guid></item><item><title>Biomimetic water channels: general discussion.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/29493adf25bd92d6cd7eba8ede07c73b1aff480b</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/29493adf25bd92d6cd7eba8ede07c73b1aff480b</guid></item><item><title>Modeling QCM-D Response to Deposition and Attachment of Microparticles and Living Cells.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d409af190d35ae9e1f2fb7e6dba05a9eec9a1270</link><description>Quartz crystal microbalance with dissipation monitoring (QCM-D) is a powerful tool for studying adhesion, yet its use for analyzing the deposition of microparticles and living cells on surfaces has been hampered by difficulties in interpretation. Here we report a new quantitative model of QCM-D response, presented as an equivalent acoustic impedance circuit. As an essential feature, the particle interaction with surrounding fluid is modeled by relations for a freely oscillating rotating and translating sphere in an unbounded fluid, which is a valid approximation for microparticles. This helps deduce from the measured reponse the parameters pertinent to the contact mechanics. We use the model to analyze deposition of different microparticles as well as Pseudomonas fluorescens bacteria on several substrates using QCM-D combined with real-time microscopy. The parameter space is increased by varying particle type and size, substrate surface chemistry and rigidity, and ionic strength of the solution, which allows observation of diverse responses and transition from inertial to elastic loading, including rarely observed resonant regimes. Ultimately, we find that the model describes reasonably well the observed response for different microparticles and substrates, as well as for bacteria, and enables extraction of the contact characteristics in elastic and mixed loading regimes. It also reveals discrepancies between measured and anticipated parameters for large particles. The new model can be a useful tool for interpreting and quantifying QCM-D data on the adhesion of particles and living cells to surfaces, including time-dependent adhesion phenomena.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d409af190d35ae9e1f2fb7e6dba05a9eec9a1270</guid></item><item><title>Degradation of Polyamide Membranes Exposed to Chlorine: An Impedance Spectroscopy Study.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/aeba0bf276663748825a2104ceb658ae275e58e3</link><description>Polyamide is the key material in modern membrane desalination; however, its well-known and incompletely understood drawback is its low tolerance to chlorine, the most efficient in-line disinfectant. Here we report a first investigation of the mechanism and kinetics of chlorine attack using electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) that directly probes changes in ion permeation upon chlorination at different pH values, focusing on its early stages and low chlorine concentrations (15-197 ppm). EIS results partly conform to an established two-stage mechanism that proceeds as N-chlorination followed by either C-chlorination in acidic conditions or amide bond scission in alkaline conditions. However, early time kinetics in acidic conditions shows inconsistencies with this model, explained by possible effects of direct ring chlorination and finite polymer relaxation rates. The findings indicate that (a) N-chlorination reduces membrane polarity and ion permeability, while C-chlorination has an opposite effect; (b) chlorination in acidic conditions must involve other reactions, such as direct ring chlorination, in addition to N-chlorination and Orton rearrangement; and (c) the ultimate chemical transformations (C-chlorination or amide bond scission) result in an irreversible increase in membrane polarity and loss of ion rejection. The results highlight the potential of EIS as a powerful and sensitive tool for studying chemical degradation of ion-selective materials that may assist in developing new chlorine-resistant membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/aeba0bf276663748825a2104ceb658ae275e58e3</guid></item><item><title>In Situ Modification of Reverse Osmosis Membrane Elements for Enhanced Removal of Multiple Micropollutants</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3fc2a80468bae26855e8e7334251be9442964427</link><description>Reverse osmosis (RO) membranes are widely used for desalination and water treatment. However, they insufficiently reject some small uncharged micropollutants, such as certain endocrine-disrupting, pharmaceutically active compounds and boric acid, increasingly present in water sources and wastewater. This study examines the feasibility of improving rejection of multiple micropollutants in commercial low-pressure RO membrane elements using concentration polarization- and surfactant-enhanced surface polymerization. Low-pressure membrane elements modified by grafting poly(glycidyl methacrylate) showed enhanced rejection of all tested solutes (model organic micropollutants, boric acid, and NaCl), with permeability somewhat reduced, but comparable with commercial brackish water RO membranes. The study demonstrates the potential and up-scalability of grafting as an in situ method for improving removal of various classes of organic and inorganic micropollutants and tuning performance in RO and other dense composite membranes for water purification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3fc2a80468bae26855e8e7334251be9442964427</guid></item><item><title>Effect of the membrane exclusion mechanism on phosphate scaling during synthetic effluent desalination.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/69dc7d41d3baede4ea496da60c5497a5817bbe24</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/69dc7d41d3baede4ea496da60c5497a5817bbe24</guid></item><item><title>Ion partitioning and permeation in charged low-T* membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7332fa3eb17508e86193e230e1c1a48b33a2009a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7332fa3eb17508e86193e230e1c1a48b33a2009a</guid></item><item><title>Membrane Charge Weakly Affects Ion Transport in Reverse Osmosis</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f90d9e06bb843b3f4623596a6f499606385e44b</link><description>Polyamide RO membranes have been a “golden standard” in water desalination, with aromatic polyamide layer providing an excellent balance between salt rejection and water permeability. Yet, there st...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7f90d9e06bb843b3f4623596a6f499606385e44b</guid></item><item><title>Water and Ion Transfer to Narrow Carbon Nanotubes: Roles of Exterior and Interior.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e40e24896f2904999017d72e897b62d9b6a2b34</link><description>Narrow carbon nanotubes (CNTs) desalinate water, mimicking water channels of biological membranes, yet the physics behind selectivity, especially the effect of the membrane embedding CNTs on water and ion transfer, is still unclear. Here, we report ab initio analysis of the energies involved in transfer of water and K+ and Cl- ions from solution to empty and water-filled 0.68 nm CNTs for different dielectric constants (ϵ) of the surrounding matrix. The transfer energies computed for 1 ≤ ϵ &lt; ∞ permit a transparent breakdown of the transfer energy to three main contributions: binding to CNT, intra-CNT hydration, and dielectric polarization of the matrix. The latter scales inversely with ϵ and is of the order 102/ϵ kJ/mol for both ions, which may change ion transfer from favorable to unfavorable, depending on ion, ϵ, and CNT diameter. This may have broad implications for designing and tuning selectivity of nanochannel-based devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e40e24896f2904999017d72e897b62d9b6a2b34</guid></item><item><title>Spatial pattern and surface-specificity of particle and microorganism deposition and attachment: Modeling, analytic solution and experimental test.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4642a0fd79bc2bac24a3aab608174c1ee4b4dd91</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4642a0fd79bc2bac24a3aab608174c1ee4b4dd91</guid></item><item><title>Water Content and Ionic Conductivity of Thin Films of Different Anionic Forms of Anion Conducting Ionomers</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d8a87fdc4fe947577e3aee6e30fb6c0e6b82386f</link><description>Typically, in polymer electrolyte based electrochemical devices such as electrolyzers and fuel cells, ionomers in the catalyst layers are present as ultra-thin films coating the electrochemically a...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d8a87fdc4fe947577e3aee6e30fb6c0e6b82386f</guid></item><item><title>Blends of polymer semiconductor and polymer electrolyte for mixed ionic and electronic conductivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a987488b6458db6bcaedbec358c62ae10370086d</link><description>Mixed ionic and electronic conductivity is achieved by blending a semiconducting polymer, P3HT, with a polymer electrolyte, PEO. Blend composition and PEO Mw direct the blend morphology and tune the mixed conductivity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a987488b6458db6bcaedbec358c62ae10370086d</guid></item><item><title>Nanofiltration Membrane Characterization</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8cdc8829674a1ed44460f9ced9fc8512de00f4b5</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8cdc8829674a1ed44460f9ced9fc8512de00f4b5</guid></item><item><title>Electrospun Ion-Conducting Composite Membrane with Buckling-Induced Anisotropic Through-Plane Conductivity.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d56f8c7db2be52a9984b96149517b69c10d6e563</link><description>Fuel cell (FC) is an attractive green alternative for today's fuel combustion systems. In common FCs, a polymer electrolyte membrane selectively conducts protons but blocks the passage of electrons and fuel. Nafion, the current benchmark membrane material, has a superior conductivity owing to unique morphology comprising randomly oriented elongated ionic nanochannels within its Teflon-like matrix. Channel orientation enhances Nafion conductivity, yet there has been no facile method to induce a stable alignment in the desired through-plane (TP) direction. Here, we report an approach based on dual electrospun Nafion-PVDF nanofiber composites that yields a stable TP alignment. It utilizes extreme thinness and strong inherent orientation within electrospun nanofibers, which is readily converted to TP alignment by plunging an electrospun nanofiber mat into a thin slit, resulting in nanofiber buckling and subsequent consolidation. Using TEM and SAXS, we demonstrate a pronounced and sustained TP ion channel orientation in prepared membranes, yielding a highly anisotropic swelling and conductivity exceeding that of bulk Nafion when normalized to Nafion content. The analysis also highlights the importance of PVDF as a stabilizing component, preserving orientation upon annealing, while a similarly prepared pure Nafion membrane loses anisotropy. The approach holds potential to advance the FC technology by overcoming current limitations of ionomeric membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d56f8c7db2be52a9984b96149517b69c10d6e563</guid></item><item><title>Simplifying concentration-polarization of trace-ions in pressure-driven membrane processes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e18aff2ec7fa6c696b294b84fbabecdb5c151826</link><description>Accounting for concentration-polarization (CP) is critical for modeling solute transport in membrane separation processes. In a mixed-electrolyte solution, ions CP is affected not only by diffusion and advection but also by electromigration. Yet, the classic film model, lacking an electromigration term, is frequently used for modeling ion CP. Often, ion CP is altogether neglected to reduce the computational load. Here, we study the CP of trace ions in a dominant salt solution, a case relevant for many reverse-osmosis and nanofiltration processes. First, we revisit the solution-diffusion-electromigration-film theory to obtain an analytical solution for the CP and membrane-transport of trace-ions in a dominant salt solution. Secondly, we consider limiting conditions relevant to reverse-osmosis and nanofiltration, from which we derive two compact equations that emerge as a seamless extension to the classic film theory. These equations can be used to account for the effect of electromigration on CP with minimal effort. Thirdly, we use our theory to quantify the effect of electromigration on ion CP in different dominant salt solutions. Finally, by analyzing two environmental membrane processes, we demonstrate how our theory deviates from the conventional one and quantify the implications on membrane scaling potential and the transport of ionic contaminants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/e18aff2ec7fa6c696b294b84fbabecdb5c151826</guid></item><item><title>Polyamide desalination membranes: Formation, structure, and properties</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d96ab255386801617efb5f3d27506c8229628306</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d96ab255386801617efb5f3d27506c8229628306</guid></item><item><title>Putting Together the Puzzle of Ion Transfer in Single-Digit Carbon Nanotubes: Ab Initio Meets Mean-Field</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/71c8ac9098ae16358440df148032f30417758023</link><description>
 Nature employs channel proteins to selectively pass water across cell membranes, which inspires search for bio-mimetic analogues. Carbon nanotube porins (CNTPs) are intriguing mimics of water channels, yet ion transport in CNTPs still poses questions. As alternative to continuum models, here we present a molecular mean-field model, computing ab initio all required thermodynamic quantities for KCl salt and H+ and OH- ions present in water. Starting from water transfer, the model considers transfer of free ions, along with ion-pair formation to address ion-ion interactions. High affinity to hydroxide, suggested by experiments and making it dominant charge carrier in CNTP, is revealed as an exceptionally favorable transfer of KOH pairs. Nevertheless, free ions, coexisting with less mobile ion-pairs, apparently control ion transport. The model explains well the observed effects of salt concentration and pH on conductivity, transport numbers, anion permeation and its activation energies, and current rectification. The proposed approach is extendable to other sub-nanochannels and help design novel osmotic materials and devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/71c8ac9098ae16358440df148032f30417758023</guid></item><item><title>A comprehensive review on water stable metal-organic frameworks for large-scale preparation and applications in water quality management based on surveys made since 2015</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bce76a0d3eb4eae9e022e3e01d5006e604045f01</link><description>Abstract Water is one of essential resources of modern society. Employing cost-effective technologies to treat water and wastewater is of vital importance for household uses, industries and the environment. Water-stable metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as promising innovative materials for water treatment, due to their versatility and properties such as large internal surface area, designable pore sizes, and chemical functionalities. In highly porous MOFs, metal center(s)/cluster(s) and organic ligands are linked with coordination bonds. This review paper presents the most recent developments in the industrial-scale synthesis of MOFs and applications in water purification. MOFs can be fabricated by several approaches; the microwave assisted continuous flow synthesis technologies can lead to higher production yields. The fabricated MOFs are then purified by the organic solvent and/or the solid separation, and activated by a few technologies (e.g., supercritical ). Process safety in production, reactors design, and process optimization are important in production. The shaping techniques for MOFs on supporting materials via surface grafting/coating or embedment can be used to fabricate the MOFs-based materials with the better stability suitable for industrial applications. MOFs demonstrate much better performances than the commercially available materials in adsorption, filtration, sensing, and catalysis. Toxicity from MOFs is mainly due to the chemicals involved in the production and nano-size effects on human cells. Mitigation strategies like environmental-friendly processes for fabrication of MOFs and shaping using polymer are suggested. Various advantages from MOFs make them suitable for water treatment in the near future. Graphical abstract</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/bce76a0d3eb4eae9e022e3e01d5006e604045f01</guid></item><item><title>A mixed-charge polyelectrolyte complex nanofiltration membrane: Preparation, performance and stability</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3cd141697a7ef3711c9bd3a2008919ef5f56d264</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3cd141697a7ef3711c9bd3a2008919ef5f56d264</guid></item><item><title>Proton Conductive Composite Membranes with Stable Anisotropic Though-Plane Conductivity: A New Preparation Approach</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a913750b6f73e09985b8d1f613863c2c8d1cab98</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a913750b6f73e09985b8d1f613863c2c8d1cab98</guid></item><item><title>Ion Transport, Selectivity and Charge Formation Mechanisms in Carbon Nanotube Porins: An Ab Initio Study</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/55946947d17a9430fb10e4dddb97517644144f05</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/55946947d17a9430fb10e4dddb97517644144f05</guid></item><item><title>New compact expressions for concentration-polarization of trace-ions in pressure-driven membrane processes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98212892301f8174f68effc854f8fa07c5c63564</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/98212892301f8174f68effc854f8fa07c5c63564</guid></item><item><title>Elucidating the Effect of Aliphatic Molecular Plugs on Ion-Rejecting Properties of Polyamide Membranes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c722583507a792f704af575940f1f96612c6726a</link><description>Polyamide RO membranes are widely used for seawater desalination owing to their high salt rejection and water permeability; however, improved selectivity-permeability trade-off is still desired. "Molecular plugs," small molecules immobilized within the polyamide structure, offer an attractive approach; however, their overall effect on polyamide physicochemical properties poses many questions. Here, we analyze the effect of decylamine, a promising plug, and a few charged and uncharged mimics on polyamide films using several in situ techniques. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) reveals a complex pH-dependent response, whereby, upon exposure to amine solution, conductivity first rapidly drops; however, under alkaline conditions, when amine is uncharged, the trend subsequently slowly reverses, and conductivity increases. This slow reversal was observed for noncharged alcohols of similar size as well, but not for larger surfactant molecules. The reversal was assigned to the uptake of plug molecules within polyamide, as opposed to the fast initial drop assigned to surface adsorption. EIS and quartz-crystal microbalance (QCM) results showed that exposure to decylamine under alkaline conditions ultimately led to an irreversible decrease in conductivity, that is, stronger ion rejection, remaining after re-exposure of polyamide to amine-free buffer. This suggests that plug uptake within polyamide resulted in polymer stress, indeed observed in surface stress measurements, and subsequent relaxation. The results indicate that the moderate size of decylamine and conditions minimizing its charge were optimal for irreversible change; however, charge interactions helped maximize its binding within polymer and induce the desired sustained change in selectivity. The results have many potential implications for improving current membrane desalination technology and increasing inherent membrane selectivity toward hard-to-remove species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c722583507a792f704af575940f1f96612c6726a</guid></item><item><title>Elucidating ion transport mechanism in polyelectrolyte-complex membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/84ba6836e31a90b6ece225eb219625676236d2fc</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/84ba6836e31a90b6ece225eb219625676236d2fc</guid></item><item><title>Putting together the puzzle of ion transfer in single-digit carbon nanotubes: mean-field meets ab initio.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b298de5b4a41a5baaa89bf3af2cf263298ac6a26</link><description>Nature employs channel proteins to selectively pass water across cell membranes, which inspires the search for bio-mimetic analogues. Carbon nanotube porins (CNTPs) are intriguing mimics of water channels, yet ion transport in CNTPs still poses questions. As an alternative to continuum models, here we present a molecular mean-field model that transparently describes ion coupling, yet unlike continuum models, computes ab initio all required thermodynamic quantities for the KCl salt and H+ and OH- ions present in water. Starting from water transfer, the model considers the transfer of free ions, along with ion-pair formation as a proxy of non-mean-field ion-ion interactions. High affinity to hydroxide, suggested by experiments, making it a dominant charge carrier in CNTPs, is revealed as an exceptionally favorable transfer of KOH pairs. Nevertheless, free ions, coexisting with less mobile ion-pairs, apparently control ion transport. The model well explains the observed effects of salt concentration and pH on conductivity, transport numbers, anion permeation and its activation energies, and current rectification. The proposed approach is extendable to other sub-nanochannels and helps design novel osmotic materials and devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b298de5b4a41a5baaa89bf3af2cf263298ac6a26</guid></item><item><title>Ambipolar blend-based organic electrochemical transistors and inverters</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8acb96503420d5fc94393925727401e80268512f</link><description>CMOS-like circuits in bioelectronics translate biological to electronic signals using organic electrochemical transistors (OECTs) based on organic mixed ionic-electronic conductors (OMIECs). Ambipolar OECTs can reduce the complexity of circuit fabrication, and in bioelectronics have the major advantage of detecting both cations and anions in one device, which further expands the prospects for diagnosis and sensing. Ambipolar OMIECs however, are scarce, limited by intricate materials design and complex synthesis. Here we demonstrate that judicious selection of p- and n-type materials for blend-based OMIECs offers a simple and tunable approach for the fabrication of ambipolar OECTs and corresponding circuits. These OECTs show high transconductance and excellent stability over multiple alternating polarity cycles, with ON/OFF ratios exceeding 103 and high gains in corresponding inverters. This work presents a simple and versatile new paradigm for the fabrication of ambipolar OMIECs and circuits with little constraints on materials design and synthesis and numerous possibilities for tunability and optimization towards higher performing bioelectronic applications. Ambipolar organic electrochemical transistors simplify bioelectronics circuitry but are challenging due to complicated material design and synthesis. Here, the authors demonstrate that p- and n-type blends offer a simple and tuneable approach for the fabrication of ambipolar devices and circuits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/8acb96503420d5fc94393925727401e80268512f</guid></item><item><title>Polystyrene Sulfonate Particles as Building Blocks for Nanofiltration Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed174d466c88352fbf2d2e3d6f92488a28900925</link><description>Today the standard treatment for wastewater is secondary treatment. This procedure cannot remove salinity or some organic micropollutants from water. In the future, a tertiary cleaning step may be required. An attractive solution is membrane processes, especially nanofiltration (NF). However, currently available NF membranes strongly reject multivalent ions, mainly due to the dielectric effect. In this work, we present a new method for preparing NF membranes, which contain negatively and positively charged domains, obtained by the combination of two polyelectrolytes with opposite charge. The negatively charged polyelectrolyte is provided in the form of particles (polystyrene sulfonate (PSSA), d ~300 nm). As a positively charged polyelectrolyte, polyethyleneimine (PEI) is used. Both buildings blocks and glycerol diglycidyl ether as crosslinker for PEI are applied to an UF membrane support in a simple one-step coating process. The membrane charge (zeta potential) and salt rejection can be adjusted using the particle concentration in the coating solution/dispersion that determine the selective layer composition. The approach reported here leads to NF membranes with a selectivity that may be controlled by a different mechanism compared to state-of-the-art membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ed174d466c88352fbf2d2e3d6f92488a28900925</guid></item><item><title>A New Fabrication Approach for Mixed Matrix Membrane Fabricated with Interstitially Sealed Mof Nanoparticles</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1171edb98d5ea4e2344bec5017df24b57498845</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/a1171edb98d5ea4e2344bec5017df24b57498845</guid></item><item><title>Ion Transport and Specificity in Polyamide Membranes Studied by Conductivity and its Activation Energy</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e67995cee39c66ca191ed255c896e60d5ac3f24</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/0e67995cee39c66ca191ed255c896e60d5ac3f24</guid></item><item><title>Dynamics of underwater microparticle adhesion to soft hydrated surfaces: Modeling and analysis by time-dependent AFM force spectroscopy.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7b18f65d7ef271e79328285e87b7bfd7cb900e53</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/7b18f65d7ef271e79328285e87b7bfd7cb900e53</guid></item><item><title>Preparation, nano-mechanics and particle deposition behavior of thin, antifouling hydrogel coatings</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d35a4b91a72e2f463284fd819198db02aff98774</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/d35a4b91a72e2f463284fd819198db02aff98774</guid></item><item><title>Direct wind-powered vertical axis brackish water desalination system</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/50784687a9ad63cc076858f9036263836aabc2c8</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/50784687a9ad63cc076858f9036263836aabc2c8</guid></item><item><title>Analyzing ion uptake in ion-exchange membranes using ion association model</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4ca946c9d8c8ebe9eea36178e8ce8091b003d36a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/4ca946c9d8c8ebe9eea36178e8ce8091b003d36a</guid></item><item><title>Preparation and Optimization of Novel Anisotropic Proton-Exchange Membranes with Enhanced through-Plane Conductivity</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3dc9b6ab67184ba6b476425a859bc35e4acc7232</link><description>Maximizing through-plane (TP) conductivity, as opposed to in-plane (IP), is desired for proton exchange membranes (PEMs) in fuel cells, electrolysis and electrodialysis. Nafion, the benchmark PEM material, owes conductivity to randomly oriented ion-channels. Channel alignment in electrospun nanofibers was shown to enhance conductivity along the fibres by an order of magnitude, but it proved challenging to convert this to desired stable TP conductance. Another challenge is that orientation proves unstable and returns to random after nanofiber consolidation.
 Previously, we reported fabrication of electrospun nanofiber-based membrane with a stable anisotropic TP alignment of proton conducting channels prepared by co-spinning, buckling and fusion of Nafion and PVDF nanofibers (Odess, Li et al, ACS Appl Mat Interfaces, 2021), as shown in Figure 1. PVDF nanofibers serve as a mechanical reinforcement as well as a stabilizing component to safeguard Nafion TP alignment during annealing and swelling, akin to a solid template. However, the prepared 50% Nafion membrane still showed a TP conductivity slightly inferior to Nafion.
 In this report, we systematically optimized the Nafion content in the 50-80% range, as well as buckling and consolidation procedure and its temperature regime, to achieve a maximal and sustained conductance, exceeding that of pure Nafion. It was found that the TP proton conductivity of the membrane with 60% Nafion already exceeded that of Nafion 117 and further increased with Nafion content (Figure 1), with decrease in anisotropy (TP/IP conductance ratio). As another attractive feature, compared with Nafion 117, the TP conductivity of aligned membranes decreased less at lower humidity, i.e., was less sensitivity to dehydration, apparently due to better channel connectivity. Anisotropic structure and nanoscopic alignment were further confirmed by TEM and SAXS. The results demonstrate the potential of the new buckling approach for making novel nanofiber-based anisotropic membranes with significantly improved performance in electromembrane applications.
 
 
 
 
 
 Figure 1
</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3dc9b6ab67184ba6b476425a859bc35e4acc7232</guid></item><item><title>Pseudo-bottle-brush decorated thin-film composite desalination membranes with ultrahigh mineral scale resistance</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6dd71d7536f2ad0473c9af14cde01914287bd31c</link><description>High water recovery is crucial to inland desalination but is impeded by mineral scaling of the membrane. This work presents a two-step modification approach for grafting high-density zwitterionic pseudo-bottle-brushes to polyamide reverse osmosis membranes to prevent scaling during high-recovery desalination of brackish water. Increasing brush density, induced by increasing reaction time, correlated with reduced scaling. High-density grafting eliminated gypsum scaling and almost completely prevented silica scaling during desalination of synthetic brackish water at a recovery ratio of 80%. Moreover, scaling was effectively mitigated during long-term desalination of real brackish water at a recovery ratio of 90% without pretreatment or antiscalants. Molecular dynamics simulations reveal the critical dependence of the membrane’s silica antiscaling ability on the degree to which the coating screens the membrane surface from readily forming silica aggregates. This finding highlights the importance of maximizing grafting density for optimal performance and advanced antiscaling properties to allow high-recovery desalination of complex salt solutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/6dd71d7536f2ad0473c9af14cde01914287bd31c</guid></item><item><title>Ion Coupling, Bonding, and Transfer in Narrow Carbon Nanotubes.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fb997f951804e2b9c70866c637bf65b40c07ffb6</link><description>Narrow carbon nanotubes (nCNT) are unique mimics of biological channels with water-ion selectivity attractive for applications such as water purification and osmotic energy harvesting, yet their understanding is still incomplete. Here, an ab initio computation is employed to develop the full picture of ion transfer in nCNT including specificity and coupling between ions. The thermodynamic costs of ion transfer are computed for single ions and ion pairs and used to evaluate different local coupling scenarios including strong (pairing) and weak (free-ion) coupling as well as "electroneutrality breakdown" (EB), possible for cations only due to their chemisorption-like interaction with nCNT. The results also indicate that nCNT behaves as a highly polarizable metal-like shell, which eliminates the dielectric energy when CNT accommodates coupled cation and anion. This allows facile computation and comparison of the full transfer costs, including translation entropy, for different ions in different coupling modes to identify the dominant regime. EB transfer appears most favorable for K+, while anions strongly favor transfer as pairs, except for chloride which favors weak coupling and, at neutral pH, transfers as a trace ion coupled to both cation and OH-. The results demonstrate that, in general, observed ion permeation and conduction in nCNT, especially for anions, reflect a complex ion-specific and composition-dependent interplay between different ions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/fb997f951804e2b9c70866c637bf65b40c07ffb6</guid></item><item><title>Boosting Carbon Capture with CO2-Ultrapermeable Molecularly Imprinted Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/69696cee021bd62ac65376b6b6806f197998bd4e</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/69696cee021bd62ac65376b6b6806f197998bd4e</guid></item><item><title>The solution-diffusion model: “Rumors of my death have been exaggerated”</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1efa5fde4bdf7a06733529ec4b3316754e2f2915</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/1efa5fde4bdf7a06733529ec4b3316754e2f2915</guid></item><item><title>Direct-Through Channels of ZIF-8 Composite Membranes via In-situ Poly-BMA Sealing: Radical-induced Phase Transformation and Dye Removal Efficiency</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/28ba4c56b3112962ac57119d12eb605943c0dbb4</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/28ba4c56b3112962ac57119d12eb605943c0dbb4</guid></item><item><title>Anisotropic membrane with high proton conductivity sustaining upon dehydration</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3d6b37f451444134ee0a8b3799f3b99f89e5d2a0</link><description>In fuel cells and electrolyzers, suboptimal proton conductivity and its dramatic drop at low humidity remain major drawbacks in proton exchange membranes (PEMs), including current benchmark Nafion. Sustained through-plane (TP) alignment of nanochannels was proposed as a remedy but proved challenging. We report an anisotropic composite PEM, mimicking the water-conductive composite structure of bamboo that meets this challenge. Micro- and nanoscale alignment of conductive pathways is achieved by in-plane thermal compression of a mat composed of co-electrospun Nafion and poly(vinylidene fluoride) (PVDF) nanofibers stabilizing the alignment. This translates to pronounced TP-enhanced proton conductivity, twice that of pure Nafion at high humidity, 13 times larger at low humidity, and 10 times larger water diffusivity. This remarkable improvement is elucidated by molecular dynamics simulations, which indicate that stronger nanochannels alignment upon dehydration compensates for reduced water content. The presented approach paves the way to overcoming the major drawbacks of ionomers and advancing the development of next-generation membranes for energy applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/3d6b37f451444134ee0a8b3799f3b99f89e5d2a0</guid></item><item><title>RO performance in a mixed solvent system: Analysis of nopinone concentration from a methanol-water solution</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac7ace4956a4c4608530ab7d30feba72d8e9c754</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac7ace4956a4c4608530ab7d30feba72d8e9c754</guid></item><item><title>Ion uptake and pairing in membranes: The pore model</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ea4fe8e185000b3a3fd8c90ebe58719abea842a</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/9ea4fe8e185000b3a3fd8c90ebe58719abea842a</guid></item><item><title>3D Nanoscale Structures of Hydrated Polyamide Desalination Membranes Revealed by Cryogenic Transmission Electron Microscopy Tomography.</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac8ff8f118a377659d374686756f8be1919e7af8</link><description>Desalination via reverse osmosis (RO) membrane technology is a preferred solution to the ongoing global challenges of freshwater scarcity. The active separation layer of RO membranes is a polyamide thin film (&lt;200 nm), whose morphology critically influences membrane performance. However, conflicting descriptions of trends between morphology and performance abound in the literature due to the lack of a rigorous morphological description of these membranes. Notably, comprehensive three-dimensional (3D) morphological characterization of these membranes has so far been conducted exclusively under dry conditions, which contrasts with the operational, hydrated state of these membranes. Here, we present, for the first time, characterization of the hydrated 3D nanoscale morphology of polyamide films from commercial brackish water (BW) and seawater (SW) membranes using cryo-transmission electron microscopy (cryo-TEM) tomography. Our findings reveal significant morphological differences between hydrated and dry membranes, resulting in variations in key structural parameters that impact performance. Both SW and BW membranes swell and increase in total volume and thickness upon hydration, with BW membranes exhibiting more pronounced swelling (32% vs 7% in volume and 35% vs 11% in effective thickness), primarily due to the lower degree of cross-linking of BW membranes. Additionally, while the surface area decreases upon hydration for both SW and BW membranes, indicating a smoothing of surface nodules and cavities, surface roughness remains unchanged, suggesting that current roughness measurement methods such as atomic force microscopy do not capture intrinsic morphological features. Overall, this study demonstrates the feasibility of employing cryo-TEM tomography techniques to characterize RO membrane morphology under operation relevant conditions, thus enabling a better linkage between membrane morphology and performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/ac8ff8f118a377659d374686756f8be1919e7af8</guid></item><item><title>Solution-diffusion-mechanics model: Derivation, generalization, and non-equivalence of molecular simulations and experiments</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/672622f6138d9958fb8c04ef2549852b405d6c2d</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/672622f6138d9958fb8c04ef2549852b405d6c2d</guid></item><item><title>Isotopic Fingerprints of Proton-mediated Dielectric Relaxation in Solid and Liquid Water</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/84894a3bc202733c4f7ca43af9bdc2d7cfe8a434</link><description>We report cross-validated measurements of the isotope effect on dielectric relaxation for four isotopologues of ice and water, including the 1-10^5 Hz region, in which only sporadic and inconsistent measurements were previously available. In ice, the relaxation rates exhibit an activated temperature dependence with an isotope-independent activation energy. Across 248-273 K, the H_2O/D_2O relaxation rate ratio remains constant at 2.0 \pm 0.1. This scaling agrees with Kramers'theory in the high-friction limit if the moving mass is the proton or deuteron, indicating that dielectric relaxation is governed by a classic proton transfer over an energy barrier rather than molecular reorientation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/84894a3bc202733c4f7ca43af9bdc2d7cfe8a434</guid></item><item><title>Thickness Dependence and Fundamental Limitations for Ion Permeation in Nanoscale Films</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b91d0cd2522cebb40810480629aa8c30ca155f0e</link><description>Nanoscale films play a central role in biology and osmotic separations. Their water/salt selectivity is often regarded as intrinsic property, favoring thinner membranes for faster permeation. Here we highlight and quantify a fundamental limitation arising from the dependence of ion self-energy on film thickness, governed by its ratio to Bjerrum length. The resulting relation factors out this dependence from intrinsic ion permeability, which agrees well with available data and enables evaluation of dielectric properties of ultrathin films, advancing understanding of ion transport in membranes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/b91d0cd2522cebb40810480629aa8c30ca155f0e</guid></item><item><title>Polyelectrolyte-ionomer complex nanofiltration membranes: complexation stoichiometry, kinetics, and separation performance</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c5f9d856d923640d9a9dbb9667cb1dd73b2741ca</link><description>No abstract available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/c5f9d856d923640d9a9dbb9667cb1dd73b2741ca</guid></item><item><title>The Influence of Ion Solvation and Association Interactions on Mean Ionic Activity Coefficients in Neutral Polymeric Membranes</title><link>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73b72663c356167bd4ff1da777db9e67da97e0d7</link><description>The influence of material properties on ion-hydrated polymer thermodynamic interactions is not fully understood. In this study, we probed how polymer properties (i.e., the network mesh size and dielectric constant) contribute to interactions between ions, water molecules, and the solvated polymer by synthesizing polymer networks with varied cross-link density and functionality (e.g., hydroxyl, ether, or nitrile). We characterized the hydration-dependent network mesh size, relative permittivity (i.e., dielectric constant), and the sodium chloride mean ionic activity coefficients in the polymers and related these properties to each other using a theoretical model that describes quantitatively the influence of ion solvation and ion pairing interactions on ionic activity coefficients in neutral polymers. These results and analysis help to explain the relationship between the network mesh size, polymer dielectric constant, and mean ionic activity coefficients in solvated polymers, which may be useful to guide molecular engineering strategies for polymer membrane materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/73b72663c356167bd4ff1da777db9e67da97e0d7</guid></item></channel></rss>